<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="533" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>PASSED AT THE <lb/>SPECIAL SESSION OF THE EIGHTEENTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>CONVENED <lb/>AT THE CITY OF AUSTIN</head>
<byline>JANUARY 8, 1884, AND ADJOURNED FEBRUARY 6, 1884.</byline>
<byline>BY AUTHORITY OF THE STATE OF TEXAS</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN, TEXAS 1884</byline>
<pb n="534" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">NOTE.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Constitution of the State of Texas, Article III.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Sec. 39. No law passed by the Legislature, except the general appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation act, shall take effect or go into force until ninety days after the adjournment of the session at which it was enacted, unless in case of an emergency, which emergency must be expressed in a preamble or in the body of the act, the Legislature shall, by a vote of two-thirds of all the members elected to each house, otherwise direct; said vote to be taken by yeas and nays, and entered upon the journals.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="535" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">PROCLAMATION BY THE GOVERNOR OF TEXAS.</head>
<p>To all whom these presents may concern:</p>
<p>Whereas, The Eighteenth Legislature of the State of Texas did, at its regular biennial session, which convened in the city of Austin, Texas, on the ninth day of January, A. D. 1883, and adjourned on the thirteenth day of April, A. D. 1883, propose the following amendments to the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution, to-wit:</p>
<p>That sections 4 and 6, article 7, of the Constitution of the State of Texas, be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The lands herein set apart to the public free school fund, shall be sold under such regulations, at such times, and on such terms as may be prescribed by law; and the Legislature shall not have power to grant any relief to purchasers thereof. The Comptroller shall invest the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeds of such sales and of those heretofore made, as may be directed by the Board of Education herein provided for, in the bonds of the United States, the State of Texas, or counties in said State, or in such other securities, and under such restrictions as may be prescribed by law; and the State shall be responsible for all investments.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. All lands heretofore, or hereafter granted to the several coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of this State for educational purposes, are of right the property of said counties respectively, to which they were granted, and title thereto is vested in said counties, and no adverse possession or limitation shall ever be available against the title of any county. Each county may sell or dispose of its lands in whole or in part, in manner to be provided by the commissioners&#8217; court of the county. Actual settlers residing on said lands, shall be protected in the prior right of purchasing the same to the extent of their settlement, not to exceed one hundred and sixty acres, at the price fixed by said court, which price shall not include the value of existing improvements made thereon by such settlers. Said lands, and the proceeds thereof, when sold, shall be held by said counties alone as a trust for the benefit of public schools therein; said proceeds to be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vested in bonds of the United States, the State of Texas, or counties in said State, or in such other securities and under such restrictions as may be prescribed by law; and the counties shall be responsible for all invest<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments; the interest thereon, and other revenue, except the principal shall be available fund.</p>
<p>That section 9, article 8, of the Constitution of the State of Texas, be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 8.</head>
<p>&#8220;Section 9. The State tax on property, exclusive of the tax neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to pay the public debt, and of the taxes provided for the<pb n="536" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" /><fw type="header" place="top">Proclamation.</fw>benefit of public free schools, shall never exceed thirty-five cents on the one hundred dollars valuation; and no county, city or town shall levy more than twenty-five cents for city or county purposes, and not to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed fifteen cents, for roads and bridges, on the one hundred dollars valuation, except for the payment of debts incurred prior to the adoption of this amendment, and for the erection of public buildings, street, sewer and other permanent improvements, not to exceed twenty-five cents on the one hundred dollars valuation in any one year, and except as is in this Constitution otherwise provided.&#8221;</p>
<p>That section 3 of article 7, of the Constitution of the State of Texas, be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 3. One-fourth of the revenue derived from the State occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pation taxes, and a poll tax of one dollar on every male inhabitant of this State between the ages of twenty-one and sixty years, shall be set apart annually for the benefit of the public free schools, and, in addition thereto, there shall be levied and collected an annual ad valorem State tax of such an amount, not to exceed twenty cents on the one hundred dollars valuation, as, with the available school fund arising from all other sources, will be sufficient to maintain and support the public free schools of this State for a period of not less than six months in each year; and the Legislature may also provide for the formation of school districts within all or any of the counties of this State, by general or special law, without the local notice required in other cases of special legislation, and may authorize an additional annual ad valorem tax to be levied and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected within such school districts for the further maintenance of public free schools and the erection of school buildings therein; provided, that two-thirds of the qualified property tax paying voters of the district, voting at an election to be held for that purpose, shall vote such tax, not to exceed in any one year twenty cents on the one hundred dollars valua<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of property subject to taxation in such district, but the limitation upon the amount of district tax herein authorized shall not apply to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporated cities or towns constituting separate and independent, school districts."</p>
<p>That article 5 of the Constitution of the State shall be amended by adding thereto another section, which shall read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 29. The county court shall hold at least four terms for both civil and criminal business annually, as may be provided by the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture, or by the commissioners&#8217; court of the county under authority of law, and such other terms each year as may be fixed by the commissioners&#8217; court; provided, the commissioners&#8217; court of any county having fixed the times and number of terms of the county court, shall not change the same again until the expiration of one year. Said court shall dispose of probate business either in term time or vacation, under such regulation as may be prescribed by law. Prosecutions may be commenced in said courts in such manner as is, or may be, provided by law, and a jury therein shall consist of six men. Until otherwise provided, the terms of the county court shall be held on the first Mondays in February, May, August and November, and may remain in session three weeks.</p>
<p>And whereas, the Governor of Texas, in compliance with law,<pb n="537" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="v" /><fw type="header" place="top">Proclamation.</fw>issued his proclamation ordering an election to be held in the several counties of the State on the fourteenth day of August, A. D. 1883, and submitting the said proposed amendments to the qualified electors for members of the Legislature;</p>
<p>And whereas, said election was held in accordance with said proclama<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and the laws of the State of Texas, and the returns thereof made to the Secretary of State, now on file in his office, show that 29,734 votes were east for amendment to section 4, article 7 of the Constitution, and 21,060 votes were cast against said amendment; that 29,452 votes were east for amendment to section 6, article 7 of the Constitution, and 20,837 votes were cast against said amendment; that 30,158 votes were cast for amendment to section 9, article 8 of the Constitution, and 20,188 votes were cast against said amendment; that 30,553 votes were cast for amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment to section 3, article 7 of the Constitution, and 20,237 votes were cast against said amendment; that 30,640 votes were cast for amendment to article 5, and 17,498 votes were cast against said amendment;</p>
<p>Now, therefore, I, John Ireland, Governor of the State of Texas, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and laws of the State, do hereby proclaim and make known to the public, that a majority of the votes cast at said election were cast in favor of each of said pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed amendments, and that they, the said several proposed amendments, have become, and are, a part of the Constitution of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I have hereunto signed my name, and <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L. S.]</p></body></floatingText>have caused the seal of the State to be affixed, at the city of Austin, this twenty-fifth day of September, A. D. 1883.</p>
<closer>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, <lb/>Governor.</signed>
<signed>By the Governor: <lb/>JOS. W. BAIKES,. <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="538" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vi" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">PROCLAMATION BY THE GOVERNOR OF TEXAS.</head>
<p>To all whom these presents may concern:</p>
<p>Whereas, An extraordinary occasion has arisen, requiring the conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of the Legislature:</p>
<p>Now, therefore, I, John Ireland, Governor of the State of Texas, do, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and laws of said State, hereby call a Special Session of the Eighteenth Legislature, to be convened in the city of Austin, commencing at 12 o&#8217;clock M. on the Second Tuesday in January, A. D. 1884, for the following purposes, to-wit:</p>
<p>1. To provide for the levy and collection of a tax to maintain a sys<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tem of free schools, under the amended Constitution.</p>
<p>2. To adjust the free school law to the requirements of the amended Constitution.</p>
<p>3. To reduce taxation for general revenue purposes.</p>
<p>4. To effect necessary legislation so as to protect the interests of the State, and provide an equitable rule, in the re-sale of lands purchased by the State at tax sales, between the original owner and the State.</p>
<p>5. To consider and provide a remedy for wanton destruction of fences.</p>
<p>6. To provide a more efficient system of highways, and to amend the law providing a penalty for enclosing school lands.</p>
<p>7. To provide some mode by which the agents of the State at the Capital can take care of and protect the property of the State.</p>
<p>8. To amend the law organizing the judicial districts of the State.</p>
<p>9. To determine whether or not the common school funds shall be invested in any other securities than those named in the Constitution; and, if so, to provide therefor.</p>
<p>10. To determine whether or not the State shall be represented at the Exposition to be held in New Orleans in 1885; and, if so, to provide therefor.</p>
<p>11. To make appropriations to meet deficiencies in appropriations heretofore made for Texas Veterans, and the contingent expenses, the per diem pay and mileage of the Eighteenth Legislature.</p>
<p>12. To authorize counties to issue bonds for the purpose of funding their indebtedness, created for other purposes than for the erection of court houses; and to allow the Board of Education to transfer State and Federal bonds to the University fund.</p>
<p>13. To amend the law passed at the regular session of the Eighteenth Legislature, approved April 12, 1883, entitled &#8220;An act to provide for the classification, sale and lease of lands heretofore or hereafter surveyed and set apart for the benefit of the<pb n="539" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Proclamation.</fw>Common School, University, Lunatic, Blind, Deaf and Dumb, and Orphan Asylum funds.</p>
<p>14. The re-enactment of the bill amending the attachment law, passed at regular last session, but which never reached the Executive.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I have hereto signed my name, and <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L. S.]</p></body></floatingText>have caused to be impressed hereon the seal of State, at Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin, this the 15th day of October, A. D. 1883.</p>
<closer>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, <lb/>Governor.</signed>
<signed>By the Governor: <lb/>JOS. W. BAINES, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<pb n="540" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="viii" />
</div2>
<pb n="541" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Proclamation.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS OF TEXAS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 12.] CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to defray the contingent expenses of the Eighteenth Legislature, convened on January 8, 1884, in Extra Session by Proclamation of the Governor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, it is of sufficient importance that the contingent expenses of the Extra Session of the Eighteenth Legislature be promptly paid, in or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der that the material furnished and labor performed may be procured at cash prices; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of fifteen thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to pay the contingent expenses of the Extra Session of the Eighteenth Legislature, and that, except in the case of accounts for printing done and stationery furnished, the approval by the chairman of the committee on contingent expenses of either House, coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tersigned by the President of the Senate or Speaker of the House of Representatives, as the case may be, shall be sufficient authority to au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorize the Comptroller to issue his warrant on the State Treasurer for the payment of any account against said fund. The accounts for print<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and stationery shall take the course prescribed by the Revised Stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />utes.</p>
<p>Section 2. That the public importance of the objects herein contem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plated creates an imperative public necessity and emergency fully author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />izing the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring the reading of bills upon three several days, and the said rule is hereby suspended, and this act shall be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 12, originated in the House, and passed the same Jany. 10th 1884 by a &#8532; vote, ayes 88, nays 0.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 12, passed the Senate Jany. 11th 1884, by a &#8532; vote. Yeas 29.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 12th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<pb n="542" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 4.] CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation for mileage and per diem pay of mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers and per diem pay of officers and employees of the called session of the Eighteenth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of fifty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated, out of any moneys in the Treasury, not otherwise appropriated, for the payment of mileage and per diem pay of the members and the payment of the per diem pay of the officers and employees of the called session of the Eighteenth Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature.</p>
<p>Section 2. That the certificate of the Secretary of the Senate, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the President thereof, or the certificate of the Chief Clerk of the House, approved by the Speaker thereof, shall be sufficient evidence to the Comptroller, upon which he shall audit the claims and issue his warrants upon the Treasurer for the respective amounts.</p>
<p>Section 3. That the balance of the moneys remaining in the Treasury heretofore appriated for the per diem pay and mileage of the members and the per diem pay of the officers and employees of any preceding ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of the Legislature of the State of Texas, be and the same is hereby re-appropriated for the purposes specified in this act.</p>
<p>Section 4. And whereas, the called session of the Eighteenth Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture for the payment of the members and officers of which this law is en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />acted, is now in session, and public policy requires this payment, there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore an imperative public necessity exists, that the rule rquiring this bill to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is so enacted, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 4, originated in the House and passed the same Jany 10th 1884 by a &#8532; vote. Ayes 88, nays 1.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 4 passed the Senate Jany 11th 1884, by a &#8532; vote, Ayes 26, nays none.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 14th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<pb n="543" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>H. B. No. 5.]</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act entitled &#8220;An Act to redistrict the State into Judicial Districts and fix the times for holding court therein, and to provide for the election of Judges and District Attorneys in said dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricts at the next general election to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in Nov. 1884. Approved April 9th 1883.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State Texas, That section 10 of an act entitled: An Act to redistrict the State into judicial districts and fix the times for holding court therein and to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vide for the election of judges and district attorneys in said districts at the next general election to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in Nov. 1884, appoved April 9, 1883, be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The county of Galveston shall constitute the tenth judicial district and the District Court shall be begun and held therein as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows: On the first Mondays in February, April, June, October and De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cember and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 17th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 33.] CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act making appropriations for deficiencies in the appropriations here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tofore made for payment of expenses in support of the government from March 1, 1883, to February 29, 1884, and for payment of the annual interest on the public debt from March 1st 1884, to February 28th 1885.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the following sums or so much thereof as may be necessary be and the same are hereby appropriated out of the monies in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for deficiencies in the appropriations heretofore made for payment of expenses in support of the Government from March 1, 1883 to February 29, 1884, and for payment of the annual interest on the public debt from March 1, 1884 to February 28, 1885.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Deficiencies in Pensions to Texas Veterans.</head>
<p>To pay deficiencies in the appropriations for Texas Veterans. $75,000 00</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Deficiencies in Contingent Expenses.</head>
<p>To pay deficiencies in the appropriation for contingent ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses and to pay officers and employees of the regular ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of the Eighteenth Legislature..... $1,250 00</p>
<p>For payment of annual interest on State bonds now outstand<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, from March 1, 1884 to February 28th 1885.....$244,062 20</p>
<p>For payment of the expenses of attached witnesses in felony cases..... $15,000 00</p>
<pb n="544" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>For sheriffs, district attorneys, clerks, justices of the peace and other officers in criminal matters..... $5,000 00</p>
<p>Section 2. That whereas the deficiencies named in the preceding sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion remain due and unpaid, to the inconvenience of parties due the same, therefore an emergency and necessity exists for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house, and said rule is so suspended, and that this act should take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 33, originated in the House, and passed the same by a &#8532; vote, Jany. 22, 1884, Ayes 82.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 33, passed the Senate Jany. 25, 1884, by a &#8532; vote Ayes 26.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 28th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 30.] CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend section 40 of an act entitled: An act to redistrict the State into judicial districts and fix the times for holding court therein, and to provide for the election of judges and district attorneys in said Districts at the next general election to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in November 1884. Approved, April 9, 1883.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That, section 40 of an act entitled: An act to redistrict the State into judicial districts and fix the times for holding court therein; and to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vide for the election of Judges and District Attorneys in said districts at the next general election to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in November 1884. Approved, April 9, 1883 shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 40. A district attorney shall be elected in each of the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing districts at the next general election, towit: First, Second, Third, Fourth, Fifth, Seventh, Eighth, Ninth, Twelfth, Thirteenth, Twentieth, Twenty-first, Twenty-second, Twenty-third, Twenty-fourth, Twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fifth, Twenty-sixth, Twenty-seventh, Twenty-eighth, Twenty-ninth, Thirtieth, Thirty-first, Thirty-second, Thirty-third, Thirty-fourth, Thir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty-fifth, Thirty-sixth, Thirty-seventh and Thirty-eighth.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 28th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="545" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. S. B. No. 70.] CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend section 16, of an act entitled &#8220;An act to redistrict the State into Judicial Districts and fix the times for holding court therein and to provide for the election of Judges and district attorneys in said districts at the next general election, to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in November 1884,&#8221; approved April 9th 1883.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas; That Section 16, of the above recited act be amended, so as hereafter to read as follows;</p>
<p>Section 16. The Sixteenth Judicial District shall be composed of the counties of Denton, Wise, Montague and Cooke and the District Court shall be held therein as follows: In the county of Denton on the first Mondays in January and August, and may continue in session six weeks: In the county of Wise on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and August and may continue in session five weeks: In the county of Montague on the eleventh Mondays after the first Mondays in January and August and may continue in session four weeks: In the county of Cooke on the fifteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and August and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Section 2. The large amount of business to be transacted during the remainder of this session, and the necessity that this act should be passed at the present session, creates an imperative necessity that the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house, be suspended and said rule is therefore suspended.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. S. B. No. 70 originated in the Senate and passed the same January 23rd 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. S. B. No. 70 passed the House of Representatives January 28th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk House of Representatives.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 30th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 34.] CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend &#8220;an act to redistrict the State into judicial districts and fix the times for holding court therein, and to provide for the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of Judges and District Attorneys in said districts, at the next general election to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day in November 1884, approved April 9th 1883,&#8221; in so far as the same relates to the second and third judicial districts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of<pb n="546" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Texas, that the act of the Legislature entitled &#8220;An act to redistrict the State into judicial districts and fix the times for holding courts therein, and to provide for the election of Judges and District Attorneys in said districts, at the next general election, to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in November 1884," approved April 9th 1883, in so far as the same relates to the second and third judicial districts shall be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The second judicial district shall be composed of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of Sabine, San Augustine, Nacogdoches and Cherokee; and the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict courts shall be held therein as follows; In the county of Sabine on the first Monday in February and September and may continue in session two weeks. In the county of San Augustine on the second Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September and may continue in session four weeks. In the county of Nacogdoches on the sixth Monday after the first Mondays in February and September and may continue in session six weeks. In the county of Cherokee on the twelfth Monday after the first Monday in February and September and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Third Judicial District shall be composed of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of Henderson, Houston and Anderson and the District Courts shall be held therein as follows. In the county of Henderson on the first Monday in February and September, and may continue in session four weeks. In the county of Houston on the fourth Monday after the first Monday in February and September and may continue in session seven weeks. In the county of Anderson on the eleventh Monday after the first Monday in February and September and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. A District Judge shall be elected in each of said districts, viz: the second and third Judicial Districts, at the next general election in this State, to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in No<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vember A. D. 1884, and the Judges so elected shall hold their offices, for the term of four years.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. A district attorney shall be elected in the second and third judicial districts at said general election in the year 1884.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. All writs and process, civil and criminal, heretofore issued or which, may be issued, and made returnable to the terms of said district courts, as said terms are fixed by law, (now) at the time this act takes effect, shall be and are hereby made returnable to the next ensuing terms of said courts, as they are prescribed in this act,&#8212;and all writs and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cess issued by or from said courts after the adjournment of the term last held under the law as it exists, at the time of the passage of this act, shall be made returnable to the terms as prescribed in this act, and all such writs and process hereinbefore mentioned are hereby legalized and vali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dated to all intents and purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The courts shall be held under this act on and after the first Monday in September A. D. 1884.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The Governor shall appoint a District Judge, for the third Judicial District during the month of August A. D. 1884, who shall hold his office until the election and qualification of<pb n="547" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>his successor. At the date of such appointment the Judge of the pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent third Judicial District shall be the Judge of the second District as prescribed in this act, and on and after the first Monday in September 1884, the counties of Henderson, Houston and Anderson shall cease to be a portion of any other judicial district and be and become the third Judicial District of Texas, and the counties of Sabine, San Augustine, Nacogdoches and Cherokee shall be and become the Second Judicial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict of Texas, until the said first Monday in September A. D. 1884, the District Courts shall be held in all the counties mentioned in this act as now prescribed by law and as portions of the district of which they are now a part, except that the terms of the court in Henderson county shall not be held in August A. D. 1884.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The District Attorney of the Third Judicial District as it now exists, shall continue to be District Attorney of the Third Judicial District as it is herein established until the election and qualification of a district attorney at the general election in the year 1884 and the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Attorney of the fourth District shall continue to be the district attorney thereof until the election and qualification of his successor at the general election in the year 1884; and the Governor shall appoint a Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Attorney for the second Judicial District as herein organized, on or before Sept. 1st 1884 who shall hold his office until the election and qual<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ification of his successor at the general election in the year 1884.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The near approach of the end of the session, creates a ne<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessity for the suspension of the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days, and it is hereby suspended.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 34, originated in the Senate and passed the same January 23rd 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 34 passed the House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives January 28th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J.W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk House of Representatives.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 30th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 68.] CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend section 4, of an act entitled: &#8220;An act to reorganize the Twelfth, Sixteenth, Seventeenth, Twenty-Ninth, Thirty-Fourth and Thirty-Fifth Judicial Districts and to fix the times of holding the courts therein; to change the times for holding the District Courts in the Seventh and Fourteenth Judicial Districts and in the counties of Kaufman, Sabine, San Augustine and Nacogdoches, and to provide for a District Attorney in the Sixteenth Judicial District,&#8221; approved, March 27, 1883.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Sec. 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That section 4 of an act entitled: &#8220;An act to reorganize the Twelfth, Sixteenth, Seventeenth, Twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="548" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Fourth and Thirty-Fifth Judicial Districts, and to fix the times of hold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the courts therein; to change times for holding the District Courts in the Seventh and Fourteenth Judicial Districts, and in the counties of Kaufman, Sabine, San Augustine and Nacogdoches, and to provide for a District Attorney in the Sixteenth Judicial District,&#8221; approved March 27, 1883, be and the same is hereby amended so as to read, hereafter as follows:</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Section 4.</head>
<p>That the counties of Wheeler, Oldham, Donley and the unorganized counties of Collingsworth, Greer, Childress, Hall, Briscoe, Floyd, Par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mer, Castro, Swisher, Armstrong, Randall, Deaf Smith, Potter, Carson, Gray, Hemphill, Roberts, Hutchinson, Moore, Hartley, Dallam, Sher<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man, Hansforth, Ochiltree and Lipscomb, be and the same are hereby constituted the Thirty-fifth Judicial District and the District court shall be held in the counties composing said District as follows: In the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty of Donley on the first Mondays in January and July, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session four weeks. In the county of Oldham on the fourth Monday after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session four weeks. In the county of Wheeler on the first Mondays in April, and November and may continue in session four weeks. The un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />organized counties of Sherman, Moore, Potter, Castro, Parmer, Deaf Smith, Hartley and Dallam are hereby attached to the county of Oldham for Judicial purposes; the unorganized counties of Carson, Randall, Arm<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strong, Swisher, Floyd, Briscoe, Hall and Childress are hereby attached to the county of Donley for for Judicial purposes; the unorganized coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of Greer, Collingsworth, Gray, Hutchinson, Hansford, Ochiltree, Roberts, Hemphill and Lipscomb are hereby attached to the county of Wheeler for Judicial purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that this act changes the times of holding the Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Courts in Wheeler and Oldham counties so that the next District Court of Oldham county should be held in February next creates an im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perative public necessity and an emergency exists requiring the immedi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate passage of this act and that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended and that this act take effect from and after its passage and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 68 originated in the House and passed the same Jany. 16th 1884, by a &#8532; vote, ayes 84, nays none.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk, House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 68, passed the Senate Jany. 28th 1884, by a &#8532; vote, ayes 28 nays none.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 30th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<pb n="549" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 35.] CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend section 30 of &#8220;an act to redistrict the State into judicial districts and fix the times for holding courts therein and to provide for the election of judges and district attorneys in said districts at the next general election to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in November 1881&#8221; approved April 9th 1883.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas; That section 30, of &#8220;an act to redistrict the State into judicial districts and fix the times for holding courts therein and to provide for the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of judges and district attorneys in said districts at the next general election to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in No<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vember 1884&#8221; approved April 9th, 1883, shall hereafter read as follows:.</p>
<p>Section 30. The thirtieth judicial district shall be composed of the counties of Jack, Clay, Wichita, Archer, Young, Throckmorton, Baylor and Wilbarger and the unorganized counties of Hardeman, Knox, Has<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />kell, King, Lamb, Bailey, Dickens, Crosby, Lubbock, Hockley, Cochran and Cottle and the district courts shall be held therein as follows: In the county of Jack on the second Mondays in January and July and may continue in session three weeks: in the county of Young on the third Monday after the second Mondays in January and July and may continue in session three weeks: in the county of Throckmorton on the sixth Monday after the second Mondays in January and July and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session two weeks; in the county of Baylor on the eighth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day after the second Mondays in January and July and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Wilbarger on the tenth Monday, after the second Mondays in January and July and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Wichita on the twelfth Monday after the sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ond Mondays in January and July and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Archer on the fourteenth Monday after the second Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in January and July and may continue in session two weeks: in the county of Clay on the sixteenth Monday after the second Mondays in January and July and may continue in session four weeks; the county of Haskell be and the same is hereby attached for judicial purposes to the county of Throckmorton: the counties of King, Lamb, Bailey, Dick<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ens, Crosby, Lubbock, Hockley, Cochran, and Knox, to the county of Baylor: the counties of Hardeman and Cottle to the county of Wilbarger, and when the county of Knox shall be organized, the county of King shall be attached to it for judicial purposes and the county of Cottle to the county of Hardeman whenever the county of Hardeman shall be or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganized.</p>
<p>Section 2. All judges heretofore elected or appointed and whose terms of office shall not expire at the next general election, shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue to hold their offices until the terms for which they were appointed or elected shall expire and shall hold the courts in the District in which they reside.</p>
<p>Section 3. All laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<pb n="550" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Section 4. The near approach of the close of the present session of the Legislature and the great amount of business requiring action, creates an imperative public necessity for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each House, said rule is therefore suspended.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 35, originated in the Senate and passed the same January 23rd 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 35, passed the House of Representatives January 38th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk of the House of Representatives.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>January 30th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. H. B. No. 11] CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend article 413, chapter 2, Title 13, of an act entitled: &#8220;An act to adopt and establish a Penal Code and a code of criminal proced<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ure for the State of Texas,&#8221; passed February 21, 1879, and to repeal all laws in conflict therewith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Article 413, Chapter 2 Title 13 of an act entitled, &#8220;An act to adopt and establish a Penal Code and a Code of Criminal Procedure for the State of Texas&#8221; passed February 21, 1879, be so amended as to here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after read as follows:</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 413.</head>
<p>Any person or persons placing a gate on or across any third class road, or on or across any road such as is designated in article 412 of the Penal Code shall be required to keep said gate and the approaches to the same in good order, and the gate shall be ten feet wide and so constructed as to cause no unnecessary delay to the travelling public in opening and shut<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ting the same; and provide a fastening to hold said gate open till the passengers go through and such person or persons shall place a perma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nent hitching post and stile block on each side of and within sixty feet of such gate. Any person or persons, who may hereafter place a gate on or across a third class road, or on or across any road such as is desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated in article 412, who shall wilfully or negligently fail to comply with the requirements of this article shall be deemed guilty of a mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demeanor, and on conviction may be fined in any sum not less than five nor more than twenty dollars for each offense, and each week of such failure shall constitute a seperate offense. Any person or persons, who shall wilfully or negligently leave<pb n="551" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>open any gate on or across any third class road or on or across any road such as is designated in article 412, shall be deemed guilty of a misde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />meanor, and on conviction may be fined in any sum as above provided for.</p>
<p>Section 2. All laws and parts of laws in conflict herewith be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Section 3. The near approach of the close of the present session of the Legislature and the importance of this bill creates an imperative pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic necessity and emergency that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. H. B. No. 11, originated in the House and passed the same Jany. 17th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk, House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. H. B. No. 11, passed the Senate Jany. 28th, 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 2nd, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 28.] CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Article 4360, of Title 87, Chapter One, providing for the establishment of Public Roads, and to prohibit Commissioners&#8217; Courts from altering or changing Public Roads, except for the purpose of shortening the distance from the point of beginning to the point of destination, and to repeal all laws in conflict with this act.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Article 4360, Title 87, Chapter One, shall be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4360.</head>
<p>The Commissioners&#8217; courts, of the several counties shall have full power and it shall be their duty to order the laying out and opening of Public Roads when necessary, and to discontinue or alter any road when<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever it shall be deemed expedient, as whereinafter prescribed, provided that hereafter no public road shall be altered or changed, except for the purpose of shortening the distance from the point of beginning to the point of destination.</p>
<p>Section 2. All laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 2nd, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<pb n="552" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 92.] CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to make an appropriation to be used by the Governor for the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of rewards and ferreting out and suppressing crime.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the sum of fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) or so much thereof as may be necessary is hereby appropriated out of any money in the treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ury not otherwise appropriated, to be used by the Governor for the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of rewards, and ferreting out and suppressing crime.</p>
<p>Section 2. The wide-spread and increasing lawlessness in this State, and the growing insecurity of life and property create an emergency and an imperative public necessity which requires that the constitutional rule that bills be read on three several days be suspended and that this act take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 92, originated in the House and passed the same by a &#8532; vote Feby. 3d 1884 ayes 93 nays 0.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk of House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. 92 passed the Senate by a &#8532; vote, Feby. 2d 1884, ayes 27, nays 1.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 4th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. H. B. 6, 23, 24, 25, 26, 29, 34, 43, 47 and 63.] CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend articles 4360, 4361, 4366, 4367, 4370, 4371, 4372, 4375, 4379, 4384, 4387, 4389, and 4390, of Title 87, chapter one and to add thereto articles 4390a, 4390b, 4390c, and also to amend article 4392 of chapter 2, and article 4418 of chapter 4, Title 87 of the revised civil statutes relating to Public roads and to enforce the provisions of article 4390a, of this bill and to provide adequate penalties therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That articles 4390a, 4390b, 4390c, be added to chapter 1, Title 87, of the Revised Civil Statutes, and that articles 4360, 4361, 4366, 4367, 4370 4371, 4372, 4375, 4379, 4384, 4389 and 4390, of said chapter and title, and article 4392, chapter 2, and article 4418 chapter 4, Title 87, be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4360.</head>
<p>The Commissioners&#8217; Courts of the several counties, shall have<pb n="553" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>full power, and it shall be their duty, to order the laying out and open<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of public roads when necessary, and to discontinue or alter any road, whenever it shall be deemed expedient, as hereafter prescribed; provided, that hereafter no public road shall be altered or changed except for the purpose of shortening the distance from the point of beginning to the point of destination.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4361.</head>
<p>It shall be the duty of the Commissioners&#8217; Courts to classify all public roads in their counties into first, second and third class roads, and to act as supervisors of roads in their respective precincts as hereinafter provided, and Commissioners&#8217; Courts may, on their own motion, where it is deemed necessary, open new roads or straighten existing ones.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4366.</head>
<p>All applications for a new road, and all all applications to discontinue an existing one, shall be by petition to the Commissioners&#8217; Court, signed by at least eight freeholders in the precinct or precincts in which such road is desired to be made or discontinued, specifying in such petition the beginning and termination of such road proposed to be opened or dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />continued, provided, that where one or more persons live within any enclosure either or all of them may petition the Commissioners&#8217; Court for a third class road or neighborhood road to their nearest trading points, mills, gins, school and church houses and county seats, and the courts shall open such roads, as hereinafter provided in the opening of third class roads: and provided further, that no part of a public road shall be discontinued, unless a new road connecting that part of such roads, not discontinued shall first be opened, and provided further, that no part of a first or second class road shall be reduced to a road of a lower class.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4367.</head>
<p>All roads hereafter ordered to be made shall be laid out by a jury of of freeholders of the county, to be appointed by the commissioners&#8217; court. Said jury shall consist of five persons, a majority of whom may proceed, with the county surveyor, to lay out, survey and describe such road, to the greatest advantage to the public and so that the same can be traced with certainty and the field notes of such survey and description of the road shall be included in the report of the jury, and if adopted shall be recorded in the minutes of the commissioners&#8217; courts.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4370.</head>
<p>The jury of freeholders provided for in article 4367 shall issue a notice in writing to the land owners through whose lands such proposed road may run, or to his agent or at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />torney, of the time when they will proceed to lay out such road, or when they will assess the damages incidental to the opening<pb n="554" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of the same, which notice shall be served upon such owner, his agent or attorney, at least five days before the day therein named. If such owner is a non-resident of the county the notice may be given by publication in a news paper published in the county, as notices are required to be given to non-resident defendants as to action in the district or county court, and the road may be established after four weeks publication, the cost of publishing to be paid as directed by judgament of the court.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4371.</head>
<p>The owner of any such land may, at the time stated in such notice, or previously thereto, present to the jury a statement in writing of the dam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ages claimed by him, if any, incidental to the opening of such road, and thereupon the jury shall proceed to assess the damages, returning their assessment and the claimant&#8217;s statement with their report, to the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners&#8217; court.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4372.</head>
<p>If the commissioners&#8217; court shall approve of the report and order such road to be opened, they shall consider the assessment of damages by the jury and the claimant&#8217;s statement thereof, and allow to such owner just damages and adequate compensation for the land taken, and when paid or secured by deposit with the county treasurer, to the credit of such owner, they may proceed to have such road opened. If the owner of the land is not satisfied with the assessment by the commissioners&#8217; court, he may appeal therefrom as in cases of appeal from judgment of Justices&#8217; Court, but such appeal shall not prevent the road from being opened, but shall be only to fix the amount of damages. If no claim of damages is filed with such jury, after notice as provided in the preceding article, the same shall be considered as waived.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4375.</head>
<p>The Commissioners&#8217; Court may alter or change the course of any pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic road in accordance with article 4360 of this chapter, after notice and upon application in the same manner as provided in this chapter for the discontinuance of a road, except that that the application need not be signed by more than one freeholder of the precinct in which such altera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion or change is proposed to be made.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4379.</head>
<p>For further and better providing for public roads, any lines be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween different persons or owners of land, any section line, or any direct line through an enclosure containing twelve hundred and eighty acres of land or more, may, upon the conditions pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for in the following articles of this chapter, be declared pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic highways, and left open and free from all obstructions for fifteen feet on either side of said lines, but the marked<pb n="555" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>trees and other objects used to designate said lines, and the corners of surveys, shall not be removed or defaced.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4384.</head>
<p>At a regular term of the court, after due service of notice as provided in the preceding article, the commissioners&#8217; court may, in its discretion, should it deem the road of sufficient public importance, issue an order declaring the lines designated in the application to be public highways, and direct that the same be opened by the owners thereof and left open for a space of fifteen feet on each side of said line.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4387.</head>
<p>All costs attending the proceedings provided for in relation to opening of neighborhood roads shall be paid by the county, if the application be granted.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4389.</head>
<p>The owners of the land whose lines have been or may be declared pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic highways and also any person through whose land a third class road may run, shall have the right to erect a gate or gates across said road or roads when necessary said, gate or gates to be not less than ten feet wide and free of obstructions at the top, provided, that when the right of way for any third class road or neighborhood road has been granted to the county without cost, the owner of such land shall have the right to put a gate across such road or roads; but where such right of way has been condemned and paid for according to existing law, the county commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners&#8217; court shall have the right to prevent any obstruction of such a road by a gate.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4390.</head>
<p>The amount of damages to be allowed to the owners of said lands for opening the line of a neighborhood road, as provided in this chapter, shall be assessed as provided for in the case of first, second and third class roads in this chapter.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4390a.</head>
<p>The county commissioners of the several counties are hereby consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tuted supervisors of public roads in their respective counties, and each commissioner shall supervise the public roads within his commissioner&#8217;s precinct once each year and shall receive as compensation therefor three dollars per day for the time actually employed in the discharge of his duties, to be paid out of the road and bridge fund of the county, provided, that no commissioner shall receive pay for more than ten days in each year. He shall also make a report to the first regular term of the commissioners&#8217; court held in his county during the year, said report to be made under oath, and to state: First, the<pb n="556" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>condition of all roads and parts of roads in his precinct, Second, the condition of all culverts and bridges. Third, the amount of money re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />maining in the hands of overseers subject to be expended upon the roads within his precinct. Fourth the number of mile posts, and finger boards defaced, and torn down. Fifth, what, if any, new roads of any kind should be opened in his precinct, and what, if any, bridges, culverts or other improvements are necessary to place the roads in his precinct in good condition and the probable cost of such improvements, also, the name of any overseer who has failed to work the road, or in any way neglected to perform his duty. Said report shall be spread upon the minutes of the court to be considered in improving public roads and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />termining the amount of taxes to be levied therefor and if any commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of any commissioners&#8217; court in any county in this State shall fail or refuse to discharge any or all duties made obligatory upon him by the provisions of section 1, article 4390a he shall be deemed guilty of a mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demeanor, and, upon conviction therefor before any court of competent jurisdiction, shall be fined in any sum not less than ten nor more than fifty dollars.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4390b.</head>
<p>No entire road of the first or second class shall hereafter be discon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinued except upon vacation by order of the commissioners&#8217; court or non use for a period of three years.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4390c.</head>
<p>The report made by the supervisors of public roads to the commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners&#8217; court, as provided for in article 4390a shall be submitted, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gether with all contracts made by said court since its last report for any work on any road, to the grand jury, at the first term of the district court thereafter.</p>
<p>Section 2. Article 4392. An overseer shall be appointed and hands apportioned by said court for each road precinct at the time of establish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the same; and at the first regular term of court in each year, the said court shall appoint an overseer for each road precinct in the county, and shall at the same time designate all the hands liable to work on public roads, and apportion them to the several overseers; provided, that hands shall as nearly as practicable be apportioned to work on the road precinct nearest to their place of abode; and provided further, that the supervisor of public roads shall at any time apportion any hands in his precinct, who, from any cause, may not have been apportioned as otherwise pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided in this act.</p>
<p>Section 3. Article 4418. It shall be the duty of the overseer, within ten days after he has had his road worked, to file with the county attorney of his county, or the justice of the peace of his precinct, a complaint in writing, and under oath against each person who has been summoned to work and who has failed to work and failed to furnish a substitute, and has failed to pay one dollar for each day he has so failed to work or furnish a substitute, and also against each person so so sum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="557" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>moned who has refused to do a reasonable amount of work on the road, or who has refused to perform the reasonable directions of the overseer.</p>
<p>Section 4. The fact that the commissioners&#8217; court of the several counties will shortly meet and levy taxes for 1884, and the further fact, that it is important for this act to go into effect immediately, for the purpose of securing to the people the full benefit of the recently adopted constitutional amendments, constitute an imperative public necessity, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quiring that the constitutional requirement requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended; therefore it is enacted that the consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tutional rule be suspended and that this act, take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. H. B. 6, 23, 24, 25, 26, 29, 34, 43, 47 and 63, originated in the House and passed the same by &#8532; vote Jan. 23d 1884 ayes 89, nays 5.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk, House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. H. B. 6, 23, 24, 25, 26, 29, 34, 43, 47, and 63, passed the Senate Feby. 2nd 1884, ayes 18 nays 8.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL KAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 5th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 44.] CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Article 804, Chapter 1, Title XVIII, of the Penal Code.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Article 804, Chapter 1, Title XVIII, of the Penal Code of the State of Texas be and the same is hereby so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 804.</head>
<p>The agreement to come within the definition of conspiracy must be to commit one or more of the following offenses, to-wit: Murder, robbery, arson, burglary, rape, or any other offense of the grade of a felony.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that property in this State is being wilfully wantonly destroyed daily creates an imperative public necessity that, this bill be in force and take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B., No. 44, originated in the House, and passed the same, Jan&#8217;y 31, &#8216;84, by a &#8532;ds vote, to-wit: Ayes 75.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk of the House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<pb n="558" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B., No. 44, passed the Senate, Feb&#8217;y 4, &#8216;84, by &#8532;ds vote, to-wit: Ayes 23.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 5th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. H. B. 56 &#38; 67.] CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend, sections 31 and 38 of an act entitled, &#8220;an act to redis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict the State into judicial districts, and fix the times for holding court therein, and to provide for the election of judges and district attorneys in said districts, at the next general election to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in November 1884, approved April 9, 1883.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section. 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That sections thirty one (31) and thirty-eight (38) of an act entitled, &#8220;an act to redistrict the State into judicial districts, and fix the times for holding court therein; and to provide for election of judges and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict attorneys in said districts at the next general election, to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in November, 1884, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved April 9, 1883,&#8221; be so amended as hereafter to read as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 31. The thirty-first judicial district shall be composed of the counties of Wheeler, Oldham, Donley and the unorganized counties, of Greer, Collingsworth, Childress, Hall, Motley, Floyd, Briscoe, Swisher, Hale, Castro, Parmer, Deaf Smith, Randall, Armstrong, Gray, Carson, Potter, Hartley, Moore, Hutchinson, Roberts, Hemphill, Lipscomb, Ochiltree, Hansford, Sherman and Dallam; and the district courts shall be held therein as follows: In the county of Donley on the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session four weeks; in the county of Oldham on the fourth Monday after the first Mondays in Jan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uary and July, and may continue in session four weeks: in the county of Wheeler on the first Mondays in April and November, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session four weeks. The unorganized counties of Carson, Ran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dall, Armstrong, Swisher, Hale, Floyd Briscoe, Hall, Motley and Childress are attached to the county of Donley for judicial purposes. The unor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganized counties of Sherman, Moore, Potter, Castro, Parmer, Deaf Smith, Hartley and Dallam shall be attached to the county of Oldham for ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial purposes, and the unorganized counties of Greer, Colingsworth, Gray, Hutchinson Hansford, Ochiltree, Roberts, Hemphill and Lipscomb are attached to the county of Wheeler for judicial purposes.</p>
<p>Section 38. The Thirty-eighth judicial district shall be composed of the counties of Comal, Kendall, Kerr, Bandera, Medina Uvalde, Edwards, Kinney, and Crockett, and the district courts therein shall be held as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows: In the county of Kinney on the first Mondays in March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Uvalde on the second Monday after the first Mondays in March and Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="559" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ber, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Medina on the fourth Monday after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Bandera on the sixth Monday after the first Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session two weeks; in the county of Kerr on the eighth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Kendall on the eleventh Monday after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Comal on the thirteenth Monday after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of. The unorganized county of Edwards is hereby attached to the county of Kerr for judicial purposes, and the county of Crockett is hereby attached to the county of Kinney for judicial purposes.</p>
<p>Section 2. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Section 3. The near approach of the close of the session of the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature creates an imperative public necessity, which justifies the suspen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and the same is therefore suspended.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. H. B. 56 &#38; 67, originated in the House and passed the same Jany. 28th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk, House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. H. B. 56 &#38; 67 passed the Senate<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />February 1st 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 5th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 72.] CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Articles 3027 and 3029 of Chapter 3 Title 57 of the Revised Statutes of the State of Texas:</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That articles 3027 and 3029 Chapter 3, Title 57, of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas be and they are hereby so amended as hereafter to read as follows, to wit:</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 3027.</head>
<p>The County Court shall at its first term after the 31st day of December and the 30th day of June of each year appoint three persons to perform the duties of Jury Commissioners for said<pb n="560" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Court who shall possess the same qualifications as Jury Commissioners for the District Court and the same proceedings shall be had in the County Court by the officers thereof and by the commissioners for pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curing jurors as are required by this title for similar proceedings in the district court except as modified by the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 3029.</head>
<p>Such commissioners shall select jurors for all the terms of the County Court to be holden within six months next after the adjournment of the first term of said court after the said 31st day of December and the 30th day of June of each year and the County Judge shall designate the num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of jurors to be so selected for each term and week.</p>
<p>Section 2. The fact that there is no law now in force authorizing the appointment of Jury Commissioners for the County Courts, and that said Courts will meet throughout the State on the first Monday in February next, creates an imperative public necessity and emergency that the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 72 originated in the House and passed the same Jany 18th 1884. Ayes 73, nays 9.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk, House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 72 passed the Senate Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary 2nd 1884. Ayes 24</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<p>NOTE.&#8212;The foregoing bill was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the 4th day of February A. D. 1884, and was not signed by him, or returned to the House in which it originated, with his ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jection thereto, within the time prescribed by the constitution, and there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />upon became a law without his signature.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BAINES, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H. B. So. 98.] CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend chapter 9, section 1, of an act of the regular session of the Seventeenth Legislature entitled: &#8220;an act authorizing the county commissioners&#8217; court of the several counties of this State to issue bonds for the erection of a court-house, and to levy a tax to pay for the same, approved Feb&#8217;y 11, 1881,&#8221; so as to include the issue of jail bonds.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section 1 of chapter 9, of the laws of the regular<pb n="561" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>session of the Seventeenth Legislature be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Section 1.</head>
<p>That the county commissioners court of any county is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized and empowered to issue the bonds of said county, with interest coupons attached, in such amount as may be necessary to erect a suitable building for a court-house, or jail, or both; said bonds running not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding fifteen years, and redeemable at the pleasure of the county, and bearing interest at a rate not exceeding eight per cent, per annum.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas there are now many counties in this state without suitable jails, and there is no law authorizing counties to issue bonds to pay for the construction of the same, therefore an imperative public necessity and emergency exists requiring the suspension of the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 98, originated in the House and passed the same by a &#8532;ds vote, Jan&#8217;y 30, &#8216;84, ayes 87, nays 4.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk of the House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 98, passed the Senate, Feb&#8217;y 2d, &#8216;84 by a &#8532;rds, vote&#8212;Ayes 23, Nays&#8212;</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<p>NOTE&#8212;The foregoing bill was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the 4th day of February 1884, and was not signed by him or returned to the house in which it originated, with his objec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion thereto, within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />upon became a law without his signature.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BAINES, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 68.] CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize counties to issue bonds for bridge purposes and to levy a tax to pay the same; also to validate bonds heretofore issued for bridge purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas; That the County Commissioners Courts of the several counties of this State are hereby authorized and empowered to issue the bonds of said county, with interest coupons attached, for such amounts as may be necessary for the purpose of buy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing or constructing bridges for public uses within such county,<pb n="562" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>said bonds to run not exceeding twenty years and bear interest at any rate not to exceed eight per cent per annum.</p>
<p>Section 2. The Commissioners Court shall levy an annual advalorem tax, not to exceed fifteen cents on the one hundred dollars valuation, sufficient to pay the interest on, and create a sinking fund for the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demption of said bonds. The sinking fund herein provided for shall not be less than four per cent on the full sum for which the bonds are issued.</p>
<p>Section 3. Said bonds shall never be sold at less than their face value, and the interest on the same shall be paid annually on the 10th day of April of each year, and they shall be registered, and an account kept by the county treasurer of the amount of said bonds and the principal and interest paid on each, in a well bound book for that purpose; provided, that no county shall issue a larger amount of bonds than a tax of ten cents on the one hundred dollars valuation of property in the county will liquidate in ten years.</p>
<p>Section 4. Said bonds shall be signed by the County Judge and coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tersigned by the County Clerk, and registered by the treasurer before they are delivered.</p>
<p>Section 5. Moneys in the hands of the county treasurer belonging to the sinking fund of any county shall be first applied to the payment, of said bonds, or be invested in other bonds of that county, or other coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties in the State, or in bonds of this State or United States; provided in no case shall more than the face value be paid for the bonds above men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned.</p>
<p>Section 6. All bonds heretofore issued for the purposes named in this bill, are hereby validated; provided said bonds come within the limita<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of the provisions of this hill.</p>
<p>Section 7. The near approach of the close of the session of the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature and the importance of a law authorizing the issuance of bridge bonds, creates an emergency and a public necessity, that the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 68, originated in the Senate and passed the same Jany. 13th 1884&#8212;ayes 16&#8212;nays 11.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 68 passed the House of Representatives by &#8536; vote, Feby 2nd 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk, House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>NOTE.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the 4th day of February 1884 and was not signed by him or returned to the house in which it originated, with his objection thereto, within the time prescribed by the constitution and therefore be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />came a law without his signature.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BAINES, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="563" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 13.] CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend sections 3 and 11 of an act to provide for the sale of all real estate bid off to the State by collectors of taxes, at tax sales, the owners of which have not redeemed the same, approved April 7, 1879, and to extend the right of redemption.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That sections 3 and 11 of an act to provide for the sale of all real estate bid off to the State by collectors of taxes at tax sales, the owners of which have not redeemed the same, approved April 7, 1879, be so amended as to read as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 3. The collector of taxes shall, prior to the sale of any real estate that has been previously bid off to the State at tax sales, the own<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers of which have failed to redeem the same, advertise the real estate to be sold in some news paper published in the county for six successive weeks, if there be such news paper published therein, otherwise he shall post advertisements of said sale at the court house door and at one pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic place in each justices&#8217; precinct of his county, for at least six weeks, giving in said advertisement, whether published or posted such descrip<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the lands to be sold as shall be given on the Comptroller&#8217;s list and stating the time, place and terms of sale, which shall be between legal hours, on the first Tuesday of some specified month at the court house door at public out-cry, to the highest bidder for cash: provided, that no real estate shall, in any case be sold for less than the amount des<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ignated by the Comptroller as due thereon, together with all costs of advertisements and sale: and provided further, that no sales shall be made under the provisions of this act, until six months after the same goes into effect; and provided further, that the former owner of any such real real estate his heirs or assigns may redeem the same at any time prior to the sale thereof, by the payment to the collector of the county in which such real estate is situated, or to the Comptroller if in an unorganized county, of the amount, designated by the Comptroller as due thereon with costs of advertisement; and provided further, that if it shall at any time appear to the satisfaction of the Comptroller that, any land has been sold to the State for taxes which have, been paid, or that the sale has not been made in accordance with the law authorizing the sale of land for taxes he shall, upon payment of the amount that may be due thereon, cancel such sale, and in all cases he shall deliver to the owner of the land, or his agent, a certificate under seal of his department, set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ting forth the fact that such land has been redeemed, or that such sale has been cancelled, which certificate shall release the interest of the State and the same may be recorded in the proper county as other con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyances of real estate are recorded.</p>
<p>Section. 11. Taxes collected by State or county, by sales made under the provisions of this act, shall be placed to the credit of the different funds for which originally assessed under the direction respectively of the Comptroller of Public Accounts<pb n="564" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and the commissioners&#8217; court of the county in which the sale is made; the balance of the proceeds, after satisfying all taxes penalties and costs accrued, shall, under direction of the Comptroller, be placed in the Treasury of the State as a special tax sale fund, and be subject to be reclaimed by the owner or owners of the land on proof as required in case of escheated estates.</p>
<p>Section 2. That so much of said act hereby amended as is in conflict with the provisions of this act be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Section 3. Whereas, there is now no law authorizing the redemption of lands which have heretofore been sold for taxes, and which were bid off for the State, and on which time allowed by law for their redemption has expired; and whereas, the owners of said lands are anxious to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />deem the same; and whereas, such redemption will greatly increase the general revenue fund; therefore, an imperative public necessity and emergency exists for the suspension of the constitutional rule, requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house, and the same is hereby suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 13, originated in the House and passed the same Jany. 18th 1884, ayes 85.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk, House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 13 passed the Senate, Feby. 4th 1884, Ayes 22, nays 3.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 5th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. H. B. Nos. 86, 89, and 93.] CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend sections 5, 7, 26 and 39 of an act entitled, &#8220;An act to re-district the State into Judicial Districts and fix the times for hold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing courts therein; and to provide for the election of Judges and Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Attorneys in said districts at the next general election to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in November, 1884, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved, April 9, 1883.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That sections 5, 7, 26 and 39 of an act entitled, &#8220;An act to re-district the State into Judicial Districts and fix the times for holding courts therein; and to provide for the election of Judges and District Attorneys in said district at the next general election, to be held on the first Tues<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day after the first Monday in November, 1884, Approved April 9, 1883&#8221; be so amended so as to hereafter read as follows, to wit:</p>
<pb n="565" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Section 5. The fifth judicial district shall be composed of the counties of Bowie, Cass, Marion, Morris, Titus, Franklin and Camp, and the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict courts therein shall be held as follows, In the the county of Cass on the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session three weeks. In the county of Bowie on the third Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion three weeks. In the county of Morris on the sixth Monday after the first Mondays in February and September and may continue in session two weeks. In the county of Titus on the eighth Monday after the first Mondays in February and September and may continue in session two weeks. In the county Franklin on the tenth Monday after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in February and September and may continue in session two weeks. In the county of Camp on the twelfth Monday after the first Mondays in February and September and may continue in session three weeks. In the county of Marion on the fifteenth Monday after the first Mondays in February and September and may continue in session six weeks; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that no jury shall be empanelled in Marion county after the fourth weeks of said terms, unless the judge shall, in term time, make an order to be entered on the minutes of the district court, directing that juries be drawn for a longer time at the succeeding term.</p>
<p>Section 7. The seventh judicial district shall be composed of the counties of Upshur, Gregg, Smith, Van Zandt, Rains and Wood, and the district court therein shall be held as follows, In the county of Upshur on the first Mondays in January and July and may continue: in session two weeks. In the county of Gregg on the second Monday after the first Mondays in January and July and may continue in session three weeks. In the county of Smith on the fifth Monday after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in January and July and may continue in session eight weeks. In the county of Van Zandt on the thirteenth Monday after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in January and July and may continue in session four weeks. In the county of Rains on the seventeenth Monday after the first Mondays in January and July and may continue in session two weeks. In the county of Wood on the nineteenth Monday after the first Mondays in January and July and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>Section 26. The twenty sixth judicial district shall be composed of the counties of Williamson and Travis and the district courts shall be held therein as follows: In the county of Williamson on the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in January and July of each year and may continue in session six weeks, and in the county of Travis on the first Mondays in March and October of each year and may continue in session for the March term sixteen weeks, and for the October term twelve weeks.</p>
<p>Section 39. One district Judge shall be elected in each of the districts created by this act, at the next general election in this State, to be held on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in November A. D. 1884, and the Judges so elected shall hold their offices for the term of four years; provided, that the prov in of this section shall not apply to the thirtieth, thirty first, thirty<pb n="566" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>third and thirty sixth judicial districts, passed at the regular session of the Eighteenth Legislature, approved April 9, 1883.</p>
<p>Section 2. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Section 3. Whereas, the short time remaining of the present session, and the fact that it is important that this hill should be passed at once, creates a public emergency, therefore be it enacted that the constitutional rule requiring bills to read on three several days be and the same is hereby suspended.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. H. B. Nos. 86, 89 and 93, originated in the House and passed the same Jany. 28th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk, House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. H. B. Nos. 86, 89 and 93, passed the Senate Feby. 1st 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 6th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. H. B. Nos. 2, 8 &#38; 9.] CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prescribe the punishment for the wanton and wilful cutting, injuring or destroying fences.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any person who shall wantonly, or with intent to injure the owner, and wilfully cut, injure or destroy any fence, or part of a fence, (with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out such fence is the property of the person so cutting, injuring or de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stroying, the same,) shall be deemed guilty of an offense, and upon con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viction therefor shall be punished by confinement in the State Peneten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tiary for a term not less than one year nor more than five years. A fence within the meaning of this act is any structure of wood, wire, or of both, or of any other material, intended to prevent, the passage of cattle, horses, mules, asses, sheep, goats or hogs. Provided, however, that it shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute no offense for any person owning and residing upon land enclosed by the fence of another, who refuses permission to such person or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons so residing within said enclosure, free egress and ingress to their said land, for such person or persons to open a passage way through said en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />closure.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that fences are being continuously destroyed in many parts of the State by lawless persons, and the penalty now fixed by law is not of sufficient magnitude to deter of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fenders and suppress the crime, creates an emergency which justifies the suspension of the constitutional rule which requires bills to be read on three several days in both houses, and that<pb n="567" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>this act should take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. H. B. Nos. 2, 8 &#38; 9, originated in the House, and passed the same, Jan. 31st, &#8216;84, Toy &#8532; vote&#8212;Ayes 71, noes 22.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk of the House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. H. B. Nos. 2, 8 &#38; 9, passed the Senate, Jan&#8217;y 31st, &#8216;84, by &#8532; vote, towit: Ayes 28.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 6th, 1884</date>, at 10 a. m.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. S. B. No. 29.] CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize the owner or agent to render land for taxes due for the years 1871 to 1876 inclusive, and providing for the assessment and collection of taxes due thereon.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas; That the owner or agent of any land which has not been assessed for any year or years from A. D. 1871 to 1876, inclusive, may furnish the assessor of the county in which the land is situated, a list of such land with an affidavit of its cash value for the years for which the rendition is made, and the assessor, if satisfied with the valuation, shall assess the State, county and special taxes against the same, at the same rate assessed by the county court of the county in which the land is situated, upon other lands which were rendered and assessed for the year or years such taxes may be due and the Comptroller of public accounts, or the county col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lector, is hereby authorized to receive the taxes due thereon and receipt for the same and such receipt shall be a receipt in full for all tax due prior to 1876.</p>
<p>Section 2. All laws or parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act are hereby repealed. The near approach of the close of the pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent session of the Legislature creates an imperative, public necessity and emergency requiring bills to be react on three several days, be suspended and that this act take effect from and after its passage and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. S. B. No. 29 originated in the Senate and passed the same Feby. 4th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<pb n="568" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. S. B. No. 29 passed the House of Representatives&#8212;ayes 84, nays 1&#8212;Feby. 5th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk, House of Representatives.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 6th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 46.] CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the several county commissioners courts of the State<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of Texas to provide for more than four terms of the county court an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually, for the transaction of civil and criminal business.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the county commissioners courts of the several counties in the State may at a regular term thereof by an order entered upon the records of said court provide for more terms of the county court for the trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />action of civil, criminal and probate business and fix the times at which each of the four terms required by the constitution, and the terms ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding four, if any, shall be held, not to exceed six terms annually; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided that when the commissioners court shall have fixed the number of terms of the county court, by an order entered of record, said court shall not change the number of terms of the county court for one year from the date of the entry of the original order fixing the terms of the county court.</p>
<p>Section 2. The near approach of the close of the session rendering<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />it improbable that this bill will pass in the usual course of legislation, creates an imperative public necessity for the suspension of the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days and it is so suspended.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 46 originated in the Senate and passed the same Feby. 1st 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 46 passed the House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives Feby. 5th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk, House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>NOTE.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the 6th day of February A. D. 1884 and was not signed by him nor returned to the House in which it originated with his ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jections thereto within the time prescribed by the constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BAINES, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="569" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 42.] CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act requiring a gateway in every three miles of fencing and punishing the building or maintaining any fence without such gateway.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That it shall be unlawful for any person or persons by joining fences, or otherwise to build or maintain more than three miles lineal measure of fence, running in the same general direction, without a gateway in same, which gateway must be at least eight feet wide and shall not be locked; provided that all persons who have fences already constructed in viola<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of this section shall have six months within which to conform to the provisions hereof.</p>
<p>Section 2. If any person or persons shall build or maintain more than three miles lineal measure of fencing, running in the same general di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rection, without providing such gateway, he shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction shall be fined in any sum not less than one nor more than two hundred dollars, and each day that such fence remains without such gateway shall constitute and be punished as a separate offence.</p>
<p>Section 3. The provisions of this bill shall only apply to pasture lands.</p>
<p>Section 4. The near approach of the close of the present session of the Legislature, renders it probable that this bill cannot pass in the usual course of legislation, therefore an imperative public necessity ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ists for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, said rule is therefore suspended.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 42, originated in the Senate and passed the same Jan. 31st 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 42, passed the House of Representatives Feby. 5th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk, House of Representatives.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 6th 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<pb n="570" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. S. B. Nos. 32 and 44.] CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to establish and maintain a system of public free schools for the State of Texas, and to repeal so much of chapter 3, of title 78 of the Revised Civil Statutes of Texas, as refer to public free schools outside of incorporated cities and towns, assuming or having assumed control of their public free schools, and all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas; That the constitutional provisions for public schools are hereby appended as a part of the school law of this State.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Section 1. Article 7.</head>
<p>A general diffusion of knowledge being essential to the preservation of the liberties and rights of the people, it shall be the duty of the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature of the State to establish and make suitable provision for the sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port and maintenance of an efficient system of public free schools.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Section 2. Article 7.</head>
<p>All funds, lands and other property heretofore set apart and appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated for the support of public schools, all the alternate sections of land reserved by the State out of grants heretofore made, or that may hereafter be made to railroads or other corporations of any nature what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever, one half of the public domain of this State, and all sums of money that may come to the State from the sale of any portion of the same, shall constitute a perpetual school fund.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Section 3. Article 7&#8212;Amended Constitution.</head>
<p>One fourth of the revenue derived from the State occupation taxes and a poll tax of one dollar on every male inhabitant of this State between the ages of 21 and 60 years shall be set apart annually for the benefit of public free schools, and in addition thereto, there shall be levied and collected an annual ad valorem State tax of such an amount, not to exceed twenty cents on the one hundred dollars valuation, as with the available school fund arising from all other sources, will be sufficient to maintain and support, the public free schools of this State for a period of not less than six months in each year, and the Legislature may also provide for the formation of school districts within all or any of the counties of this State by general or special laws without the local notice required in other cases of special Legislation, and may author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ize an additional annual ad valorem tax to be levied and collected within such school districts for the further maintenance of pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic free schools and the erection of school buildings therein; provided, that two thirds of the qualified property tax paying voters of the district voting at an election to be held for that purpose, shall vote such tax not to exceed in any one year 20<pb n="571" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>cents on the one hundred dollars valuation of the property subject to taxation in such district, but the limitation upon the amount of district tax herein authorized shall not apply to incorporated cities or towns con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stituting separate and independent school districts.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Section 4. Article 7&#8212;Amended Constitution.</head>
<p>The lands herein set apart to the public free school fund shall be sold under such regulations, at such times and on such terms as may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by law, and the Legislature shall not have power to grant any relief to purchasers thereof. The Comptroller shall invest the proceeds of such sales and of those heretofore made as may be directed by the Board of Education herein provided for, in the bonds of the United States, the State of Texas, or counties in said State, or in such other securities and under such restrictions as may be prescribed by law, and the State shall be responsible for all investments.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Section 5. Article 7.</head>
<p>The principal of all bonds and other funds and the principal arising from the sale of the lands hereinbefore set apart to said school fund, shall be the permanent school fund, and the interest derivable therefrom and the taxes herein authorized to be levied shall be the available school fund, which shall be applied annually to the support of the public free schools, and no law shall ever be enacted appropriating any part of the permanent or available school fund to any other purpose whatever, or shall the same nor any part thereof ever be appropriated to or used for the support of any sectarian schools and the available school fund herein provided shall be distributed to the several counties, according to their scholastic population, and applied in manner as may be provided by law.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Section 6. Article 7&#8212;Amended Constitution.</head>
<p>All lands heretofore or hereafter granted to the several counties of this State for educational purposes, are of right the property of said coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties respectively to which they were granted, and title thereto is vested in said county, and no adverse possession or limitation shall ever be avail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able against the title of any county. Each county may sell or dispose of its lands in whole or in part in manner to be provided by the commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners court of the county. Actual settlers residing on said lands shall be protected in the prior right of purchasing the same to the extent of their settlement, not to exceed 160 acres, at the price fixed by said court, which price shall not include the value of existing improvements made thereon by such settlers, said lands and the proceeds thereof, when sold shall be held by said counties alone as a trust for the benefit of public schools therein, said proceeds to be invested in bonds of the United States, the State of Texas, or counties in said State, or in such other securities and under such restrictions as may be prescribed by law, and the<pb n="572" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>counties shall be responsible for all investments, the interest thereon and other revenue except the principal, shall be the available fund.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Section 7. Article 7.</head>
<p>Separate schools shall be provided for the white and colored children and impartial provision shall be made for both.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Section 8. Article 7.</head>
<p>The Governor, Comptroller and Secretary of State shall constitute a Board of Education, who shall distribute said funds to the several coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties and perforin such other duties concerning public schools as may be prescribed by law.</p>
<p>Section 2. One fourth of all occupation taxes and the one dollar poll tax levied and collected for the use of public free schools, exclusive of the delinquencies and cost of collection, the interest arising from any bonds or funds belonging to the permanent school fund and all the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest derivable from the proceeds of sale of land heretofore set apart for the permanent school fund which have hitherto or may hereafter come into the State Treasury. All monies arising from the lease of school lands and such an amount of State tax, not to exceed 20 cents on the one hundred dollars valuation of property as may be from time to time levied by the Legislature shall constitute the available school fund, which fund shall be apportioned annually to the several counties of this State ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording to the scholastic population of each, for the support and main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenance of the public free schools.</p>
<p>Section 3. No part of the public school fund shall be appropriated to or used for the support of any sectarian school.</p>
<p>Section 4. All avaiable public-school funds of this State shall be appropriated in each county for the education alike of white and colored children and each race shall receive its just pro rata according to soholas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tic census.</p>
<p>Section 5. All children without regard to color over eight years of age and under sixteen years of age shall be entitled to the benefit of the public school fund.</p>
<p>Section 6. The scholastic year shall commence on the first day of September of each year and end on the thirty first day of August there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after.</p>
<p>Section 7. The children of the white and colored races shall be taught in separate schools and in no case shall any school consisting partly of white and partly of colored children receive any aid from the public school fund.</p>
<p>Section 8. The terms &#8220;colored race&#8221; and &#8220;colored children&#8221; as used in the preceding sections and elsewhere in this act, include all persons of mixed blood, descended from negro ancestry, to the third generation inclusive, although one ancestor of each generation may have been a white person.</p>
<p>Section 9. All conveyances, devises and bequests of property for the benefit of the public schools, made by any one for any county, city, town, district or community, shall when not other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="573" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>wise directed by the grantor or devisor, vest said property in the county judge of the county, or the mayor of the city or town, or the trustees of the school district or community and their successors in office, as the trustees for those to be benefitted thereby, and the same when not other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise directed, be administered by said officers under such rules as may be established by the State Superintendent.</p>
<p>Section 10. Public schools shall be taught for five days in each week, schools to be closed on such holidays as may be agreed on by the trustees. A school month shall consist of not less than twenty days, exclusive of given holidays, and the public schools shall be taught for not less than seven hours each day including intermissions and recesses.</p>
<p>Section 11. The Governor, Secretary of State and Comptroller, shall constitute a State board of education who shall hold their sessions at the seat of Government. The Governor shall be ex officio president of the Board and a majority of the members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business.</p>
<p>Section 12. There shall be elected, at each general election for State and county officers, a state superintendent of public instruction, who shall hold his office for a term of two years and until his successor is elected and qualified, and shall receive an annual salary of twenty five hundred dollars, and may appoint one clerk at an annual salary of twelve hundred dollars, both payable out of the available school fund. The Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perintendent shall take the oath of office prescribed by the constitution and shall perform such duties as may be prescribed by law. Appeals shall always lie from the rulings of the State Superintendent to the State Board of Education. Any person elected State Superintendent of pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic instruction shall not during his term of office and for four years there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after be eligible to election to any other State office.</p>
<p>Section 13. The superintendent of public instruction shall be charged with the administration of the school law and a general superintendency of the business relating to the public schools of the State; he shall hear and determine all appeals from the rulings and decisions of subordinate school officers, and all such officers and teachers shall conform to his de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cision, unless they are reversed by the State Board of Education. He shall prescribe suitable forms for reports required of subordinate school officers and teachers, and blanks for their guidance in transacting their official business and conducting public schools, and shall from time to time prepare and transmit to them such instructions as he may deem necessary for the faithful and efficient execution of the school laws, and by whatsoever is so communicated to them, shall they be bound to gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ern themselves in the discharge of their official duties. He shall exam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ine and approve all accounts, of whatsoever kind, against the school fund, that are to be paid by the State Treasurer, and upon such approval the Comptroller shall be authorized to draw his warrant.</p>
<p>Section 14. The State Superintendent shall file all reports, documents and papers transmitted to him and the State board of education, by county or city school officers and from all other<pb n="574" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>sources pertaining to public schools, and keep a complete index of the same.</p>
<p>Section 15. The State Superintendent shall advise and counsel with the the school officers of the counties, cities, towns, school districts and communities as to the best methods of conducting the public schools and shall be empowered to issue instructions and regulations binding for ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />servance on all officers and teachers in all cases wherein the provision of the school law may require interpretation in order to carry out the designs expressed therein. Also in cases that may arise in which the law has made no provision, and where necessity requires some rule, in order that there may be no hardships to individuals and no delays or inconvenience in the management of school affairs.</p>
<p>Section 16. He shall after the close of the present session of the Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature cause to be printed in pamphlet form, for general distribution, fifteen thousand copies, or more, if needed, of the school laws.</p>
<p>Section 17. The State Superintendent shall require of county, city and town superintendents and other school officers and teachers such re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ports relating to the school fund and other school affairs as he may deem proper for collecting information and advancing the interests of the pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic schools, and shall furnish to county, city and town superintendents for the use of such officers and teachers the necessary blanks and forms for making such reports and carrying out such instructions as may be required of them.</p>
<p>Section 18. The State Superintendent shall one month before the meeting of each regular session of the Legislature, and ten days prior to any special session thereof, at which, under the Governor&#8217;s proclamation convening the same, any legislation may be had respecting the public schools, mate a full report to the board of education, of the condition of the public schools throughout the State. Such reports shall give all the information called for by the board of education and shall contain such other matters as the State superintendent shall deem important.</p>
<p>Section 19. The Governor shall lay such reports before the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture.</p>
<p>Section 20. Eleven hundred copies of said report shall be printed in pamphlet form for the use of the Legislature, and for distribution among the various school officers and libraries within the State, and the super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />intendents of public schools of other States and territories of the United States and Canada and the Bureau of Education at Washington city.</p>
<p>Section 21. The State Superintendent shall be ex officio secretary of the State Board of Education and shall keep a complete record of all its proceedings, which shall be signed by the president of the board and at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tested by the Superintendent.</p>
<p>Section 22. The State Board of Education shall, on or before the fif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth day of July of each year, make an apportionment of the available school fund, among the several counties of the State, and to the several cities and towns constituting separate school organizations, according to the scholastic population of each, and the State Superintendent shall de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liver an abstract of such apportionment, to the Comptroller and to each<pb n="575" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>county judge and mayor of each city or town that has control of the pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic schools, a statement of the amount apportioned to their county, city or town, as the case may be, and he shall issue to the county treasurer of each county, and to the city treasurer of any city or town having con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trol of the public school, a certificate for the amount of the available school fund so apportioned to his county, city or town, which certificate shall be signed by the Governor, as President of the Board of Educa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, countersigned by the Comptroller of Public Accounts and attested by the Secretary.</p>
<p>Section 23. The State Superintendent shall be allowed by the State Board of Education, an amount necessary for the expenses for books, postage, express charges, printing, stationery, porter hire and other nec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />essary office expenses to be paid out of the available school fund.</p>
<p>Section 24. The Comptroller shall keep a separate account of the amount of the available school fund arising from every source, and shall draw his warrant upon the State Treasurer in favor of any county or city Treasurer for the amount of the available school fund due his county, or city or town, as the case may be, on presentation of a certificate from the State board of education issued to the county, city or town treasurer, showing the amount due each from the available school fund duly en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dorsed by such treasurer.</p>
<p>Section 25. The Comptroller shall on or before the meeting of each regular session of the Legislature, report to the Legislature an estimate of the amount of the available school fund, to be received for the suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding two years, and which may be subject to appropriation for the establishment and support of public schools and the several sources from which the same accrue.</p>
<p>Section 26. The State Treasurer shall receive and hold as a special deposit all moneys belonging to the available school fund and keep an account of the several sources from which they accrue, and he shall pay out such moneys on the warrant of the Comptroller.</p>
<p>Section 27. The Treasurer shall, thirty days before each regular ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of the Legislature, and ten days before any special session at which any legislation can be had respecting the public schools, report to the Governor the condition of the permanent and available school fund, the amount of each, and the manner of its disbursement, and he shall also make any additional report required by the Board of Education.</p>
<p>Section 28. The Treasurer shall not under any circumstances use any portion of the permanent or available school funds in payment of any warrant drawn against any other fund whatever.</p>
<p>Section 29. It shall be the duty of the County Commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers Court of all counties not exempted from this section to sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />divide their respective counties into convenient school districts, at least one month before the first Monday in October 1884. Said courts shall designate said school districts by numbers; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that when districts are once established, they shall<pb n="576" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>not be changed without the consent of a majority of the legal voters in all districts affected by such change.</p>
<p>Section 30. Said school districts shall be so made as to be as con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />venient as possible to the scholastic population, and said courts shall give the metes and bounds of each district, and shall designate; the same carefully by giving the whole surveys and parts of surveys, with acreage of whole surveys and the approximate acreage of parts of sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veys in each district, and the county judge shall carefully record the same, and each district shall be given a number, which number shall be painted in large letters or figures over the doors of the school houses, said signs to be provided by the district trustees of each district.</p>
<p>Section 31. That whenever twenty or more qualified property hold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing tax paying voters of any district, wish for the purpose of taxing themselves, for the building of school houses or supplementing the State school fund apportioned to said district shall make application to the county commissioners court duly signed by them, said court shall enter up an order for an election to be held in said district, to deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mine whether such tax shall be levied or not, said application shall desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nate the amount of tax, asked to be levied, and the order of said court shall state&#8212;1st When said election shall be held. 2nd At what point or points the polls shall be opened; 3rd The amount of tax to be voted on; provided, that no election shall be held to determine the levy of a tax exceeding twenty cents on the one hundred dollars valuation of prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty. The commissioners court shall order the sheriff to give notice of such election by posting three notices in the district for three weeks be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore election and the sheriff shall obey such order. Not more than one such election shall be held in the same scholastic year.</p>
<p>Section 32. The County Commissioners Court shall appoint a pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />siding officer to hold said election, who shall make due return thereof as is required by law for holding a general election, and all persons who favor taxation for school purposes, shall have written or printed on their ticket &#8220;For school tax,&#8221; and all persons opposed to such taxation, shall have written or printed on their ticket &#8220;Against school tax.&#8221;</p>
<p>Section 33. All persons who are legal qualified voters of the State and county of his residence and who are resident property tax payers in said district, as shown by the last assessment roll of the county, shall be entitled to vote in any school district election, and if at any such elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, two-thirds of such qualified voters, voting at such election shall vote for the tax, it shall be declared by the County Commissioners Court, to have carried in said district and be so entered upon the records of said court to have been carried, and in all cases the returning officer shall make a full and complete return as in other elections, to said court, within five days after said election is held, and said return shall be opened and counted at the first meeting of said court and the result de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clared.</p>
<p>Section 34. Any one present may challenge a voter, but it the chal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lenged party takes an oath that, he is a qualified voter of the State and county and that he is a resident property tax payer, in said district, he shall be entitled to vote.</p>
<pb n="577" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Section 35. All polls for school district elections, shall be opened at 10 o&#8217;clock a. m. and shall not be closed before 4 o&#8217;clock p. m., and none of the officers holding such election shall be entitled to compensation there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />for.</p>
<p>Section 36. All trustees for school districts, shall be elected by the qualified voters at a school district meeting for that purpose, on the first Saturday of August of each year, except as hereinafter provided. The Commissioner&#8217;s Court shall appoint three persons to hold such election, and shall make the return of said election within five days after election to the county Judge and if no election is held, the county Judge shall at once appoint three trustees, for said districts for the ensuing year. All persons living in the district, qualified to vote for State and county officers shall be entitled to vote at said election. No person shall be eligible to serve as a school trustee, who cannot read and write.</p>
<p>Section 37. The trustees of school districts, provided for in the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceding sections of this act, and their successors in office shall be a body politic and corporate in law, and shall be, known by and under the title and name of district trustees of district number &#8212; and county &#8212;State of Texas, and as such, may contract and be contracted with, sue and be sued, plead and be impleaded in any court of this State of proper jurisdiction, and may receive any gift, grant, donation or devise made for the use of the public schools of the district. All reports and other official papers shall be headed with the number of district and name of county.</p>
<p>Section 38. At any time after the expiration of two years after any district has levied a school tax on itself, and twenty resident property holding tax payers and qualified voters of the district may have an elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion held to determine whether such tax shall be abrogated, increased or diminished, by making a written application to the county commissioners court, such election shall be held and conducted as elections provided for in section 32 of this act, and all resident property tax paying voters of said district shall be entitled to vote at such election. The person hold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing such election shall make return of such election within five days to the county commissioners&#8217; court, and said court shall at its first meeting thereafter, open said returns and declare the result. And said court shall enter an order to that effect, and shall thereafter levy such tax on said district as may be provided for by the result of said election.</p>
<p>Section 39. The county commissioners court shall at the time, of levying the tax for county purposes, also levy upon each school district the amount of taxes said district has voted upon itself, and it shall be the duty of the tax assessor to make a seperate roll for each school district in alphabetical order one copy to be deposited with the county commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners&#8217; court, and the other with the collector, and the taxes levied upon the real property in said district shall be a lien thereon, and the same shall be sold for unpaid taxes in the manner and at the time, sales occur for State and county taxes. The tax assessor shall assess and the tax collector shall collect said district taxes, as other taxes. The tax assessor shall receive a commission of<pb n="578" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>one per centum for assessing such tax, and tire tax collector a commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of one per centum for collecting the same. The tax collector shall pay all such taxes to the county treasurer and said treasurer shall credit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />each school district with the amount belonging to it, and to pay out the same as other school moneys.</p>
<p>Section 40. The Scholastic census shall be taken by the district trustees under the supervision of the county judge, of all children in each district between the ages of eight and sixteen years, giving name, age, color, sex and the name of the parent or guardian, as may directed by the State Superintendent, and return the said list to the county Judge by the first Monday in June of each year. The county Judge shall by the first Monday in July thereafter aggregate the whole number of children in the county, and make an abstract in duplicate thereof, one to be filed with the county clerk and the other forwarded by him to the State Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perintendent; said census rolls shall be sworn to by the trustees taking the census, and said abstracts by the county Judge before any officer authorized to administer oaths.</p>
<p>Section 41. Children within scholastic age belonging to a community lying on a county line may be transferred to an adjoining community in the other county. Application for such transfer must be made before the school fund is apportioned by the county judge. The pro rata share of the school fund of transferred children shall be held by the county treasurer and paid to the treasurer of the county to which the children were transferred on the order of the county judge of the county from which the children were transferred.</p>
<p>Section 42. The county Judge may, at any time before or after he apportions the school fund among the several districts or communities, and before the school opens, transfer a child from one district or com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />munity to another in the same county, and in every such case, if the transfer is made after the apportionment, he shall transfer the pro rata share of such child in the school fund to the proper district.</p>
<p>Section 43. The county Judge shall have, under the direction of the State Superintendent, the immediate supervision of all matters pertain<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to public education in his county. He shall confer with and coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sel teachers and trustees, visit and examine schools, deliver lectures on topics calculated to excite an interest in public education, or secure some one to do so. He shall organize and hold teachers institutes, and Shall approve all vouchers against the school fund of his county. He shall approve all contracts between teachers and trustees. He shall dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />charge such other duties as may be prescribed by the State Superin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tendent. He shall distribute all school blanks and books to the officers and teachers of the public schools. He shall make such annual reports to the State Superintendent as may be required by that officer; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that in considering whether he will approve a contract between a teacher and trustees he shall be authorized to consider the amount of salary promised the teacher.</p>
<p>Section 44. The County Judge shall give a bond in the sum of one thousand dollars to be approved by the county commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers court and filed with the county clerk, said bond to be<pb n="579" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>made payable to the county commissioners court and their successors in office, and conditioned for the faithful performance of his duties. He shall also take the oath of office prescribed by the constitution.</p>
<p>Section 45. County Judges stall be entitled to the following com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation: For disbursement of five hundred dollars or less of the school fund, twenty-five dollars shall be allowed. For disbursement of five hundred dollars, and not exceeding one thousand dollars, fifty dollars shall be allowed. For disbursement of each additional thousand dollars, or fractional part thereof, ten dollars shall be allowed, and ten per cent on the salary thus allowed shall be added thereto for postage, stationery and printing expenses connected with the administration of the school law. Said compensation herein authorized shall be paid to the County Judge by the county treasurer out of the public school fund, upon the approval of his voucher by the commissioners court.</p>
<p>Section 46. The County Judge upon receipt of the certificate issued by the board of education, for the state fund belonging to his county shall add thereto the county fund, if any, and deduct the amount esti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mated as his compensation, and the commissions of the treasurer and any other lawful expenses against said funds, and shall apportion the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mainder to the several school districts or communities as per scholastic census.</p>
<p>Section 47. The treasurers of the several counties shall be treasurers of the available public free school fund for their respective counties. The Treasurers of the several counties shall be allowed for receiving and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bursing the school funds, the fees provided in article 2403, Revised Stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />utes of Texas. Should the collector of taxes of the county make default in paying over to the treasurer, on the certificate of the board of educa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, in a reasonable time, such treasurer shall be allowed in the settle<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of his accounts such exchange for collecting, the pro-rata distribu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive portion of school fund due Ins county as may be allowed and certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied to by the State Superintendent. Within twenty days after the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceipt of his certificate of election it shall be the duty of the county treasurer to execute a bond, with two or more good and sufficient sure<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties, for the faithful performance of his duties under this chapter. Such bond shall be in double the probable amount of the available school fund which may come into his hands, to be estimated by the county judge, and shall be made payable and conditioned as prescribed in article 989 Revised Statutes of Texas. Upon receipt of the certificate from the State Board of Education, duly countersigned by the Comptroller, showing the pro-rata of the available school fund to which his county is entitled under the apportionment, the county treasurer shall present the same to the col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lector of taxes for his county, who shall pay the same from time to time out of the school taxes in his hands. The county treasurer shall endorse the amounts so paid by the collector on the certificate, and shall also exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cute and deliver to the collector duplicate receipts for such payments, and when the the Whole amount of such certificate shall have been paid, the county treasurer shall deliver the same to the collector, in whose hands<pb n="580" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>it shall be a voucher for so much money in his settlement with the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller of Public Accounts. The county treasurer shall keep a record of all school funds received by him, showing the year for which the same are to be disbursed, and shall credit school communities or districts, after numbering and otherwise designating such communities or districts, with such amounts as may be apportioned to them by the county Judge. All balances of the general fund not appropriated for the current year shall be carried over by the treasurer as a part of the general fund for the county for the succeeding year, and balances unexpended or unappropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated for a school community or district shall be carried over for the bene<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fit of such school community or district, if the community be reorganized for the following year, and if it be not reorganized, shall be added to the general fund for distribution, for the general benefit of the county at large.</p>
<p>Section 48. Any one desiring to teach, a public free school shall, un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />less known to the County Judge, present a certificate from the Justice of the Peace of the Precinct in which he or she desires to teach, or in which he or she may reside; or in case the applicant has acquired no resi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence in this State, then some other certificate satisfactory to the County Judge, that the applicant is of good moral character, and of correct ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />emplary habits; the County Judge shall thereupon, unless satisfied that some good cause exists for refusing such certificate; convene the county school board of examiners, and direct an examination of the applicant on the branches hereinafter named, as follows, to-wit: Applicants for third grade certificates shall be examined in orthography, reading, writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, arithmetic, geopraphy, and english grammar. Applicants for sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ond grade certificates shall be examined in the branches named in the third grade and also in composition and history of the United States. Applicants for first grade certificates shall be examined in the branches named in the third and second grades, and also in the elementary branches of algebra, geometry, and natural philosophy, school discipline and methods of teaching. The examination must be conducted in the English language, and no applicant shall receive a certificate unless the board of examiners be satisfied that he or she is competent to teach the branches named in the grade of certificate applied for, in the English language. The board of examiners shall examine such applicant as to his or her competency to teach the branches named in the preceding clauses, and shall make a report under oath of such examination to the County Judge, who shall, if such report be favorable; issue a certificate of com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />petency to the applicant, according to the grade recommended by the board of examiners, authorizing his or her employment by the trustees of any school district or community in the county in which the same is issued. Such certificate shall be valid in the county where issued for the current scholastic year, and may be renewed by the county Judge for any subsequent year without examination and without charge to the teacher if he be satisfied of the propriety of such renewal. A teachers certificate shall be canceled on account of such miscon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duct or immorality as the trustees shall report to the county<pb n="581" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="49" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>judge disqualifying him, in their opinion, for the instruction of children; hut before making such report, the trustees shall give such teacher rea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonable notice of the charges against him, and an opportunity to be heard. It shall be the duty of the teacher to keep an accurate record of the daily attendance of each pupil, and all other statistical data required by the State Superintendent and shall make a full report thereof to the county Judge at the close of their respective schools.</p>
<p>Section 49. Teachers with certificates from the Texas State Normal Schools, and the Summer Normal Schools of Texas shall not be required to be examined by the county board of examiners. Any person holding a diploma from a Texas State Normal School may teach in the public schools of this State during good behavior; any person holding a certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficate of one year&#8217;s attendance at a Texas State Normal School may teach in the public schools of the State for three- years after its issuance or during good behavior; Any person holding a certificate from a sum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mer Normal school of Texas may teach in the State for two years or during good behavior. The State Superintendent shall prescribe rules for granting certificates by Summer Normal Schools.</p>
<p>Section 50. Teachers shall receive salaries not exceeding the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing sums: Teachers with first grade certificates $75. per month; teach<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers with second grade certificates $50. per month; teachers with third grade certificates $30. per month; Provided that teachers teaching under certificates of one years attendance at a State Normal School shall be regarded as teachers with second class certificates: Provided further that this rule shall not apply to teachers employed in districts voting a local tax on themselves. Teachers shall admit all children over and under scholastic age into the public schools. All tuition paid for students at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tending a free school, under and over the scholastic age, shall be paid to the trustees for the benefit of the community or district in which the school is taught.</p>
<p>Section 51. Teachers shall keep daily registers, in which the names ages and studies of the pupils, and their daily attendance shall be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corded, and such other matters as may be prescribed by the State Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perintendent. Said registers shall be open to the inspection of all par<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ents, school officers and other persons who may be interested to examine the same. All teachers shall make monthly reports on such subjects as may be designated by the State Superintendent or county judge, to be approved by a majority of the trustees of the district, and shall file the same with the county judge when they present their vouchers for their months salaries. They shall make such term reports at the end of schools as may be prescribed by the State Superintendent, and until such term reports are made the trustees shall not approve vouchers for last months salaries, and until they are returned to and approved by county judges, county judges shall not approve their vouchers for last months salaries, nor shall the county treasurer pay same. All monthly and term reports shall be made under oath and county judges are hereby empowered to administer oaths for such purposes.</p>
<p>Section 52. It shall be the duty of all teachers in the public<pb n="582" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="50" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>schools of this State to attend the Summer Normal Institute as far as possible.</p>
<p>Section 53. School trustees shall determine how many schools shall be maintained in their respective school districts or communities, and at what points they shall be located; they shall determine when the schools shall be opened and when closed; they shall contract with teach<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers and manage and supervise the schools subject to the rules and regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations of the county judge and State Superintendent. They shall ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prove all teachers vouchers and all other claims against the school fund of their districts or communities; Provided that trustees of districts or com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />munities in making contracts with teachers shall not create a deficiency debt against the district or community.</p>
<p>Section 54. Trustees of districts that levy a school tax, shall make contracts with teachers to teach the public schools of their respective districts for a period of not less than six months in a scholastic year, which time may be divided into two terms or not as may be directed by the board of trustees, but the compensation to teachers under written con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tract with the trustees shall be approved by the county judge before the school is taught stating that the teacher will teach such school for the time and money specified in the contract, and that he will employ the number of competent assistants necessary when the number of children in the district shall exceed fifty, and all children within the scholastic age, who have settled in such a district since the scholastic census was taken shall be entitled to receive all the benefits of the schools of such district, and in such districts the trustees shall have the right to increase the salaries of teachers and the scholastic age, and may also have the schools taught longer than six months if it is deemed advisable.</p>
<p>Section 55. All the public schools in this State shall be required to have taught in them orthography, reading in English, penmanship, arithmetic, English Grammar modem geography and composition and other branches as may be agreed on by the trustees or directed by the State Superintendent.</p>
<p>Section 56. Three teachers holding first grade certificates, to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed by the county judge, shall constitute the county board of exam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iners, and shall receive from each teacher examiner for a certificate the sum of three dollars, and the county judge shall keep a record of all cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates issued by said board and all other certificates and diplomas of teachers, giving the name, age, sex, color and nativity of the person, the date, grade, and length of time of each certificate. Teachers certificates shall be valid anywhere in the State, without re-examination, until for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />feited as hereinafter provided; provided, however, that, when a teacher removes from one county to another, before leaving such county, he or she shall obtain from the county judge, duly certified to and authenti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cated by his official signature, a certificate showing that the certificate granted to him or her as a teacher has not been canceled. And no teacher, who removes into another county and fails to obtain such certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficate shall be competent to contract with school trustees, unless he be re-examined.</p>
<pb n="583" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="51" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Section 57. The trustees of school districts or communities shall have the management and control of the public schools; they shall have the power to employ and dismiss teachers; but in cases of dismissal, teachers shall have the right of appeal to the county judge and State Superintendent.</p>
<p>Section 58. The trustees of schools shall have the power to admit scholars over or under scholastic age, either in or out of the district or community, on such terms as they may deem proper and just, and they may suspend from the privileges of schools any pupil found guilty of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corrigible conduct, but such suspension shall not extend beyond the cur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Tent term of the school.</p>
<p>Section 59. County judges, trustees and all school officers, except teachers, shall take oaths to faithfully and impartially discharge the du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of their respective offices.</p>
<p>Section 60. White and colored children shall not be taught in the same schools, but the colored children shall receive the benefit as far as practicable of the public school fund, and the funds set aside in any dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict or community for colored children shall not. be used for the educa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of white children, nor shall the public school fund set aside in any district or community for white children be used for the education of col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ored children. Three white trustees shall in all cases be elected or ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed for the management and control of white schools, and three colored trustees shall be elected or appointed in any school district for the colored schools therein upon the written application of ten colored residents of said district having one or more children within the scholas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tic age, to the county judge one month before any annual election in said district for school trustees. In case there are not enough colored chil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dren in any school district as laid off, then two or more of said districts may be consolidated by the trustees for the benefit of the colored school, and each of the districts shall pay pro-rata, according to colored scholastic census in each, from the district school fund, for its support, and shall be governed by the trustees of both districts.</p>
<p>Section 61. When a school district or community has no school house or not a sufficient number, the available public free school fund for any one year to the credit of said district or community with the county treasurer, may be used for the purpose of erecting a house, upon the following conditions, to-wit: 1st A suitable piece of land shall be do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated as a site, and a deed therefor executed and delivered to the county judge, conveying said land to the county judge and his successors in office, in trust for public free school purposes, which deed must be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corded as other deeds. 2nd. The citizens of the district or community, must contribute of their labor and means, an amount, at least equal to the school fund so used.</p>
<p>Section 62. The trustees of such district or community, must make an application to the county judge, for the appropriation of said fund, which application shall give the plan and be accompanied by a list of subscription of labor and means by the members of the district or commu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nity, amounting in value to at least one half of the estimated cost of the house.</p>
<p>Section 63. On the receipt of such application, the county<pb n="584" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="52" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>judge shall, if the law has been complied with, and the house to be erected, is large enough to accommodate the pupils of the district or com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />munity, approve the same and enter an order, appropriating an amount of said fund, equal to one half of the estimated cost of said building, for the erection thereof, but said appropriation shall not be drawn from the<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />treasury, or paid, until the completion of the building, in accordance with the plan and specifications, and then only upon the warrant of the county judge.</p>
<p>Section 64. The trustees of such, school district or community, shall contract for the erection of such building, and superintend the construc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the same, and the county judge shall draw his warrant or warrants upon the school fund so appropriated, only upon accounts first approved by them.</p>
<p>Section 65. No mechanic, contractor, material man or other person can contract for, or in any other manner have or acquire any lien upon the house so erected, or the land upon which the same is situated, and all contracts with such parties, shall expressly stipulate for a waiver of such lien.</p>
<p>Section 66. The available school fund of any school district or com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />munity, for one year may be used, in the purchase of suitable school property, upon the execution of the deed as provided herein, and the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tribution of the remainder of the purchase money by citizens of the district or community, which must first be paid.</p>
<p>Section 67. The trustees of any school district or community, upon the<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />order of the county commissioners court, approving the terms thereof, when deemed advisable, may make sale of any property belonging to said school district or community, and apply the proceeds to the purchase of necessary grounds, or to the building or repairing of school houses.</p>
<p>Section 68. The trustees of any school district or community not haying a school house, may rent or lease a suitable house, instead of building or purchasing one, if deemed advisable by them; the rent shall be paid by the county treasurer, out of the available school fund to the credit of the district or community, upon the warrant of the trustees ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the county judge.</p>
<p>Section 69. All school houses erected, grounds purchased or leased for a school district or community, and all other property belonging thereto shall be under the control of the district trustees of such commu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nity or district.</p>
<p>Section 70. A school house constructed in part by voluntary subscrip<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion by colored parents or guardians and for a colored school district or community, shall not be used without the consent of the colored district or community assisting in its erection, for the education of white chil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dren; and a like rule shall protect the use of school houses erected in part by voluntary subscription of white parents or guardians, for the benefit of white children.</p>
<p>Section 71. The following named counties shall be exempted from the district system provided for in this act, to wit; Mata<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gorda, Harrison, Fannin, Montgomery, Rusk, Lamar, Red River, Anderson, Shelby, San Augustine, Sabine, Hidalgo, Starr, Zapata, Webb, Duval, Kaufman, Hopkins, Camp, Upshur,<pb n="585" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="53" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Grimes, Smith, Gregg, Limestone, Freestone, Washington, Nacogdoches; Angelina, Bastrop, Hunt, Jasper, Newton, Tyler, Polk, San Jacinto,. Franklin, Titus, Marion, Panola, Lee, La Salle, Yan Zandt, Robertson, Jefferson, Hardin, Liberty, Chambers, Orange, Waller, Houston and Cass, Brazos and Burleson.</p>
<p>Section 72. Schools in said counties shall be organized as follows, and subject to the following provisions of this act: Provided, the general pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act govern when not in conflict with the special provisions hereof as to community system. It shall be lawful for the parents, guar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dians, or other persons having control of any children residing in any county named in the foregoing section, who may be within the scholastic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age, to unite and organize themselves into free school communities, enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled to share in the benefits of the available school fund, belonging to such county, upon complying with the conditions hereinafter prescribed.</p>
<p>Section 73. The bona fide residents of this State, desiring to unite in the organization of a free school community shall make an application in writing, to the county judge, on or before the first day of August of each year, stating that they desire in good faith, to organize a free school, under the provisions of this law, and shall ask that their just pro-rata of the available school fund of the county be set apart for the benefit of their school community. Said petition shall be signed in person by each petitioner, and should any petitioner be unable to sign his or her name, then said petitioner shall authorize the signing of his or her signature to the petition, in the presence of at least two lawful witnesses.</p>
<p>Section 74. Such petition shall set forth: 1st That the application is made in behalf of a white or colored community, as the case may be; 2nd An alphabetical list of the names of the children within the scholas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tic age. 3rd The age and sex of each child. 4th A similar list of all children within the scholastic age, residing in convenient distances to the school house of said community, who have no parents, guardians or other persons lawfully controlling them; and also a list of children not of scholastic age, who it is proposed shall be pupils of the community school. 5th The capacity of the school house, and the character-of other school conveniences, if any: 6th The names of three or more competent per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons, to act as trustees for such school community. And the trustees of the community shall have the control of the public school house, and dur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the time in which no public school is being taught, may rent out the house for such rent as can be obtained, such rent to be used to keep in repair such school house; 7th That no similar petition has been signed by the petitioners, for any other community, for the scholastic year, for which said community is then being organized. And should the seventh statement prove untrue as to any of the signers of said petition, the children under the control of such signer shall forfeit their interest in the school fund, for the scholastic year for which said community is being formed.</p>
<p>Section 75. On receipt of such petition the county judge shall revise and correct it, by comparing the list of names with the<pb n="586" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="54" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>official census returns and shall keep the same open for further correction as may be shown to his satisfaction to be just and proper, until the first day of August of each year, at which time, if satisfied that the petition is in good faith, lie shall enter an order in a book kept for that purpose, sanctioning the establishment of such school community, and shall desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nate it by its name and number.</p>
<p>Section 76. Such communities may be organized for male and female schools, separate or mixed, as the population and necessities and condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of each community may require; provided, that in towns of not more than fifteen hundred inhabitants, no more than two school commu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nities for white children and two communities for colored children shall be organized.</p>
<p>Section 77. At any time before the apportionment of the available school fund to the several school communities in the county, the county judge may assign any child not included in the list of an organized school community, to some convenient and proper school community and set apart to such community the proper pro rata of such child out of such school fund of the county.</p>
<p>Section 78. Three trustees shall be appointed, by the county judge: for each community school and the three citizens named in the petition, shall in all cases be appointed trustees unless the county judge be satis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied from personal knowledge that the parties so named are either un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />worthy or incompetent. Said trustees shall discharge such duties as are herein prescribed or which may be prescribed by the State Superinten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent and shall see that the schools for which they are trustees are con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducted in accordance with the provisions and limitations of this law. Said trustees shall be removed from office by the county judge upon the written application of a majority of the patrons of the school.</p>
<p>Section 79. It shall be the duty of the trustees of a school community already provided with a school house, to contract with a teacher holding a certificate of competency from the county judge to teach school for the community for as long a period as the school fund entered to the credit of the community will warrant. The school shall open at such time as the trustees may decide, and be taught continuously until the close of the term, unless suspended by the trustees. The trustees shall in some public way, give two weeks notice of the time of opening the school.</p>
<p>Section 79a. Trustees shall make contracts with teachers, and in mak<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing them shall base their contracts with the teachers on the basis of the number of pupils within scholastic age, registered in the community; provided, however, that should the attendance fall below thirty-three and one-third per cent of the registered pupils in such community, the trustees thereof may discontinue the school.</p>
<p>Section 79b. Trustees in making contracts with teachers, shall determine the salary to be allowed or wages to be paid, upon the following rates of tuition: To teachers holding a first class certificate, not more than two dollars and fifty cents; to those holding a second class certificate, not more than two dollars; and to such as hold a third class certificate, not more than<pb n="587" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="55" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>one dollar and fifty cents per month, per capita shall be allowed for pupils within the scholastic age. And it shall not be lawful for trustees or teachers to demand as a condition of admittance into school the payment of extra tuition of pupils of scholastic age; provided, that in no event shall teachers holding a first class certificate receive from the public free school fund more than seventy-five dollars per month, and those holding a second class certificate more than fifty dollars per month, and those holding a third class certificate more than thirty dollars per month.</p>
<p>Section 79c. Trustees may employ one or more assistant teachers whenever the average daily attendance exceeds thirty-five pupils. The teacher shall be entitled to pay for pupils over and under age at such rates as the trustees may prescribe. If the necessity for the employment of an assistant teacher is caused by the attendance of private pupils, then the trustees shall require the teacher to employ at his or her expense, an assistant, holding a certificate of competency as teacher.</p>
<p>Section 79d. The amount contracted by trustees to be paid a teacher, shall be paid on a check drawn by a majority of the trustees on the county treasurer, and approved by the county judge. The check shall in all instances, be accompanied by the affidavit of the teacher that he is en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to the amount specified in the check as compensation under his contract as a teacher.</p>
<p>Section 80. It shall be the duty of the assessor of taxes for each and every county in this State not operated under the district system, prior to the first day of June of each and every year, to take an accurate census of all the children within their respective counties who will be of the age of eight and under the age of sixteen years on the first day of Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember next succeeding the taking of such census.</p>
<p>Section 81. Such census shall state the name of the child, his or her age, sex and color.</p>
<p>Section 82. For the purpose of ascertaining the facts required by the preceding article to be placed in such census, the assessor shall avail himself of all accessible information, and may when he may deem it necessary, require the parent or guardian of any child, or any other per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, to answer under oath touching such matters.</p>
<p>Section 83. No allowance shall be made by the Comptroller of Pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic Accounts to any assessor of taxes for any assessment of taxes in his county, until such assessor shall have exhibited and filed with him a certificate from the county clerk under his hand and seal of office, show<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing that such census and abstracts, approved by the county judge as here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inafter required, have been delivered to him by the assessor within the time hereinafter provided.</p>
<p>Section 84. Such census shall be verified by the affidavit of the asses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sor, and shall be by him returned to the county judge on or before the tenth day of June of each year.</p>
<p>Section 85. It shall be the duty of the assessor to make out and submit to the county judge, for his approval, two abstracts of such census, showing the number of children white and<pb n="588" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="56" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>colored, male and female, and such, other information as may have been required by the State Superintendent, and upon the approval thereof by the county judge, to mail the same on or before the first day of July to the State Superintendent.</p>
<p>Section 86. The assessor shall receive as compensation for taking such census and making such abstracts, and the other duties required of him in connection therewith, for the first one thousand children enrolled, five cents per capita, and for all children so enrolled in excess of one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand, three cents per capita, to be paid upon the warrant of the Comptrol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ler, out of the available school fund, by the tax collector of the county, upon the certificate of the county judge, attested by his signature and seal of his office, that said census and abstracts have been delivered to him as required by law.</p>
<p>Section 87. The Governor shall immediately appoint a Superintend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent of Public Instruction, who shall hold said office and discharge its duties, until the Superintendent of Public Instruction elected at the next general election for state and county officers, shall qualify.</p>
<p>Section 88. Nothing in this act shall be construed to interfere with the teaching or management of public schools, for the scholastic year ending August 31st 1884, but all such schools shall be taught, conducted, paid for and closed under the laws in force prior to the passage of this act; provided further, that nothing in this act shall be construed to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peal the present laws appertaining exclusively to public schools of cities and towns, which have or may hereafter assume control of the public schools within their counties, whether incorporated or not.</p>
<p>Section 89. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with any of the provisions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Section 90. Whereas the near approach of the close of the present session of the Legislature leaves only a few days for the consideration of this bill and renders it doubtful if it can be reached regularly on the calendar, and whereas the many grave defects of the present school laws render the passage of this bill an imperative public necessity and creates an emergency for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the. within S. S. B. Nos. 32 and 34 originated in the Senate and passed the same Jany. 30th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. S. B. Nos. 32 and 34 passed the House of Representatives&#8212;Ayes 75, nays 10&#8212;Feby. 4th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<p>NOTE.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the 6th day of February, 1884, and was<pb n="589" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="57" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>not signed by him, nor returned to the House in which it originated with his objections thereto, within the time prescribed by the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and thereupon became a law without his signature.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BAINES, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 33.] CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for leasing the unorganized county school leagues.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas; That the Attorney General, Commissioner of the General Land Office and Comptroller shall constitute a board to be styled the &#8220;Unorganized county school land board&#8221; with power and authority to lease the three hundred and twenty five leagues of land surveyed in the year 1882, for the unorganized counties of the State and situated in the counties of Hock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ley, Cochran, Bailey, Lamb, Andrews, Martin, Dawson and Gaines sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject to the terms hereinafter expressed, to wit; each league shall be leased separately to the highest bidder and all enclosures shall have con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />venient gates at least twelve feet wide and not more than three miles apart.</p>
<p>Section 2. That said lands shall be advertised for lease for sixty days by publication in one newspaper in each of the cities of San Antonio, Colorado City, Ft Worth and Henrietta or Decatur and may be leased for any term of years not less than five nor more than seven as may seem to said Board best for the ultimate interests of the counties affected thereby; provided that whenever any league or leagues so leased shall become the separate property of any county on its organization, then the lease as to such particular league or leagues shall cease and the same shall be and become at once subject to the control of respective county commissioners -court as other county school lands according to the provisions of the State Constitution and the laws thereof. Provided no lands shall be leased for less than five cents per acre.</p>
<p>Section 3. That the rents on said lands shall be paid to the State Treasurer annually in advance, commencing with the date of each lease respectively, and the Treasurer shall keep an account of the money re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived for each respective league and the money so received shall be used as a part of the available school fund of the State and when such league becomes the separate property of a county a sum equal to the proceeds of such lease shall be by the Treasurer paid over to the proper authority of such county out of the available school fund, to be invested and man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />aged by the commissioners court of such county, according to the provis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ions of said section six, article seven of the State Constitution less the pro rata expense of advertising etc.</p>
<p>Section 4. That said Board shall promptly report to the State Treasurer each lease made by them, specifying the league or<pb n="590" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="58" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>leagues embraced in the same, and the name or names of the lessee or lessees, and any lease so made shall become null and void on the non payment of the annual rents at the time or or times hereinbefore speci<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied, and it shall be unnecessary for any action to declare for the forfeit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ure other than the action of the Board upon the report of the Treasurer that default has been made on the payment of the annual rents, and all leases shall contain a clause making it a portion of the contract that a judicial ascertainment of the forfeiture is not required, and upon the forfeiture of any lease said Board shall immediately advertise and relet the lands on which said lease or leases have been made.</p>
<p>Section 5. That said Board is hereby clothed with authority to make such rules and regulations, not inconsistent with the provisions of this act in regard to the leasing of said lands, as they may deem best for the interest of the counties to be benefitted thereby.</p>
<p>Section 6. No corporation shall be allowed to lease said lands, and if any individual lessee or lessees transfer said lease to any corporation or allows them to use such lands they shall thereby forfeit their leases and improvements.</p>
<p>Section 1. This act shall take effect and be in force ninety days after adjournment.</p>
<p>Section 8. The near approach of the close of the session and the im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />portance of this bill creates an imperative public necessity, authorizing the suspension of the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days and said rule is hereby suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 6th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. S. B. No. 4.] CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the appointment of Commissioners to represent the State of Texas at the World&#8217;s Industrial Centennial and Cotton Ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />position to be opened at New Orleans, Louisiana on the first Monday in December A. D. 1884, to prescribe the duties of said Commissioners and making an appropriation therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas; That for the purpose of disseminating and distributing to the representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives and visitors from the various States and foreign countries, who shall visit the World&#8217;s Industrial and Cotton Centennial Exposition, to be opened at Hew Orleans on the first Monday in December A. D. 1884, in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formation in regard to the soil, climate and resources of Texas, to be ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended under the direction of the Governor and Commissioner of Insur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance, Statistics and History, under such regulations as are provided for in this act, the sum of twenty thousand dollars or so much thereof as may be necessary, to be taken out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise armronriated.</p>
<p>Section 2. That the Governor shall appoint one Commissioner to said Exposition, who shall enter at once upon the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />charge of his duty, which shall be to collect specimens of all the<pb n="591" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="59" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>products of this State, natural, artificial and manufactured, agricultural and mechanical and also to collect data appertaining to all the varied industries of Texas and to effect the best possible arrangements with rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />roads and other transportation companies for the conveyance of the same to said Exposition and back. Provided, no member of the Eighteenth Legislature shall receive the appointment as Commissioner or assistant commissioner.</p>
<p>Section 3. He shall also appoint eleven assistant commissioners, one from each congressional district, who shall assist the Commissioner and shall perform all such duties as may be prescribed by him to carry out the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Section 4. The Commissioner shall receive for his services the sum of two thousand dollars to be paid quarterly upon his own warrant, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the Governor and he shall be authorized to employ a clerk, who shall receive for his services not more than one thousand, to be paid monthly upon voucher approved by the Commissioner.</p>
<p>Section 5. The assistant commissioners shall each receive the sum of two hundred dollars by filing his affidavit that he has devoted at least thirty days to the work indicated, and he may draw two hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars of his salary previous to the opening of the Exposition, the Governor approving the same.</p>
<p>Section 6. The Commissioner shall proceed at once to New Orleans and arrange for ample grounds and space for the Texas exhibit; he shall attend in person the Exposition and devote his entire time in properly representing the State; he shall perform such other duties as may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by the Governor and the Commissioner of Insurance; Statistics and History.</p>
<p>Section 7. That all expenses incurred for the carrying out of the provisions of this act shall be regularly accounted for by said Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner and all payments to him for such purpose shall be made on vouchers, which shall be approved by the Governor.</p>
<p>Section 8. That at the expiration of said Exposition, it shall be the duty of the Commissioner to have returned to the city of Austin, and there have deposited with the Commissioner of Insurance, Statistics and History, all articles of whatever nature donated to or purchased by the State for exhibit, and the said Commissioner of Insurance, Statistics and History, shall take charge of and preserve the same for the use of the State. The said Commissioner shall make a full and detailed report to the Governor of the services performed by the Commissioner, the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses incurred and of the funds remaining on hand, if any there be, which shall be paid into the State Treasury. Provided, that all products of agriculture, or property of a wasting nature shall be sold to the best advantage of the State by the Commissioner of Insurance, Statistics and History, the Governor concurring, at public or private sale, and the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port of said sale shall be made by said Commissioner to the next Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature, and the proceeds of said sale shall be placed by him into the treasury of this State, to the credit of the general revenue fund.</p>
<p>Section 9. The Governor shall also be authorized to appoint twenty or more, honorary members to said commission, who<pb n="592" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="60" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall be authorized to represent the State at said Exposition, but shall not receive any compensation from the State for their services.</p>
<p>Section 10. The near approach of the close of the present session of the Legislature and the importance of the early appointment of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners provided for in this act, creates an imperative public necessity and an emergency for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, said rule is therefore suspended and it is enacted that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. S. B. No. 4 originated in the Senate and passed the same, ayes 19, nays 8.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. S. B. No. 4 passed the House of Representatives February 2nd 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk House of Representatives.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 7th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 59] CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Articles 3672 and 3675, Chapter 2, Title 76, Revised Civil Statutes; to add Articles 3675a, 3675b, 3675c, 3675d and 3675e and to make an appropriation.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas; That article 3672 of the Revised Civil Statutes, be so amended as here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after to read as follows:</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 3672.</head>
<p>It shall be the duty of the superintendent to have and take charge and control of all public buildings, grounds and property of the State, which may not be used by the different officers of the State government, includ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the State cemetery, and to properly care for and protect the same from actual damage, intrusion or improper uses.</p>
<p>Section 2. That article 3675, of said Revised Civil Statutes be so amended as hereafter to read as follows.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 3675.</head>
<p>That the Executive mansion, and grounds belonging to the same, and the Executive offices in the temporary State Capitol, and the rooms therein occupied, severally by the Secretary of State, the Comptroller, the Treasurer, the Attorney General, the<pb n="593" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="61" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Adjutant General, the Board of Education, the Land Board, the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of Insurance, Statistics and History, and State Engineer shall be under the charge and control of each of said officers occupying or using the same; and that the rooms on the third floor, wherein are the Supreme Court library and the rooms used and occupied as the offices of the clerks of the Supreme Court and the Court of Appeals, shall be under the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trol and in the charge of the clerks of said courts.</p>
<p>Section 3. That the following be added to said Revised Civil Statutes, to be known as article 3575a.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 3675a.</head>
<p>That all property belonging to the State, situated or being in the city of Austin, or to any department, board or office of the State, when the same shall become unfit for use or no longer needed, shall be turned over to the said superintendent, who shall sell the same at public auction, after advertising it for not less than five days, and the money arising therefrom, less the expense of advertising and selling shall be deposited in the State Treasury to the credit of the department, board or office from which it was obtained, to be expended by the said superintendent for improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments or repairs, whenever needed by the said departments, boards or offices, or for the State cemetery. The said superintendent shall make his report in writing, to the Comptroller, stating articles received, articles sold, to whom and at what price, and also a report showing how said funds were expended.</p>
<p>Section 4. That the following be added to said Revised Civil Statutes, to be known as article 3675b.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 3675b.</head>
<p>That said superintendent, during the recess of the Legislature, shall have the charge and control of the halls and committee rooms of said temporary capitol, except as hereinbefore provided, and before the assem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bling of each session of the Legislature, he shall prepare the different rooms for the uses of the Legislature.</p>
<p>Section 5. That the following be added to said Revised Civil Statutes, to be known as article 3675c.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 3675c.</head>
<p>That no room, apartment or office in said building, shall at any time be used by any person as a Red room or for any private purpose whatever. Provided, that this section shall not apply to the rooms occupied by the Judges of the Supreme and Appellate courts and Commissioners of Ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peals, on the third floor of the temporary capitol.</p>
<p>Section 6. That, the following be added to said Revised Civil Statutes, to be known as article 3675d.</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 3675d.</head>
<p>That in and about the grounds and buildings named in the<pb n="594" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="62" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>second section of this act, the watchmen employed about and around the temporary capitol and other buildings and grounds shall have all the powers and authority of a policeman of the city of Austin; and whenever, for the purpose of properly executing the provisions of this act, under the approval of the Governor, by the said superintendent there may arise a conflict with any ordinances or authority granted or given under or by virtue of the charter of the city of Austin, then and in that event so much of the said charter as authorizes the granting of such ordinances or the giving of such authority, be and the same is hereby repealed in so far as they prevent the said superintendent from efficiently performing his du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties hereunder.</p>
<p>Section 7. That the following be added to said Revised Civil Statutes, to be known as article 3675e:</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 3675e. It shall be the duty of the said superintendent to frequently inspect all the public buildings and property of the State at the capital, and at such other places as the Governor may direct; to act as adviser to all State boards in the preparation of specifications and plans for improvements and repairs to public buildings or property of the State, and to superintend the construction of the said work, where the same is not otherwise specially provided for by law. The said State boards and departments shall notify the said superintendent of improvements and repairs needed for their respective buildings and offices, and the same shall be made under his direction. He shall also be required to give his special attention to the effective maintenance of the State sewers and their connections, in use at the public buildings, and to keep the same in such sanitary condition at all times as to prevent the dissemination of disease therefrom, and to see that the gas and water pipes, with their con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nections and appliances are maintained in working order, ready at any time for immediate use. He shall also be required to prepare and have in his office a copy of the plans of all public buildings and improvements thereto under his charge, showing the exact location of all water, gas and sewerage pipes, so that in case of needed repairs or inspection, their posi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion can be determined without unnecessary expense.&#8221;</p>
<p>Section 8. It shall be the duty of said superintendent to make a report to the Governor on the first day of December next, and biennially there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after, showing the manner in which he has discharged his duties, the improvements and repairs that have been made under his superinten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence, with an itemized account of his receipts and expenditures, and the condition of all property under his charge, including an estimate of needed improvements and repairs to same.</p>
<p>Section 9. For the purpose of carrying out the objects of this act the sum of three thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated out of any money in the treasury not otherwise ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated, and it shall be the duty of the Comptroller of Public Accounts to draw his warrant upon the Treasurer for all sums due by the State on accounts certified to as correct by the said superintendent as incurred in<pb n="595" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="63" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the proper performance of his duties, and approved by the Governor.</p>
<p>Section 10. The present condition of the property of the State at the capital, and of some of the improvements upon the public buildings of the State, there being no officer of the State who is authorized to care for and protect the said property, or to superintend the construction of said improvements, creates an imperative public necessity and emergency which justifies the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days in each House, and it is so suspended, and that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 59 originated in the Senate and passed the same by a &#8532; vote February 2, 1884, ayes 22.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 59 passed the House, Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 6, 1884, by a &#8532; vote, ayes 77; noes 5.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk of the House of Representatives.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 7th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 36.] CHAPTER XXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to require the commissioners courts to lay out and open certain first-class roads.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the commissioners courts of the several counties shall see that at least one first class road of the width prescribed by law is laid out and opened from the county seat of their respective counties on the most di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rect and practicable route to the lines of their county in the direction of the county seats of each adjacent county, where no part of another county intervenes between the county seats of such counties, or if a border county, to meet the nearest road to the border, and if any adjacent county is not organized, then in the direction of the centre of such county. And the commissioners court of a county, to which one or more unorganized coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties are attached for judicial purposes, shall lay out and open at least two first class roads sixty feet in width through the extent of each such un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />organized county to intersect at right angles as nearly as may be at the centre of the county, and to meet at the county line similar roads of the adjacent counties. In counties now having public roads substantially complying with the preceding requirements as to course, the court shall be required only to give such roads the width of sixty feet and clear them of obstructions; such roads however shall not be laid out across orchards, yards lots or<pb n="596" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="64" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>grave yards or within one hundred feet of a residence without the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent of the owner, provided that this law shall not apply to counties where there already exists a sufficiency of public roads.</p>
<p>Section 2. It shall be the duty of each commissioners court within ninety clays after the passage of this act, on their own motion to appoint a jury of view to lay out the roads required in the preceding section and to mark and define them and to report in writing such marks and any prominent natural objects that may aid in defining the route selected. And upon the report of the jury of view such roads shall be declared public highways of the first class and the court shall order the overseer to open the same, and where the country is open prairie to plow a furrow on each side of the road and establish monuments at convenient, intervals.</p>
<p>Section 3. If damages are Claimed by any owner of land so appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated for public highways, or by any person where enclosed premises are crossed, a jury to assess such damages shall be appointed as now provided in section 4371 of the Revised Statutes.</p>
<p>Section 4. If the damages assessed be excessive, the court may appoint another jury to assess them, and upon the second report, if the damages are deemed excessive, the court may change the road so as to avoid the property so greatly damaged, provided such change will not divert the road more than one quarter of a mile from a direct line, provided further that in all cases where the owner or owners of lands over which such roads shall pass shall have the right of appeal to the District Court where the same shall be tried, (by first giving a bond in a sufficient amount to cover all costs) and if a greater amount of damages is there obtained the county shall pay the excess and the costs, but if no greater damages are obtained the party taking the appeal shall pay all costs, provided that such appeal shall in no case delay or prevent the immediate opening of such road after the damages assessed as above have been tendered.</p>
<p>Section 5. Persons through whose enclosed premises such roads are laid out shall have nine months to remove and adapt their fences to the road. Where the county is unorganized the owners of fences shall not be required to remove them until such county shall become organized and not then until fifty residents of such county shall petition the commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners court for the removal of such fences: provided that at all times the owners of such fences shall have at the crossing of such road conve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nient gates not less than twelve feet wide.</p>
<p>Section 6. The juries of view and the juries to assess damages, shall for the organized counties, be allowed such compensation as is now pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided by law: and for the unorganized counties the sum of two dollars per day for the actual time employed and five cents per mile for the actual distance traveled to mark and lay out the road or to assess the damages, which amounts on sworn accounts shall be paid out of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective county funds. And any person summoned as viewer as provided in this act who shall fail or refuse to perform the service required of him by law as such viewer shall be fined for contempt by the<pb n="597" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="65" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>commissioners court for every such failure, not less than five dollars, nor more than ten dollars, to be collected as other fines are collected: pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided that all reasonable excuses shall be heard.</p>
<p>Section H. Where there are no persons in the unorganized counties to act or willing to serve on the jury of view or jury to assess damages, the court shall designate citizens of their own county to perform the service.</p>
<p>Section 8. Nothing in this act shall be construed to prohibit the open<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of other roads as is now provided by law. Roads laid out under the provisions of this act shall not be changed except for the purpose of secur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing a better and more direct route, and then only after actual view by a majority of the commissioners court of that portion of the road sought to be changed.</p>
<p>Section 9. All laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Section 10. The present impracticable condition of the public roads in some parts of the State rendering public travel difficult and dangerous and obstructing communication between the different counties and sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />divisions of the State, creates an imperative public necessity which re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quires the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days and it is so suspended, and an emergency that this bill take effect and be in force from and after its passage and it is so en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />acted.</p>
<p>I Hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 36, originated in the Senate and passed the same Jany 23rd 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 36, passed the House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives Feby. 6th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk House of Representatives.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 7th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 7.] CHAPTER XXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making certain reservations for public roads out of lands here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after disposed of by the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That from and after the passage of this act, whenever any school, Univer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity or Aslyum land or any land belonging to the State shall be sold or patented by the State each sale or sales shall be made and patents issued subject to the right of the State or county to public roads across such land so sold or patented, which right of way for roads whenever they may be laid out by proper authority in pursuance of law is hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="598" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="66" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>served through and across such lands without cost to the State or county except damages done to improvements on such lands.</p>
<p>Section 2. If more than one road is laid out across any such tract of land then the county is to pay to the owner of the land, for all roads sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sequently opened in addition to damages to improvements what the land, taken for roads, costs the original purchaser.</p>
<p>Section 3. The near approach of the close of the session creates an imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I certify that the within S. B. No. 7 originated in the Senate and passed the same Feby 4, 1884. Ayes 13 nays 12.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 7, passed the House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives Feby 6th 1884, by a 4-5 vote</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk House of Representatives.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 7th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 63.] CHAPTER XXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prevent the destruction of grass.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That any person who shall wilfully fire any grass within any inclosure, not his own, in this State, with intent to destroy the grass in such pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture, or any part thereof, or any person who shall fire the grass on the outside of any in closure with the intent to destroy the grass in such in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />closure, by the communication of said fire to the grass within, shall be deemed guilty of a felony, and upon conviction, punished by confinement in the State Penitentiary for a term of not less than two nor more than five years.</p>
<p>Section 2. That if any person shall wilfully, and with intent to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jure the owner, or owners of the stock grazing thereon, set fire to any grass upon land not his own, with intent to destroy the same, he shall be confined in the State Penitentiary for a period not less than one year, nor more than three years.</p>
<p>Section 3. Whereas, there is no law fixing an appropriate penalty for the destruction of grass by fire, and whereas, there exists an imperative public emergency and necessity that the constitutional rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days, before its passage, be suspended, and the same is hereby suspended and that this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<pb n="599" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="67" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 63, originated in the Senate and passed the same&#8212;Yeas 28, nays 0&#8212;Jany. 30th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 63, passed the House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives&#8212;Yeas 71, nays 4, Feby. 6th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk House of Representatives.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 7th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H. B. No. 1.] CHAPTER XXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend article 4662, chapter 1, title 95, of the Revised Statutes, as amended and approved May 4, A. D. 1882, and to amend articles 4666 and 4668, chapter 1, title 95, of the Revised Civil Statutes, to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duce taxation for general revenue purposes, to conform the tax laws to the amended constitution, and to provide for the levy and collection of a tax to maintain a system of free schools under the amended con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That article 4662 of the Eevised Civil Statutes, as amended and approved, May 4, A. D. 1882, shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 4662. There shall be levied and collected an annual ad va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lorem State tax of seventeen and one-half (174) cents on the one hundred dollars for general revenue purposes, and twelve and one-half (12&#189;) cents on the hundred dollars f-or the maintenance of public free schools, of the cash value thereof, estimated in lawful currency of the United States, on all real property situated, and on all movable property owned, in this State on the first day January of each and every year, except so much thereof as may be exempted by the constitution and laws of this State, which cash value shall be estimated in lawful currency of the United States.</p>
<p>Section 2. That articles 4666 and 4668, chapter 1, title 95, of the Revised Civil Statutes be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>Articles 4666 and 4668. The commissioners&#8217; courts of the several counties of this State shall have the power to levy, for county revenue purposes, a tax of not more than one-fourth of one per centum, and for roads and bridges fifteen cents on the one hundred dollars&#8217; valuation of all property subject to State tax by the provisions of this act, and to pay all outstanding indebtedness incurred subsequently to the eighteenth day of April, A. D., 1876, and prior to the adoption of the amendment to section 9, article 8, of the constitution, an amount not to exceed twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five cents on the one hundred dollars valuation in any one year; and shall have the right to levy one-half of the occupation tax levied by the State upon all occupations not herein otherwise specially provided; provided,<pb n="600" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="68" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>any one wishing to pursue any of the vocations named in this act, upon which a county occupation tax may be levied, and upon which the State tax, in such cases, exceeds twenty dollars for a less period than one year may do so by paying the same quarterly; and provided further, the receipt of the proper officer, under seal, shall be prima facie evidence of the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of such taxes as are herein named; and provided further, the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act shall not, be deemed to affect the provisions of any law specially authorizing any commissioners&#8217; court to levy a different rate of tax; and, provided further, no person shall be allowed license for selling intoxicating or spirituous liquors, or keeping any nine or ten pin alley, or billiard, bagatelle, pigeon hole, jenny-lind, devil-among-the-tailors table, or anything of the kind used for profit, for a period of less than twelve months; and provided further, the mayor and board of aldermen of any incorporated town or city shall in no case levy a greater tax on any occupation than that authorized by this chapter to be levied by the county commissioners&#8217; court.</p>
<p>Section 3. Whereas the various county commissioners courts through<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out the State are about to levy taxes for the present year, therefore an emergency exists, and an imperative public necessity requires that the rule, requiring bills to be read on three several days, be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 1, originated in the House, and passed the same, Jan&#8217;y 28, &#8216;84, by &#8532; vote&#8212;ayes, 72: noes 10.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk of the House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within H. B. No. 1, passed the Senate, Feb. 1st, &#8216;84, by &#8532;d vote, to-wit: Ayes 18; noes 7.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 7th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Sub H. B. No. 50 and 84.] CHAPTER XXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to prohibit the unlawful fencing or enclosing, or keeping enclosed, of the lands of another, and of the public school, public, university and aslyum lands of the State of Texas, and to prevent the herding, or loose herding or detention of stock upon the lands of the State, the public schools, university and asylums, and to provide penalties for the violation of this act.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enaeted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That if any person or corporation shall knowingly make,<pb n="601" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="69" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>or permit to remain standing, any fence on or around the land of another, or the public, public school, university or asylum lands of this State, without the written consent of the owner thereof, duly acknowledged, or a duly executed lease of such land from the proper authority, in case of public, public school, university or asylum lands, as the case may be, duly recorded in the county where the land lies, or to which it is attached for judicial purposes, he shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction therefor fined in any sum not less than fifty cents nor more than one dollar per acre per month for each month so enclosed, or fined and imprisoned in the county jail for any period not over two years. Within the meaning of person, as used in this act, is included every man managing or controlling for a corporation, firm, or joint stock company, and any and every individual or person who shall aid, assist or direct in the violation of this act. Half of all fines collected under the provisions of this act shall be paid to the person or persons informing on the person or corporation, who shall unlawfully enclose any land; provided, that each three months said land is so enclosed shall constitute a separate of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fense. A fence within the meaning of this act is any structure of wood, wire, or both, or any other material, intended to prevent the passage of cattle, horses, mules, asses, sheep, goats or hogs. Where persons or corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rations have unlawfully fenced land belonging to the State, or public school, university, or asylum lands, it shall be the duty of the Attorney General, either in person or by proxy, to institute proceedings in the name of the State against any person or corporation so unlawfully enclos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing said lands; and the expense incurred in employing counsel to prose<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cute such cases shall be deducted from the fine or fines collected from any person or corporation violating the provisions of this act, the balance to be paid to the fund to which it belongs.</p>
<p>Section 2. All persons or corporations who have already fenced lands within the prohibition of this act shall have six months from and after the time that this act goes into effect to conform to the provisions thereof; provided, that the provisions of this act shall not apply to any person or corporation who has heretofore or may hereafter, in good faith, fence land not their own.</p>
<p>Section 3. In all prosecutions under this act, the provisions of articles 699 and 700 of the Penal Code of the State of Texas shall apply.</p>
<p>Section 4. This act shall not apply to persons who have heretofore set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled upon lands not their own, whence the enclosure is two hundred acres or less, and where the principal pursuit of such person upon the land is that of agriculture.</p>
<p>Section 5. That any person who owns or controls land surrounding land of another, may fence his own land, by fencing the inner boundaries of his survey and leaving a way or lane sixty feet wide (unobstructed by gates or otherwise), to the outer boundaries of the surrounding land, at such place as the owner or agent of the inner survey may demand; and providing two gates at such places on the inner and outer fences, as the owner of the inner survey shall demand; and they shall be kept in eon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="602" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="70" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>dition convenient for opening and closing by the owner of the fence; or if no demand is made, the opening and gates shall be at such place as the owner of the outer survey may select. When the way or lane and gates are once located they shall not be changed, except by consent of the owners of both the inner and outer surveys.</p>
<p>Section 6. It shall be unlawful for any person, firm or corporation to herd, or aid in herding, or cause to be herded, loose herded or detained for grazing by line riding any cattle, horses, mules, asses, sheep or goats on any vacant public domain, school, university or asylum lands within this State unless the same shall have been leased from the proper author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity: provided, that this section of this act shall not apply to persons herd<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing such stock, in gathering for, or carrying to and from market, or in moving the same from one section of the country to another.</p>
<p>Section 7. Any person who shall knowingly violate any of the provis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ions in section 6 of this act shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction shall be fined one hundred dollars for each year or part of a year, for each section, or part of section (meaning six hundred and forty acres of land or less, whether surveyed in sections or not) which shall be used contrary to the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Section 8. The owner of the cattle, horses or sheep shall be liable to the State in the sum of one hundred dollars for each year, or part of a year, for each six hundred and forty acres of land, or tract of less size, that may be used contrary to the provisions of this act, which may be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />covered in civil action, without affecting the criminal prosecutions pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed herein.</p>
<p>Section 9. Where such unleased land is now herded upon contrary to the provisions of this act, belonging to the unappropriated domain, public school, university or asylum lands, it shall be a bar to the criminal and civil prosecution hereinbefore provided for, for any violation prior to Jan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uary 1, 1885, if the violator of this act, or the owner of the cattle horses or sheep shall, prior to the first day of September A. D. 1884, pay into the State treasury thirty-two dollars for each section of 640 acres (or tract of less size) used contrary to this act, for the benefit of the fund to which the land belongs.</p>
<p>Section 10. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict herewith be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. The fact that there is no law making it penal to fence the lands of another, or the lands of the State, and that large quantities of lands are so fenced, creates an imperative public necessity that the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house shall be sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended, and that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. H. B. Nos. 50 and 84, originated in the House and passed the same Jany 30 1884 by a &#8532; vote&#8212;ayes 84, nays 7.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<pb n="603" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="71" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. H. B. Nos. 50 and 84, passed the Senate Jany 31, 1884, Ayes 17, notes 10.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 7th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. S. B. No. 51.] CHAPTER XXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to validate certain purchases of public school lands made by clerks in the General Land Office.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas By an erroneous ruling of the commissioner of the general land office, some of the clerks in said office have been led to believe that they had a legal right to file upon and purchase certain of the public free school lands of the State, and</p>
<p>Whereas, so believing, they did apply for and purchase some of said lands, and</p>
<p>Whereas, said applications and purchases were innocently made by them through having been so misled, therefore:</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas; That the applications and purchases of public free school lands hereto<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore made by clerks in the general land office, wherein they have complied with and shall continue to comply with the law for the sale of such lands by the State, be and the same are in all things validated, and said pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chasers are with reference to said purchases hereby placed upon an equal footing with any other citizen of this State.</p>
<p>Section 2. Nothing in this act shall be construed as validating the erroneous ruling of the commissioner of the general land office, under which said applications were received and recognized by said commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner, or to validate or authorize any file or purchase hereafter made; or to validate or in any way affect any invalid purchases made by any other persons; or to relieve any other person whomsoever from the penal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of the civil or criminal laws which may be applicable to them.</p>
<p>Section 3. Whereas, Suits both civil and criminal are about to be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stituted against the clerks in the general land office affected by this act; therefore, an emergency and imperative public necessity exists for the sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pension of the rules and the immediate passage of this act, and that it takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 51 originated in the Senate and passed the same February 1st A. D. 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. STEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 51 passed the House Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 6th A. D. 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk House of Representatives.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<pb n="604" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="72" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>NOTE.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the 6th day of February 1884 and was not signed by him or returned to the house in which it originated, with his objection thereto, within the time prescribed by the constitution, and therefore became a law without his signature.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BAINES, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S. B. No. 31.] CHAPTER XXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Section one of &#8220;An act requiring the proceeds arising from the leasing or renting of County School Lands and from sales of timber thereon to be applied exclusively to educational purposes,&#8221; passed at the regular session of the 16th Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas; That Section one of an act entitled &#8220;An Act requiring the proceeds aris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing from leasing or renting of county school lands and from sales of tim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber thereon, to be applied exclusively to educational purposes&#8221;, passed at the regular session of the 16th Legislature, be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 1. The proceeds of any leasing or renting of lands heretofore granted by the State of Texas to the several counties thereof for educa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional purposes, shall be appropriated by the commissioners courts of said counties, in the same manner as is provided by law for the appropriation of the interest on bonds purchased with the proceeds of the sale of such lands. And that the proceeds arising from the sale of timber on said lands or any part thereof, shall be invested in like manner as the consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution and law requires of proceeds of sales of such lands, and it shall be unlawful for the commissioners court of any county to apply said pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeds, or any part thereof to any other purpose, or to loan the same, or to invest the same, except as above required.</p>
<p>Section 2. Whereas, school funds are now accumulating in some of the counties of this State, arising from rental of county school lands and sales of timber taken from county school lands, and under existing legislation said proceeds are now applied and distributed in a manner not conducive to the best interest of the scholastic population; this state of facts existing, creates an imperative public necessity for a suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, prior to final action thereon, and emergency that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 31, originated in the Senate and passed the same&#8212;ayes 19, nays 3&#8212;Feby. 5th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>WM. NEAL RAMEY, <lb/>Secretary of the Senate.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<pb n="605" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="73" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>I hereby certify that the within S. B. No. 31 passed the House of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives&#8212;ayes 78, nays 1&#8212;Feby. 6th 1884.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. W. BOOTH, <lb/>Chief Clerk House of Representatives.</signed>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 7th, 1884</date>.</dateline>
<signed>JNO. IRELAND, Governor.</signed>
</closer>
<pb n="606" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="74" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
