<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="239" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="I" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main"><b>SPECIAL LAWS <lb/>OF THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>PASSED AT THE <lb/>REGULAR SESSION OF THE SEVENTEENTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>CONVENED <lb/>AT THE CITY OF AUSTIN</b></head>
<byline>JANUARY 11, 1881, AND ADJOURNED APRIL 1, 1881.</byline>
<byline>BY AUTHORITY.</byline>
<byline>GALVESTON 1881</byline>
<pb n="240" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="II" />
<pb n="241" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<head type="sub">SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize and require the commissioner of the general land office to issue a certificate for one league of land to the heirs of Moses Herrin.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Moses Herrin emigrated to the Republic of Texas prior to May 2, 1835, was a married man and resided in Texas from the time of his said immigration until his death, about the year 1846: and,</p>
<p>Whereas, said Moses Herrin received from the government of Coahuila and Texas a grant of one league of land situated in Limestone county; also a certificate from the Republic of Texas for one labor of land; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, said grant of one league of land was and is covered by an older grant in the name of Andres Varela, and was for that reason wholly lost to said Herrin and his heirs: and,</p>
<p>Whereas, the heirs of said Herrin have given the notice required by law in such cases, that they will apply to this Legislature for a special law granting them a certificate for one league of land as the heirs of said Herrin; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office be, and he is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized and required to issue a certificate for one league of land to the heirs of Moses Herrin, the same to be located and patented on any of the un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />located public domain authorized by law to be located.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 9, A. D. 1881</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend sections 23 and 31 of an &#8220;Act entitled an act amendatory of and supplemental to an act entitled an act to consolidate in one act and amend the several acts incorporating the city of Houston in Harris county,&#8221; approved April 21, A. D. 1879.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That sections 23 and 31 of an act incorporating the city of Houston, approved April 21, A. D. 1879, be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 23. That the city council shall have the exclusive control and power over the streets, alleys and public grounds and highways of the city, and to abate and remove encroachments or obstructions there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />on, to open, alter, widen, extend, establish, regulate, grade, clean, pave<pb n="242" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>or otherwise improve the same, to put drains and sewers therein, to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vent the encumbering thereof in any manner, and to protect the same from any encroachment or injury; to regulate, establish and alter the grade of all premises, and to require and compel the filling up and raising of the same; to establish, erect, construct, regulate and keep in repair all bridges, culverts, sewers, sidewalks and crossings, and to regulate the use and construction of the same, and to abate and punish any obstruc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions or encroachments thereon; and the cost of the construction of all such sidewalks, and grading done thereon, or the filling up and raising the grade of any premises, shall be defrayed by the owners of the lot or part of lot or block on which said sidewalk may front, or such grading or filling is done, and the cost of same, together with the cost of the collection thereof, shall be a good and valid charge against the owners of such lot or lots or block, and a lien and encumbrance upon the lot or part of lot, block or premises upon which, or in front of which, said im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provements may be constructed, which amount shall be assessed as a tax against the property and the owners thereof, and may be collected and the lien foreclosed in any court having jurisdiction; provided, that all improvements of sidewalks, fillings and gradings shall be advertised, and let out by contract to the lowest and best bidder. The city council shall be invested with full power and authority upon the consent of a majority of the resident owners on both sides of any street, avenue or highway or of such portion thereof as may be proposed to be improved, to grade, shell, pave, repair or otherwise improve any avenue, street, alley or other high<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />way, or any portion thereof, within the limits of said city whenever by a vote of two-thirds of the aldermen elected, they may deem such improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment for the public interest; the cost of which grading, shelling, paving or repairing shall be done at the cost and charge of the owners of the lot or lots or block fronting upon the alley, avenue, street or other highway so improved; and to make provision for the payment of the cost and ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pense of such improvements and the cost of collecting the same, the city council shall have full power to assess, levy and collect a tax upon the lot or lots or block or blocks fronting on such alley, avenue, street or other highway, which tax, when so levied and assessed, shall be a valid charge against the owner or owners of such lot or lots or block, as well as a lien and encumbrance upon the property itself, which amount may be col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected and the said lien enforced in any court of competent jurisdiction; provided, that the city alone shall pay for the improving of the intersec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of the streets from block to block across the streets either way; and provided further, that no one shall be made to pay for any improvement done on any street that may be paved or otherwise improved as herein<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />before provided, save for the proportional part of the street that may be in front of his property, and in no event shall such owner be compelled to pay for the improvement of such street more than twenty-five per cent. of the assessed value of his property fronting thereon, and that any rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road or street railway company shall be liable for any grading, paving or other improvement made upon any portion of said streets used or oc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cupied by such companies; to secure the safety and convenience of pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing in the streets, sidewalks and other places in the city, to fix the squar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, and to prevent encroachments and obstructions on the streets, side<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />walks, squares, ways, levees and public roads and places; to fix the place for anchoring all water craft on Buffalo Bayou; to establish an active system of inspection over the conduct of persons and premises, to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vent cattle, horses, swine, goats, geese and animals from running<pb n="243" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>at large in the streets; to establish and maintain a city police, prescribe the duties of policemen, and regulate their conduct; to provide for light<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the streets, and for this purpose may establish gas works for the manufacture of gas for the use of the city and the inhabitants thereof at cost price; to determine in what part of the city slaughter houses, bone boilers, soap makers, or other establishments for any business which is or may be injurious to the value of adjacent property, or unwholesome or disagreeable to the occupant of adjacent property, shall not be al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowed to be erected; to determine in what part of the city wooden buildings shall not be erected; within the limits prescribed no person shall be permitted to erect such buildings; to prevent gunpowder or other explosive material, kerosine oil or other inflammable oils, being stored within the city limits in such quantity as to endanger the safety of adjacent property; to provide means for the protection against and extinguishment of conflagrations, and for the regulation, maintenance and support of a fire department; to permit or forbid theatres, balls, or other public amusements, and to suppress the same whenever the preser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vation of order, tranquility or public safety may require; to close dram shops, drinking saloons and other places where intoxicating liquors are sold, whenever necessary or expedient; to define what shall be nuis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ances in said city, and to abate them by summary proceedings; to provide a work-house for vagabonds and disorderly persons who are unable to pay fines, and to make regulations concerning the same; to regulate weights and measures in the city, affix penalties for violation, fix stand<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ard, etc.; also that the city council may provide, own and maintain water works for the use of the city and its inhabitants; to provide and keep a city prison; to make all needful and proper regulations concerning bakers, butchers, keepers of taverns, grog-shops, and other public houses, draymen, horse drivers, water carriers, omnibus drivers, hack drivers and drivers of baggage-wagons, and especially to preserve order and prevent noise and confusion in and about the several depots on the arrival and departure of railway trains; to prevent extortion by carriers of passengers or baggage, hacks, drays, and all public conveyances, by establishing maximum rates of charges; to direct and control the laying and construction of railroad tracks, turnouts and switches, and to require that they be constructed and laid so as to interfere as little as possible with the ordinary travel and use of streets; to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire railroad companies to keep the streets through which they run in repair, and to light the same whenever deemed necessary; to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struct and keep in repair bridges and crossings at the intersection of streets and avenues, and over all ditches, sewers and culverts on the line of the railway; to regulate the speed of engines and loco<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />motives within said city; to control and regulate everything con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cerning street railways, and generally to make and establish all rules, regulations, by-laws, and ordinances which may contribute to and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mote the better administration of the affairs of said city, as well as for the maintenance of the peace, tranquility and safety of said city, and for the protection of the persons and property of its inhabitants. The city council of the city of Houston are hereby empowered and authorized to take and condemn land and real estate in said city to the public use, viz: for streets, alleys and public highways, for extending straightening and widening those streets now in use, for public wharves and landing places for steamers and other water craft, and for public squares, parks and pleasure grounds. For the condemnation of any<pb n="244" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>land or real estate, the following proceedings shall be had: The city attor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ney or attorneys, employed by the city for that purpose, shall file a peti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion in the district court of Harris county against the owner of the land or real estate sought to be condemned for any of the purposes aforesaid, setting forth, first, the name or names and residence of the owner or owners, if known, and if unknown the same shall be stated; second, the description by metes and bounds of any actual survey, had for that pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose, of the land or real estate sought to be condemned; third, the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose for which the same is proposed to be taken and applied; fourth, the supposed value of the property to be condemned; fifth, the prayer that the same be condemned to the public use for the purpose stated; and, upon the filing of such petition, like proceedings shall be had thereon as in other civil suits, and when personal service can not be had by reason of the defendant being a non-resident or unknown, service by publica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall be made as provided in other cases in the district court, and upon trial the court shall proceed to render judgment, condemning the land to public use, upon the payment of the value thereof as assessed by the jury, and upon any suit being brought thereafter against the said corporation for such property so condemned, a copy of the judgment and an actual tender of the money in court shall be sufficient answer in bar of a recovery in any such suit. All costs of proceedings for the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demnation of land and real estate under this act shall be taxed against the plaintiffs, including reasonable fees of the attorney, which the court shall appoint to represent the defendant when cited by publication.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Sec. 31. That the city council shall have power by ordinance to an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually levy, assess and collect taxes not exceeding two per cent. ad va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lorem upon all real and personal estate and property in the city not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />empt from taxation, and to determine when taxes shall be paid by cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porations or when by individual incorporators, and to levy and collect from each male inhabitant of the city over the age of twenty-one years an annual poll tax of one dollar. All taxes on real estate shall be a lien and charge upon the property, and it may be subjected to the payment of the same, and on all past due taxes, the city of Houston shall be enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled to charge and collect interest at the rate of ten per centum per an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />num from and after such tax or taxes shall have become due and pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able.&#8221;</p>
<p>Whereas, there is now no law providing for the efficient management, control and improvement of the streets and sidewalks in the city of Houston, and the same are in a dreadful condition on that account, there exists an imperative public necessity for dispensing with the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days in each house of this Legislature, and an emergency which requires this act to take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 9, A. D. 1881</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize the commissioner of the general land office to approve the bounty land warrant for nineteen hundred and twenty acres of land, issued on the twenty-fifth day of November, 1846, by Wm. G. Cooke, adjutant general, to the heirs of Wm. N. French.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, it appears that bounty land warrant No. 149, for nineteen hundred and twenty acres of land, was, on the twenty-fifth day of November, 1846, issued by Wm. G. Cooke, adjutant general, to the heirs<pb n="245" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of Wm. N. French; and, whereas, it further appears from the certificate of the commissioner of the general land office that said bounty warrant has never been located and surveyed, and that no certificate has been issued in lieu thereof under any special act, and further that said bounty warrant, not having been presented to the commissioner of claims for his approval, is, under the ninth section of the act of February 7, 1860, barred, and can not be located; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office be and he is hereby authorized to approve said bounty warrant, and to issue a patent for the amount of land named, when the same shall have been located and sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the end of this session of the Seven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth Legislature, and the fact that the Legislature can not grant the relief herein sought after April next, on account of a constitutional pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vision on the subject, creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity, justifying the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring all bills to be read on three several days, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, said rule is therefore suspended, and it is enacted that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 18, A. D. 1881</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of W. M. Harrison and L. A. Ellis.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, On the fourteenth day of February, A. D. 1880, a judgment was recovered in favor of the State of Texas, in the district court of Travis county, against T. M. Bagby, late sheriff and tax collector of Marion county, and Wm. M. Harrison, and L. A. Ellis, as sureties on the bond of said Bagby, for the sum of six thousand four hundred and eighty dollars and eighty-eight cents ($6480 88), on which a credit of one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars has been, entered; and whereas, there was, at the time of the rendition of said judgment, an agreement that the collection of the same should be stayed until such time as said sureties might be able to present their equities for relief to the Seventeenth Legislature; and whereas, said sureties have made it satisfactorily to appear that at the time of the rendition of said judgment, said Bagby was entitled to the following just and equitable offset against said claim of the State, which was unknown to said sureties at said time, and which was not presented nor considered on the trial of said cause to wit: A portion of the delin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quent and insolvent list of the tax-payers of Marion county for the year A. D. 1877, amounting to fifteen hundred and ninety-nine dollars and forty-three cents; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the clerk of the district court of Travis county, Texas, be and he is hereby authorized and required to enter a credit upon a judgment recorded for the sum of six thousand four hundred and eighty dollars and eighty-eight cents, against T. M. Bagby, late sheriff of Marion county, and Wm. M. Harrison and L. A. Ellis, his sureties, rendered in said dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict court of Travis county on the fourteenth day of February, 1880, the amount of fifteen hundred and ninety-nine dollars and forty-three cents<pb n="246" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>($1599 43), in addition to such credits as may have heretofore been en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tered thereon, and said judgment endorsed satisfied to the extent of said credits.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That when said credits shall have been entered, and said judgment endorsed as provided in section 1 of this act, such entry and endorsement shall be held to be a complete satisfaction and settlement of the right and claim which the State of Texas has by virtue of said judgment against said sheriff and Wm. M. Harrison and L. A. Ellis, his sureties, to the amount and extent of said credits.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the near approach of the end of the present session of the Legislature, and the fact that the State of Texas is about to press the collection of said judgment, create an imperative public necessity and emergency, which require the constitutional rule that bills be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act be in force from and after its passage, and be it so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 28, A. D. 1881</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of C. C. Gibbs.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, On the&#8212;day of September, 1877, thirteen land certificates for six hundred and forty acres each, issued by the State of Texas, to the International Railroad Company, and known as International Railroad land certificates, belonging to C. C. Gibbs, were destroyed by fire, and he has been unable to have the same duplicated because they cannot be identified by their numbers; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office of this State be and is hereby authorized and required to issue to the said C. C. Gibbs thirteen land certificates of like kind of said lost certificates and to supply the place thereof; provided, the commissioner of the general land office is satisfied of the destruction of said land certificates before mentioned.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the time for the location of said certificates be and is hereby extended to January the first, 1882.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the near approach of the end of this session of the Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature creates an imperative public necessity for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and an emergency that this act take effect at once; therefore, said rule is sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended, and it is enacted that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 28, A. D. 1881</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to validate donation land certificate issued to Joseph Floyd.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the donation land certificate number two hundred and sixty-four, for six hundred and forty acres of land, issued to Joseph Floyd, on the second day of June, one thousand eight hundred and thirty-eight, by George W. Hockley, secretary of war of the Republic of Texas, at the<pb n="247" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>city of Houston, for having fought bravely in battle of San Jacinto, April 21st, 1836, and which said donation certificate has never been approved by the commissioner of claims, as provided by the act of Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary 7th, 1860, and was not located prior to the creation of said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of claims, and no special act certificate issued in lieu thereof, be and the same is hereby declared approved and validated, and is enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled to be located and surveyed upon any of the unappropriated public domain belonging to the State of Texas, and when so located and sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyed, the commissioner of the general land office of the State of Texas, is hereby required to patent same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The near approach, of the close of the present session of the Legislature, and the fact that the relief herein sought cannot be granted under the constitution after April next, creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity, justifying the suspension of the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional rule requiring all bills to be read on three several days, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage; said rule is therefore suspended, and it is enacted that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 29, A. D. 1881</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Thomas B. Hearne.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Thomas B. Hearne, an old veteran of the war which sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />arated Texas from Mexico, is now in indigent circumstances, being con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fined to his room by reason of physical infirmities, and a great part of the time to his Red; and whereas, by virtue of the laws of the Republic and State of Texas, the said Thomas B. Hearne, as such veteran, was entitled to twelve hundred and eighty acres of land for his services as a volunteer soldier in said war; and whereas, the said Thomas B. Hearne has never received from the State of Texas the land to which he is justly entitled as such veteran, or any part thereof; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office be and he is hereby required to issue to Thomas B. Hearne a bounty land certificate for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land, which may be located upon any vacant public domain of the State of Texas, not heretofore reserved for other purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the close of the session, and the fact that the said Thomas B. Hearne is an old and indigent veteran, who is in daily need of the land to which he is entitled, and is suffering for want of the same, and the fact that the State should do justice to all of her citizens, creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring that this bill shall be read on three sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 30, 1881</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="248" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Mrs. Marinda Hyde, Martinn L. Baker, Roden T. Crain, the heirs of John P. Reynolds, and the heirs of Jacob Plummer.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office be directed and authorized to issue to Mrs. Marinda Hyde an unconditional certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land; to Martin L. Baker, for six hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty acres; to Roden T. Crain, for six hundred and forty acres; to the heirs of John P. Reynolds, for one league and labor; and to the heirs of Jacob Plummer, for six hundred and forty acres.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the close of the session of the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture, and the rapid diminution of public lands by location of land certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates, creates an imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 30, A. D. 1881</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize and require the commissioner of the general land office to issue a patent on certificate No. 291, to the Mexican Telegraph company, a corporation chartered under the laws of the State of New York, which certificate issued to the Houston and Texas Central Railroad company for six hundred and forty acres of land, and has been located and surveyed upon the island of Brazos de Santiago in Cameron county, and to designate the alternate section of six hundred and forty acres located and surveyed adjoining the location of said certificate as belonging to the public school lands of this State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office be and he is hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to issue a patent on certificate No. 291, to the Mexican Telegraph company, a corporation chartered under the laws of the State of New York, which certificate was issued to the Houston and Texas Central Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road company for six hundred and forty acres of land, and that said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner be also required to designate the alternate section of six hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty acres as located and surveyed by said telegraph company adjoining the location of said certificate as belonging to the public school lands of this State, as said surveys appear on the records of the general land office.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That whereas, the said telegraph com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany is actually engaged in laying its cable between the Texas coast and Vera Cruz, in the Republic of Mexico, thus cementing the telegraph sys<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tems of the United States and Mexico, and requires the immediate use of the necessary landing facilities of its cable and the erection of its of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fices and other appliances; therefore, an imperative emergency exists for the suspension of the rule that requires all bills to be read on three sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral days, and such rule is accordingly suspended, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 4, A. D. 1881</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="249" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the heirs of Lewis Grooms.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office be and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to the heirs of Lewis Grooms a head<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />right certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, to be located, surveyed and patented as other head-right certificates, and this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage. The near approach of the close of the session creates an imperative public necessity that the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 4, A. D. 1881</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the heirs of Henry J. Town<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />send, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Henry J. Townsend settled in the State of Texas during the year 1840, he then being a married man and the head of a family; that he lived in said State as a citizen thereof until his death in 1864, and whereas, neither said Henry J. Townsend or his heirs or any one for them have received the land certificate to which said Henry J. Townsend was entitled by virtue of the laws of this State; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office of this State be and he is hereby required to issue to the heirs of Henry J. Townsend, deceased, a land certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land which said cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate can be located according to the laws of this State on any of the public domain not otherwise appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the close of the session creates an im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perative public necessity for suspending the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days and it is suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 4, A. D. 1881</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of J. M. Brownson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the treasurer is hereby directed to pay to J. M. Brownson, upon his re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceipt for the same, the sum of one hundred dollars, out of the appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion made for the payment of the interest on the public debt for the year 1878, in full satisfaction and cancellation of twenty coupons of five dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars each of Texas veteran bonds, which said coupons were due on the first day of July, 1878, and numbered as follows, viz: 497, 504, 730, 1414, 1419, 1641, 1644, 1650, 1652, 1654, 1655, 1657, 1662, 1663, 1664, 1986, 4914, 6136, 6541 and 6606, and which were lost in transmitting the same by mail from Victoria to Austin; provided, that, before said money shall be paid said J. M. Brownson shall execute and deliver to the said treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer of the state his bond, with two solvent sureties, payable to the said<pb n="250" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>treasurer and his successors in office, for the sum of one hundred and fifty dollars; conditioned that he will refund the money paid to him, with interest thereon, if it shall be found that it was wrongfully or im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />properly paid to him.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the close of the session creates an imper<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 4, A. D. 1881</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to repeal sections 2, 4 and 7 of an act of the Legislature of the State of Texas, entitled &#8220;An act to amend the char<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter of the city of Dallas," approved July 9, 1879, and to amend sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions 177, 163, 90, 62 and 82, of an act of the Legislature of the State of Texas, entitled &#8220;An act to incorporate the city of Dallas, and to grant a new charter to said city,&#8221; approved August 9, A. D. 1876.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That sections 2, 4 and 7 of an act of the Legislature of the State of Texas entitled &#8220;An act to amend the charter of the city of Dallas,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved July 9, A. D. 1879, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That section 177 of the charter of the city of Dallas, approved August 9, 1876, be and the same is hereby amended so as to read as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 177. It shall be the duty of every one owning property fronting on any street in the city of Dallas, to build sidewalks, construct curbing and guttering and repair the same in front of their property, when notified by the proper city authorities, and according to ordinance.</p>
<p>&#8220;If the owners of any property fail to construct or repair such sidewalk, curbing or guttering, the same may be done by the city, and taxed against the property, according to cost of construction. Any one failing or re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fusing to build or repair the sidewalk, curbing or guttering, along their property, according to ordinance, shall be deemed guilty of a misde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />meanor and punished as provided by city ordinance; provided, the fine for any one day&#8217;s neglect shall not exceed fifty dollars."</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That section 163 of the charter of the city of Dallas, be amended so as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 163. Whenever the city council shall hereafter provide by ordinance, for the establishing, opening, widening or altering any street, avenue, alley, market place or public square, or route, or sewer, either on their own motion or on a petition by a majority of the adjoining property holders, and it becomes necessary for the purpose to take private property, just compensation is to be paid therefor to the owners of the land con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demned and appropriated; whenever the owner or owners of land cannot agree with the committee of the city council, as to the value of the land to be used, the mayor shall cause the value of such property, so taken, to he ascertained and assessed by a board of appraisers, consisting of six disinterested freeholders of the city, to be selected as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Whenever any of the aforesaid improvements have been determined upon by the city council, the mayor shall order the marshal to summon twelve disinterested freeholders of the city, to appear before him on a<pb n="251" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>day specified in the notice, and he shall have the owner or owners of the land to be taken, summoned to appear at the same time and place, and if the owner can not he found, then notice to be served on the agent of such owner; if any of the twelve freeholders do not appear at the time and place, the marshal shall summon the requisite number to fill the vacancies until there is a panel of twelve. From this list, the owner of the land shall have a right to strike off three, and the mayor in behalf of the city, shall have a right to except to three, and the remaining first six shall constitute a board of appraisers; said board shall have power to regulate their time of sitting, to enforce the execution of all necessary process, and they shall be presided over by the mayor, who shall instruct the board upon all questions of law arising, but shall have no voice in determining the value of land. A majority of the board may determine and report value of the land.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That section 90 of the charter of the city of Dallas be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 90. The city council shall have a right to annually levy and collect a poll tax, not exceeding one dollar (150) and fifty cents for every year, upon all male persons, over the age of twenty-one and under sixty, residents of the city at the time of assessment.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That section 62 of the city charter be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 62. The city council shall have the right to enact all neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary ordinances to restrain and punish vagrants, mendicants, street beg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gars and prostitutes; to restrain, punish, regulate and control all disor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />derly houses of prostitution or assignation and the keepers and inmates thereof; to regulate, punish or control all gambling and keepers of games and gambling houses and those who bet on games and gambling devices, where there is an ordinance of the city of Dallas in force, pun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ishing this or any other misdemeanor with as great a penalty as the same is punished by the statute of the State. The mayor&#8217;s court of the city of Dallas shall have jurisdiction of such misdemeanors when committed in the corporate limits of the city of Dallas.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That section 82 of the charter of the city of Dallas he amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 82. The city council shall have power to pass, publish, amend or repeal all ordinances, rules and police regulations, not contrary to the constitution of the State, and necessary for the peace, order or good government of the city or the trade, commerce and health thereof, or that may be necessary and proper to carry into effect the powers vested in the corporation or any of its officers by the act of incorporation of date August 9, A. D. 1876, and this and other amendments thereto. To enforce the observance of all such ordinances, rules and police regulations and to punish violations thereof by fines and imprisonment, or either or both, or by work on the streets or other public works as may be provided by ordinance and required by the judgment of the court; provided, that no fine shall exceed two hundred dollars, or period of imprisonment ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed fifteen days in city jail, but the city of Dallas shall have a right by ordinance to inflict penalties not exceeding this either in fine or impris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />onment.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Whereas, the present session of the Legislature is near ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />journment, and it is necessary that this bill be enacted to secure to the city of Dallas greater economy and efficiency in the administration of her government, an emergency and imperative public necessity exists that the<pb n="252" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force thirty days from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 5, A. D. 1881</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act entitled an act to amend sections 87, 96, 97, 98, 99, 127,131 and 132, of &#8220;An act to incorporate the City of Galves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, and to grant a new charter,&#8217; approved August 2, 1876.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section 87 of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereaf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 87. Nothing contained under the head of taxation shall be construed to prevent the city council from imposing, levying and collect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing special taxes and assessments for the improvement of the harbor, avenues, streets and alleys, as hereinafter provided.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That section 96 of said act be and the same is hereby amended, so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 96. That if any person shall fail, neglect or refuse to pay the taxes imposed upon him and his property within the time prescribed by the ordinances of said city, the collector shall, by virtue of his tax list and assessment roll, levy upon so much property liable to taxation belonging to such person, whether resident or non-resident, as may be sufficient to pay his, her or their taxes, and if the property levied on be personal property, the collector shall give notice of the time and place of sale, together with a brief description of the property levied on and to be sold, with the amount of taxes, interest, costs and fees due thereupon, for at least ten days previous to the day of sale, by advertisements in writing, to be posted at the courthouse door of Galveston county, and at two other public places within said city limits; and at the expiration of such notice, and on the day therein specified, the collector shall proceed to sell such property, at public auction, in front of the courthouse door of said Galveston county, within the limits aforesaid. In making sales of real property for taxes, the collector shall advertise the same for sale, by posting a list of the names of delinquents, for thirty days, as follows: one copy at the courthouse door of the county of Galveston, and a copy at two other public places within said city limits, giving in said advertisement such description as is given to the same on the tax roll in his hands, stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the name of the owner, if known, and if unknown, saying &#8220;un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />known,&#8221; together with the time, place and terms of sale; said sale to be for cash, to the highest and best bidder, at public outcry, at said court<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />house door, within said limits, between legal hours, on the first Tuesday of the month. The collector of taxes, in making sales for taxes due upon real estate, shall sell at auction, at the time and place appointed, so much of said real estate as may be necessary to pay the taxes, interest and pen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alties due, and all costs accruing thereon; and shall offer said real estate to the bidder who will pay the taxes, interest and penalties due, and costs of sale and execution of deed, for the least amount of said real estate, who shall be deemed the highest bidder. Should a less amount of said real estate than the whole parcel levied upon be sold for the taxes, inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est and penalties due, and all costs of sale and execution and deed, the<pb n="253" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>collector shall, in making his deed to the purchaser, begin at some corner of said parcel of real estate (or lot or lots), and designate the same in a square as nearly as practicable. No real estate set apart, used or desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated as a homestead shall be sold for taxes, other than the taxes due on such homestead; and if any person shall point out to the collector of taxes, within thirty days from the time the same shall become due, suffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient personal property belonging to him to pay all taxes assessed against him, together with interest, penalties and costs, the collector shall imme<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diately levy upon and sell such property so pointed out, in accordance with the provisions hereinbefore mentioned, regulating &#8216;tax sales&#8217; of personal property.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That section 97 of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 97. The collector of taxes shall execute and deliver to the purchaser, upon the payment of the amount for which the estate was sold, and costs and penalties, a deed for the real estate sold, which deed shall vest a good and perfect title in the purchaser, if not redeemed in two years, as hereinafter provided, which deed shall state the cause of sale, the amount sold, the price for which the real estate was sold, the name of the person, firm, company or corporation on whom the demand for the taxes was made, provided the name is known, and if unknown, say<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing &#8216;unknown,&#8217; the same description of the land as given in the tax rolls, and such other description as may be practicable, for better identifica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion; and when real estate has been sold he shall convey, subject to the right of redemption hereinafter provided for, all the right and interest which the former owner had therein at the time When the assessment was made. The deed of the collector, as hereinbefore provided, of any real estate sold, shall be prima facie evidence in all controversies and suits in relation to the right of the purchaser, his, her or their assigns, to the premises thereby conveyed, of the following facts:</p>
<p>&#8220;First, that the land or lot or portions thereof conveyed, was subject to taxation or assessment, at the time the same was advertised for sale, and had been listed in the time and manner required by law.</p>
<p>&#8220;Second, that the taxes or assessment were not paid at any time before the same.</p>
<p>&#8220;Third, that the land, lot or portion thereof conveyed, had not been redeemed from the sale at the date of the deed, and shall be conclusive evidence of the following facts:</p>
<p>&#8220;1. That the land, lot or portion thereof sold, was advertised for sale in the manner and for the time required by law.</p>
<p>&#8220;2. That the property was sold for taxes or assessments, as stated in the deed.</p>
<p>&#8220;3. That the grantee in the deed was the purchaser.</p>
<p>&#8220;4. That the sale was conducted in the manner prescribed by law; and in all controversies and suits involving the title to land claimed and held under and by virtue of such deed, the person or persons claiming adverse to the title conveyed by such deed, shall be required to prove, in order to defeat the said title, either that the land was not subject to taxa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion at the date of the sale; that the taxes or assessment had been paid; that the land or lots had never been listed and assessed for taxation and assessment as required by this act, or some ordinance of the city, or that the same had been redeemed according to the provisions of this act, and that such redemption was made for the use and benefit of the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons having the right of redemption under the law; but no person<pb n="254" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall be permitted to question the title acquired by the said deed, without first showing that he, she or they, or the person under whom he, she or they claim title, had title to the land at the time of the sale, or that the title was obtained after the sale, and that all taxes due upon the lands have been paid by such person, or the person under whom he claims title as aforesaid; provided, however, that the owner of such property shall have the right to redeem the same at any time within two years of the day and date of the sale thereof, upon paying to the purchaser double the amount of the taxes for which the same was sold, together with the costs of such sale, and the amount of all taxes paid by the purchaser since such sale. The collector shall have full power to levy upon any personal property to satisfy any tax imposed by this act. All taxes shall be a lien upon the property upon which they are assessed, and if said taxes are not paid on or before the time prescribed by the ordinances of said city, the same shall, from such time, bear interest at the rate of eight (8) per centum per annum till paid, which interest shall be collected by the collector at the time and in the manner provided herein for the collection of taxes; and in case any property levied upon is about to be removed out of the city, the collector shall proceed to take into his pos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />session so much thereof as will pay the taxes assessed and costs of col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lection.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That section 98 of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 98. If, from any cause, the sale of the property levied upon or seized for taxes, shall not take place at the time appointed, the collec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tor shall appoint some other time, giving the like notice and proceed to sell such property in the manner prescribed in the first instance; and in case said property or any part thereof levied upon or seized for taxes, cannot be sold on the day advertised, such sale may be postponed from day to day until completed, of which postponement the collector shall give verbal notice at the expiration of sale each day. No sale shall be considered complete until payment of the purchase money, and if the same is not paid before the completion of such tax sales the collector shall resell the property and continue such sale until the same is complete."</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That section 99 of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 99. Should the collector of taxes fail to make sale of any real estate or personal property for want of a purchaser, he shall bid the same off to the city for the taxes, interest, penalties and all costs accru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing thereon, and thereupon the city shall receive in the corporate name a deed for said property, and shall be vested with the same rights as other purchasers at such sales, and shall have power to sell and convey the same, and one deed shall include all parcels of land or lots bid off to the city, in any one day, at such tax sale. And after sale and purchase by the city of any real estate it shall not be lawful for said collector to levy upon or advertise, or sell the same for any remaining or accrued taxes due thereon, until the same shall have been redeemed by the owner or is sold by the city.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That section 127 of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 127: The city council shall be invested with full power and authority, upon the consent of the resident owners of a majority of the frontage or property on the streets to be improved, to grade, shell, repair, pave, or otherwise improve any avenue, street or alley, or any portion<pb n="255" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>thereof, within the limits of said city, whenever, by a vote of two-thirds of the aldermen elected, they may deem such improvement for the public interest; provided, the city council pay one-third and the owners of the property two-thirds thereof, except the intersection of the streets, from lot to lot, across the streets either way, shall be paid for by the city alone, and said cost shall be assessed on or against the property fronting on said thoroughfares, to be collected whenever such improvement is completed and accepted by the city council; provided, however, that the foregoing portion of this section in relation to &#8220;the consent of the resident owners of a majority of the frontage or property on the streets to be improved&#8221; shall not apply or relate to the following territory and streets of said city, to wit: From the south side of avenue A to the north side of Church street or avenue F, and from the east side of Twentieth street to the east side of Twenty-fifth street, and also on Avenue B or Strand street, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween the east side of Eighteenth street and the east side of Twentieth street; but as to said territory and streets the city council shall have the power and authority to make or cause to be made such improvements, whenever, by a vote of two-thirds of the aldermen elected, they may deem such improvements for the public interest.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That section 131 of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 131. The said city shall have power to issue bonds to the extent of thirteen hundred thousand dollars ($1,300,000) of the denomi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation of one hundred dollars, or any multiple thereof, payable forty years after date of their issue, bearing interest not to exceed five per cent. per annum, payable semi-annually; but the net proceeds of such bonds shall be used only in payingor redeeming legal and valid indebted<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness of the city now existing; provided, that the bonds herein authorized to be issued shall not be sold at less than par.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That section 132 of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 132a. The indebtedness of said city for all purposes, general as well as special, for five years after the passage of this act shall not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed thirteen hundred thousand dollars ($1,300,000), nor shall such in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />debtedness ever thereafter exceed the amount of five per cent. of the value of the taxable property of the city as shown by the regular assess<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment thereof, for the purpose of taxation; and it shall be the duty of the city clerk, quarterly, to make to the city council, for their information and guidance, a full, accurate and correct statement and report of the whole indebtedness of the city, which shall also be published for three days in the official journal of the city. Any member of the city council who shall knowingly vote for or in any manner aid or promote the pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age or adoption of any ordinance, resolution or other act of the city council, increasing the indebtedness of the city, beyond the limits herein prescribed, shall, thereby vacate his office, and shall be deemed guilty of malfeasance in office, and being thereof convicted, shall be punished in the manner and to the extent provided in section 30 of this act.</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 132b. Whenever the value of the taxable property of the city of Galveston exceeds the sum of thirty million dollars ($30,000,000), and the city council of the city of Galveston deem it advisable and necessary for the purpose of improving the city to contract additional indebtedness, a board of registration, consisting of three tax-payers, shall be appointed by the city council, whose duty it shall be to register the names of all citi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zens, on presentation of city tax receipts for the preceding year. The board<pb n="256" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of registration to endorse upon the tax receipt the date and number of registration. Two-thirds of the tax-payers so registered shall be suffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient to increase the indebtedness, but not in excess of five per cent. of the taxable value of property.&#8221;</p>
<p>See. 9. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict or inconsistent with the provisions of this act he and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. It being important that the city of Galveston should have the power to at once enforce the speedy collection of its taxes, to improve its streets, and to issue bonds for the payment of its outstanding valid indebtedness, some of which powers do not exist, and others are doubtful under its present charter, an emergency is created that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted, and the near approach of the close of the session, and the large amount of legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lative business undisposed of, causes an imperative public necessity which justifies a suspension of the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days, and it is so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 5, A. D. 1881</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
<p>THE STATE OF TEXAS, <lb/>D<smcap>EPAKTSIENT OF</smcap> S<smcap>TATE</smcap>.</p>
<p>I, T. H. Bowman, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, do hereby certify that I have compared the foregoing laws, passed by the Seven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth Legislature, with the originals now on file in this department, and that they are true copies thereof. I further certify that the Seven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth Legislature of the State of Texas convened at the city of Austin on the eleventh day of January, A. D. 1881, and adjourned on the first day of April, A. D. 1881.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I hereunto sign my name and affix <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L. s.]</p></body></floatingText>the seal of the State of Texas, at the city of Austin, on this the thirteenth day of May, A. D. 1881.</p>
<closer>
<signed>T. H. BOWMAN, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="257" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<p>Baker, Martin L.&#8212;act for relief of........................ 8</p>
<p>Brownson, J. M.&#8212;act for relief of......................... 9</p>
<p>Bagby, T. M.&#8212;act for relief of sureties................... 5</p>
<p>Crain, Roden T.&#8212;act for relief of......................... 8</p>
<p>Dallas&#8212;charter of city, amended.......................... 10</p>
<p>Ellis, L. A.&#8212;act for relief of............................ 5</p>
<p>Floyd, Joseph&#8212;land certificate issued to, validated....... 6</p>
<p>French, Wm. N.&#8212;commissioner of the land office to approve bounty warrant issued to heirs of......................... 4</p>
<p>Gibbs, C. C.&#8212;act for relief of............................ 6</p>
<p>Grooms, Lewis&#8212;act for relief of heirs of.................. 9</p>
<p>Galveston&#8212;charter of city, amended....................... 12</p>
<p>Herrin, Moses&#8212;land certificate granted to................. 1</p>
<p>Hearne, Thomas B.&#8212;act for relief of....................... 7</p>
<p>Hyde, Miranda&#8212;act for relief of........................... 8</p>
<p>Houston&#8212;charter of city, amended.......................... 1</p>
<p>Harrison, W. M.&#8212;act for relief of......................... 5</p>
<p>Mexican Telegraph Co.&#8212;act authorizing commissioner of land office to issue patent to......................... 8</p>
<p>Plummer, Jacob&#8212;act for relief of heirs of................. 8</p>
<p>Reynolds, John P.&#8212;act for relief of heirs of.............. 8</p>
<p>Relief, Private&#8212;acts granting................. 1-4-5-6-7-8-9</p>
<p>Townsend, Henry J.&#8212;act for relief of heirs of............. 9</p>
<p>Treasurer, State&#8212;authorized to pay J. M. Brownson certain coupons......................... 9</p>
<pb n="258" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" />
</div2>
</div1>
<pb n="259" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="I" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main"><b>GENERAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>PASSED AT THE <lb/>CALLED SESSION OF THE SEVENTEENTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>CONVENED <lb/>AT THE CITY OF AUSTIN</b></head>
<byline>APRIL 6, 1882, AND ADJOURNED MAY 5, 1882.</byline>
<byline>BY AUTHORITY.</byline>
<byline>GALVESTON 1882</byline>
<pb n="260" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="II" />
<pb n="261" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<head type="sub">GENERAL LAWS OF TEXAS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTEE I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation for mileage and per diem pay of members and per diem pay of officers and employees of the called session of the Seventeenth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of forty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated, out of any moneys in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the payment of mileage and per diem pay of the members and the payment of the per diem pay of the officers and employees of the called session of the Seventeenth Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature.</p>
<p>See. 2. That the certificate of the Secretary of the Seriate, approved by the President thereof, or the certificate of the Chief Clerk of the House, approved by the Speaker thereof, shall be sufficient evidence to the Comptroller, upon which he shall audit the claims and issue his war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rants upon the Treasurer for the respective amounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the balance of the moneys remaining in the treasury heretofore appropriated for the per diem pay and mileage of the mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers and the per diem pay of the officers and employees of any preceding session of the Legislature of the State of Texas be and the same is hereby reappropriated for the purposes specified in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. And whereas, the called session of the Seventeenth Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture, for the payment of the members and officers of which this law is enacted, is now in session, and public policy requires this payment, there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore an imperative public necessity exists, that the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is so enacted; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after this passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 11, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to defray the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tingent expenses of the Seventeenth Legislature, convened on April 6, 1882, in extra session, by proclamation of the Governor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, It is of sufficient importance that the contingent expenses of the extra session of the Seventeenth Legislature be promptly paid, in order that the material furnished and labor performed may be procured at cash prices; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of ten thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated out of any moneys in the treasury not<pb n="262" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>otherwise appropriated, to pay the contingent expenses of the extra ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of the Seventeenth Legislature; and that except in the case of ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />counts for printing done and stationery furnished, the approval by the chairman of the committee on contingent expenses of either house, coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tersigned by the President of the Senate or Speaker of the House, as the case may be, shall be sufficient authority to authorize the Comptroller to issue his warrant on the State Treasurer, for the payment of any ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />count against said fund. The accounts for printing and stationery shall take the course prescribed by the Revised Statutes.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the public importance of the objects herein contem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plated creates an imperative public necessity and emergency fully au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorizing the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring the reading of bills upon three several days, and the said rule is hereby suspended; and this act shall be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 11, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide temporary rooms for the Supreme Court, Court of Appeals, the Commissioners of Appeals and the law library of the State at Austin.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Secretary of State he, and he is hereby authorized, to contract at once with William Brueggerhoff for the rent of the upper story of his building, on Congress avenue, in Austin, and six rooms on the second floor of said building for the use of the Supreme Court, the Court of Ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />peals and the Commissioners of Appeals, and for the law library of the State at Austin. The said contract shall be made for three months, with the privilege of continuing for a longer period, at a rent not to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed the rate of $562.50 for three months, and with a proviso if the building shall be purchased by the State, during the present session of the Legislature, that no rent shall be paid.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The expenses to be incurred in moving the books and furni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture to said building and in preparing the rooms in said building for the courts shall be paid on vouchers, to be approved before presentation by the Secretary of State; and the sum of one thousand dollars or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated to carry out the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Whereas, it is necessary, in order that the Supreme Court, Court of Appeals and Commissioners of Appeals may have suitable rooms in which to hold their sessions, that this act shall take effect from and after its passage; therefore an emergency exists and [an] imperative pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic necessity demands the suspension of the constitutional rule which re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quires a hill to be read on three several days, therefore that the rule be suspended and that this bill take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 11, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="263" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend article 4256 of the Revised Statutes of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That article 4256 of the Revised Statutes of the State of Texas shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 4256. No railroad company shall demand or receive for trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porting a passenger over its line of road exceeding three cents for each mile, or fraction of a mile, it may transport such passenger, and any pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />senger shall be entitled to have transported with him baggage, not to exceed one hundred pounds, free of charge.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 14, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to extend the time within which all persons whose lands have been sold for taxes and bought in by the State may redeem the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all lands which have been sold for taxes and bought in by the State shall be restored to the owners of the same, if within twelve months from the passage of this act said owners, or their agents, shall pay to the State the original taxes due thereon, and taxes due for each year since said sale, with eight per cent interest thereon per annum from the date of the accrual of each year&#8217;s taxes, and all costs which have accrued thereon, and five per cent commissions to the collector, under such rules and reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ulations as shall be prescribed by the Comptroller of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas, There are persons whose lands have been sold who rare anxious to redeem the same, an emergency exists and an imperative public necessity demands that the constitutional rule requiring all bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this bill take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 20, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>lakes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to repeal all laws granting lands or land cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates to any person, firm, corporation or company for the construc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of railroads, canals and ditches.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all laws or parts of laws now in force granting lands or land certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates to any person, firm, corporation or company for the construction of railroads, canals and ditches, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that the public domain subject to location by the owners of these certificates has been exhausted creates an imperative public necessity and an emergency requiring the constitutional rule that bills be read on three several days in each honse be suspended, and the same is therefore suspended; and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 22, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="264" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide temporary shelter for the lunatics in the Asylum, rendered necessary by the recent burning of one of the Lunatic Asylum buildings.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of fourteen hundred dollars, or so much thereof as may he necessary, he and the same is hereby appropriated to erect temporary shelter for the lunatics who occupied the asylum building which was burned during the present session.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The necessity of providing immediate shelter for said lunatics creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity for the imme<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diate passage of this act, and for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house; said rule is therefore suspended, and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 25, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize district judges to fix times for holding courts in newly organized counties.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That whenever any unorganized county within this State has become organized, or may hereafter become organized, there being no time fixed by law for holding district court in such counties, the district judge in whose judicial district such county is situated shall fix times to hold at least two terms of court each year in each of such counties, by a written declaration, to be forwarded by the district judge to the district clerk of the county, and by him spread on the minutes of the district court. When the times are so fixed they shall not be changed except by an act of the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Owing to the recent organization of Wilbarger county, and there being no time fixed by law for holding courts in said county, an imperative public necessity exists that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended; and an emergency exists that this act should take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 25, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing the Board of Statistics to apply such portion of the existing appropriation as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary for the payment of statistical clerks.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. [Be it] resolved by the Senate and House of Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives of the State of Texas, That the Board of Statistics be, and they are hereby authorized to apply such portion of the existing appropriation as<pb n="265" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>may be necessary for the payment of statistical clerks to complete and publish the statistical work.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The amount of labor to be performed, and the early demand for such statistical work, creates an emergency and an imperative neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity for a suspension of the rules, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 27, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to attach the unorganized county of Crockett to the county of Kinney for judicial purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the unorganized county of Crockett be, and the same is hereby at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tached, for judicial purposes, to the county of Kinney.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The fact that under existing laws of this State the unorgan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized county of Crockett is not attached to any organized county for ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial purposes, and the fact that the public interests demand that said unorganized county be attached to some organized county, that the courts of this State may have jurisdiction over said unorganized county, creates an imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring a bill to be read on three several days be suspended, and an emergency that this act should take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 28, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for running and marking the boun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dary line between the State of Texas and the territory of the United; States, from the northeast corner of said State to the degree of long<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />itude one hundred west from London and twenty-three degrees west from Washington, as said line is described in the treaty between the United States and Spain, of February 22, 1819, and for the payment of the expenses of such survey.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor of this State be and he is hereby authorized and em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />powered to appoint a suitable person, or persons, who, in conjunction with such person, or persons, as may be appointed by, or on behalf of, the United States, for the same purpose, Shall run and mark the boundary lines between the territories of the United States and the State of Texas, as follows: Beginning at a point where a line drawn north from the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tersection of the thirty-second degree of north latitude with the western bank of the Sabine river, crosses Red river and thence following the course of said river westwardly to the degree of longitude one hundred west from London, and twenty-three degrees west from Washington, as<pb n="266" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>said line was laid down in Melish&#8217;s map of the United States, published at Philadelphia, improved to the first of January, 1818, and designated in the treaty between the United States and Spain, made February 22, A. D. 1819.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said joint commission will report their survey, made in ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cordance with the foregoing section of this act, together with all neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary notes, maps, and other papers, in order that in fixing that part of the boundary between the Territories of the United States and the State of Texas the question may he definitely settled as to the true location of the one-hundreth degree of longitude west from London, and whether the north fork of Red River, or the Prairie Dog fork of said river, is the true Red River designated in the treaty between the United States and Spain made February 22, 1819; and in locating said line said commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners shall be guided by actual surveys and measurements, together with such well established marks, natural and artificial, as may be found, and such well authenticated maps as may throw light upon the subject.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Such commissioner, or commissioners, on the part of Texas, shall attempt to have said survey, herein provided for by the joint com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission, made and performed between the first day of July and the first day of October of the year in which said survey is made, when the ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nary stage of water in each fork of said Red River may be observed; and when the main or principal Red River is ascertained as agreed upon in said treaty of 1819, and the point is fully designated where the one-hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dreth degree of longitude west from London, and twenty-third degree of longitude west from Washington, crosses said Red River, the same shall be plainly marked and defined as a corner in said boundary, and said commissioner shall establish such other permanent monuments as may be necessary to mark their work.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the sum of ten thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated out any money in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, to carry out the provisions of this act; provided, that the commissioner or commissioners on the part of Texas, shall act, in making such survey, under instructions from the Governor of the State, and shall receive for their services such sum or sums of money as the Governor may offer to pay, not to exceed the sum of three thousand dollars each; and provided further, that the person or persons, to be appointed and employed by the United States are not to be paid by the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The facts that the settlement of the boundary of that por<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the State of Texas embracing Greer county will involve impor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tant public as well private interests, which should be immediately set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled, and that the present session is confined to thirty days, creates an imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring that hills shall be read on three several days be suspended, and an emergency that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 2, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="267" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend articles 1026, 1027, 1028, 1029. 1030, 1031 and 1032, of chapter 5, title 26, and articles 1077, 1078, 1079, 1080, 1081 and 1082, of chapter 15, title 26, of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, approved February 21, 1879.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That articles 1026, 1027, 1028, 1029, 1030, 1031 and 1032, of chapter 5, title 26, of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, shall here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after read as follows, respectively:</p>
<p>Article 1026. The Supreme Court is authorized and required to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point one or more reporters of its decisions, who shall be subject to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moval by said court for any inefficiency or neglect of duty.</p>
<p>Article 1027. It shall be the duty of the reporter to prepare for publi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation, under the direction of the Supreme Court, the decisions thereof, and cause the same to be printed and published with promptness, as fast as there shall be a sufficient number to form a volume, and shall deliver to the Secretary of State, for the use of the State, one thousand copies of each volume of the reports.</p>
<p>Article 1028. Each volume shall contain an average number of pages of the volumes of Texas Reports, heretofore published, and each page shall be twenty-six ems, pica, wide and forty-six ems, pica, long. The type used shall be long primer and minion, of same size used in volume XXIII, Wallace&#8217;s United States Supreme Court Reports. The lines shall be leaded with not thicker than eight to pica leads. The paper, press work and binding shall be of the same style, and of at least equal quality, in every respect, with the volumes of Moore&#8217;s and Walker&#8217;s Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ports heretofore published. They shall be styled the &#8220;Texas Reports,&#8221; and shall be so styled on the title page and back thereof, and the num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bers of the volumes shall be continued on consecutively. The name of the reporter may be printed on the back, as on the volumes published by Moore and Walker. Each volume shall be copyrighted in the name of and for the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Article 1029. As soon as the opinions are recorded, the originals, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gether with the records anti papers in each case to he reported, shall be delivered to the reporter, upon his giving a receipt therefor, who shall return them to the respective clerks from whom he received them when he shall have finished using them.</p>
<p>Article 1030. The reporter shall be entitled to receive, in payment for the one thousand copies of each volume, delivered as aforesaid, the following compensation, viz: The sum of five dollars and fifty cents per page for as many pages as shall be contained in one copy of each volume so delivered.</p>
<p>Article 1031. When the reporter shall have delivered to the Secretary of State the copies of a volume of the reports, as required by this chap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter, the Comptroller of Public Accounts shall draw his warrant upon the State Treasurer for the amount of compensation due such reporter, based upon the certificate of the Secretary of State, and the certificate of the Board of Public Printing, that the reporter has delivered to the Secretary of State one thousand copies of the.... volume of the Texas Reports, containing.... pages, printed, published and bound in accordance with the provisions of this chapter. The Secretary of State is authorized to sell single copies of each volume delivered as aforesaid, for the sum of four dollars, exclusive of postage, the proceeds of such sale to be paid to<pb n="268" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the State Treasurer, and the Secretary of State to report thereon in his biennial report; provided, that the Secretary shall retain five hundred copies of each volume for the use of the State.</p>
<p>Article 1032. The Supreme Court shall designate, by order or other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise, all cases to be reported, and only such cases shall be reported as shall be designated by the Supreme Court for Publication, and only the main propositions specified by the court contained in the briefs of cases reported with the authorities relied on, shall be incorporated in such re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ports.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That articles 1077, 1078, 1079, 1080, 1081 and 1082, of chap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter 15, title 26, of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, shall hereafter read as follows, respectively:</p>
<p>Article 1077. The Court of Appeals is authorized and required to appoint one or more reporters of its decisions in criminal cases, and of such other of its decisions as may be required by law to be published; such reporters shall be subject to removal by said court for any ineffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciency or neglect of duty.</p>
<p>Article 1078. It shall be the duty of the reporter to prepare for pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lication, under the direction of said court, the said decisions thereof, and cause the same to be printed and published with promptness, as fast as there shall be a sufficient number to form a volume, and shall deliver to the Secretary of State for the use of the State, one thousand copies of each volume of the reports. The Court of Appeals shall designate, by order or otherwise, all cases to be reported, and only such cases shall be reported as shall be designated by the Court of Appeals for publication, and only the main propositions specified by the court contained in the briefs of cases reported, with the authorities relied on, shall be incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porated in such reports.</p>
<p>Article 1079. Each volume shall contain an average number of pages of the volumes of the Texas Reports heretofore published, and each page shall be twenty-six ems, pica, wide and forty-six ems, pica, long. The type used shall be long primer and minion, of same size used in volume XXIII, Wallace&#8217;s United States Supreme Court Reports. The lines shall be leaded with not thicker than eight to pica leads. The paper, presswork and binding shall be of the same style and of at least equal quality in every respect with the volumes of Moore and Walker&#8217;s reports heretofore published. They shall be styled the &#8220;Court of Appeals Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pors,&#8221; and shall be so styled on the title page and back thereof, and the numbers of the volumes shall be continued on consecutively. The name of the reporter may be printed on the back, as on the volumes published by Moore and Walker.</p>
<p>Article 1080. The reporter shall be entitled to receive in payment for the one thousand copies of each volume delivered as aforesaid, the following compensation, viz., the sum of five dollars and fifty cents per page for as many pages as shall be contained in one copy of each vol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ume so delivered.</p>
<p>Article 1081. As soon as the opinions are recorded, the originals, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gether with the records and papers in each case to be reported, shall be delivered to the reporter, upon his giving a receipt therefor, who shall return them to the respective clerks from whom he received them, when he shall have finished using them.</p>
<p>Article 1082. When the reporter shall have delivered to the Secretary of State the copies of a volume of the reports as required by this chap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter, the Comptroller of Public Accounts shall draw his warrant upon the<pb n="269" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>State Treasurer for the amount of compensation due such reporter, based upon the certificate of the Secretary of State, and the certificate of the Board of Public Printing, that the reporter has delivered to the Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary of State one thousand copies of the.... volume of the &#8220;Court of Appeals Report,&#8221; containing.... pages, printed, published and bound in accordance with the provisions of this chapter. The Secretary of State is authorized to sell single copies of each volume delivered as afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said, for the sum of four dollars, exclusive of postage, the proceeds of such sales to be paid to the State Treasurer and the Secretary of State to report thereon in his biennial report; provided, that the Secretary of State shall retain five hundred copies of each volume for the use of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The fact that there is no law by which the State can retain the copyright to the reports of its Supreme and Appellate Courts, and the further fact that the public interest demands an immediate change in the existing law upon the subject, creates an imperative public neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity and an emergency that the rule, requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is hereby suspended, and that this act take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted; provided, that nothing contained in this act shall be held to apply to volumes of reports the manuscript of which is now in the hands of the publisher.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 3, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend title 4 of the Revised Civil Stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />utes of the State of Texas, and to reapportion the State into Sena<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />torial and Representative Districts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That articles ll, 12, 13, 14 and 15, of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas shall be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 11. The senatorial districts of the State of Texas are consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tuted as follows, each of which shall be entitled to elect a senator:</p>
<p>Number 1&#8212;The counties of Jefferson, Liberty, Orange, Jasper, New<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, Tyler, Polk, Hardin, Chambers and San Jacinto.</p>
<p>Number 2&#8212;The county of Sabine, San Augustine, Nacogdoches, Shelby, Rusk and Panola.</p>
<p>Number 3&#8212;The county of Harrison.</p>
<p>Number 4&#8212;The counties of Cass, Marion, Bowie, Morris and Titus.</p>
<p>Number 5&#8212;The counties of Delta, Hopkins, Franklin, Camp and Hunt.</p>
<p>Number 6&#8212;The counties of Rains, Wood, Upshur, Gregg and Smith.</p>
<p>Number 7&#8212;The counties of VanZandt, Henderson, Anderson and Cherokee.</p>
<p>Number 8&#8212;The counties of Houston, Leon, Madison, Grimes and An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gelina.</p>
<p>Number 9&#8212;The counties of Trinity, Walker, Montgomery and Harris.</p>
<p>Number 10&#8212;The counties of Galveston, Brazoria and Matagorda.</p>
<p>Number 11&#8212;The counties of Wharton, Colorado, Lavaca and Gonzales.</p>
<p>Number 12&#8212;The counties of Fort Bend, Burleson, Waller, Austin and Washington.</p>
<pb n="270" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Number 13&#8212;The counties of Fayette, Bastrop and Lee.</p>
<p>Number 14&#8212;The counties of Brazos, Robertson and Milam.</p>
<p>Number 15&#8212;The counties of Limestone, Freestone and Navarro.</p>
<p>Number 16&#8212;The counties of Kaufman, Rockwall and Dallas.</p>
<p>Number 17&#8212;The counties of Collin and Denton.</p>
<p>Number 18&#8212;The counties of Grayson and Cooke.</p>
<p>Number 19&#8212;The counties of Montague, Clay, Wichita, Archer, Young, Throckmorton, Baylor, Wilbarger, Greer, Hardeman, Knox, Has<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />kell, Stonewall, King, Cottle, Childress, Collingsworth, Wheeler, Hemp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hill, Lamb, Lipscomb, Ochiltree, Roberts, Gray, Donley, Hall, Motley, Dickens, Kent, Garza, Crosby, Floyd, Briscoe, Armstrong, Carson, Hutch<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inson, Hansford, Sherman, Moore, Potter, Randall, Swisher, Hale, Lub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bock, Castro, Deaf Smith, Terry, Oldham, Hartley, Dallam, Parmer, Hockley, Lynn, Bailey, Cochran and Yoakum.</p>
<p>Number 20&#8212;The counties of Jack, Wise, Tarrant and Parker.</p>
<p>Number 21&#8212;The counties of Johnson, Ellis and Hill.</p>
<p>Number 22&#8212;The counties of McLennan and Falls.</p>
<p>Number 23&#8212;The counties of Bell, Hamilton, Coryell aud Lampasas.</p>
<p>Number 24&#8212;The counties of Burnet, Williamson and Travis.</p>
<p>Number 25&#8212;The counties of Blanco, Hays, Kendall, Comal, Guada<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lupe, Caldwell and Llano.</p>
<p>Number 26&#8212;The counties of Wilson, Karnes, Atascosa, McMullen, Live Oak, Bee, San Patricio, Refugio, Goliad, Calhoun, DeWitt, Jack<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, Aransas and Victoria.</p>
<p>Number 27&#8212;The counties of Cameron, Hidalgo, Starr, Zapata, Enci<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nal, Duval, Nueces, Webb, LaSalle, Dimmit, Frio, Zavalla, Uvalde, Mav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erick and Kinney.</p>
<p>Number 28&#8212;The counties of Bexar, Medina, Bandera, Kerr, Ed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wards, Gillespie, Mason, Kimble, Menard, Crockett, Tom Green, Presidio, El Paso and Pecos.</p>
<p>Number 29&#8212;The counties of Stephens, Eastland, Comanche, Brown, San Saba, McCulloch, Coleman, Callahan, Shackelford, Jones, Taylor, Runnels, Concho, Nolan, Fisher, Mitchell, Scurry, Howard, Borden, Daw<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, Martin, Gaines and Andrews.</p>
<p>Number 30&#8212;The counties of Palo Pinto, Hood, Somervell, Erath and Bosque.</p>
<p>Number 31&#8212;The counties of Fannin, Lamar and Red River.</p>
<p>Article 12. The county judges of the following counties shall receive returns and count the votes and issue certificates of election to persons receiving the highest number of votes for Senator at any election in their respective districts, to-wit:</p>
<p>First district&#8212;Tyler county.</p>
<p>Second district&#8212;Rusk county.</p>
<p>Third district&#8212;Harrison county.</p>
<p>Fourth district&#8212;Bowie county.</p>
<p>Fifth district&#8212;Hopkins county.</p>
<p>Sixth district&#8212;Smith county.</p>
<p>Seventh district&#8212;Anderson county.</p>
<p>Eighth district&#8212;Houston county.</p>
<p>Ninth district&#8212;Harris county.</p>
<p>Tenth district&#8212;Galveston county.</p>
<p>Eleventh district&#8212;Lavaca county.</p>
<p>Twelfth district&#8212;Washington county.</p>
<p>Thirteenth district&#8212;Bastrop county.</p>
<pb n="271" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Fourteenth district&#8212;Brazos county.</p>
<p>Fifteenth district&#8212;Navarro county.</p>
<p>Sixteenth district&#8212;Dallas county.</p>
<p>Seventeenth district&#8212;Collin county.</p>
<p>Eighteenth district&#8212;Grayson county.</p>
<p>Nineteenth district&#8212;Montague county.</p>
<p>Twentieth district&#8212;Tarrant county.</p>
<p>Twenty-first district&#8212;Ellis county.</p>
<p>Twenty-second district&#8212;McLennan county.</p>
<p>Twenty-third district&#8212;Coryell county.</p>
<p>Twenty-fourth district&#8212;Travis county.</p>
<p>Twenty-fifth, district&#8212;Hays county.</p>
<p>Twenty-sixth district&#8212;Goliad county.</p>
<p>Twenty-seventh district&#8212;Webb county.</p>
<p>Twenty-eighth district&#8212;Bexar county.</p>
<p>Twenty-ninth district&#8212;Eastland county.</p>
<p>Thirtieth district&#8212;Erath county.</p>
<p>Thirty-first district&#8212;Lamar county.</p>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Representative Districts.</head>
<p>Article 13 shall hereafter read as follows: Article 13. The represen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tative districts of the State, and the number of representatives to be elected by each district, are as follows:</p>
<p>Number 1&#8212;The counties of Liberty, Chambers, Jefferson, Orange and Hardin shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 2&#8212;The counties of San Jacinto and Polk shall elect one rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentative.</p>
<p>Number 3&#8212;The counties of Jasper, Tyler and Newton shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 4&#8212;The counties of Nacogdoches and Angelina shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 5&#8212;The counties of Sabine, Shelby and San Augustine shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 6&#8212;The county of Rusk shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 7&#8212;The county of Panola shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 8&#8212;The county of Cherokee shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 9&#8212;The county of Anderson shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 10&#8212;The counties of Anderson and Henderson shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 11&#8212;The counties of Camp and Upshur shall elect one repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentative.</p>
<p>Number 12&#8212;The county of Smith shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 13&#8212;The county of Houston shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 14&#8212;The county of Harrison shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 15&#8212;The counties of Harrison, Panola, Rusk, Shelby, Sabine and San Augustine shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 16&#8212;The county of Cass shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 17&#8212;The counties of Marion, Cass, Bowie and Morris shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>Number 18&#8212;The county of Red River shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 19&#8212;The counties of Titus, Franklin and Red River shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 20&#8212;The county of Lamar shall elect one representative.</p>
<pb n="272" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Number 21&#8212;The county of Fannin shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 22&#8212;The counties of Lamar and Fannin shall elect one rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentative.</p>
<p>Number 23&#8212;The counties of Lamar, Fannin and Delta shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 24&#8212;The county of Hopkins shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 25&#8212;The county of Hunt shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 26&#8212;The county of Van Zandt shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 27&#8212;The county of Grayson shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>Number 28&#8212;The county of Collin shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 29&#8212;The counties of Denton and Collin shall elect one repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentative.</p>
<p>Number 30&#8212;The county of Cooke shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 31&#8212;The counties of Cooke and Grayson shall elect one rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentative.</p>
<p>Number 32&#8212;The county of Denton shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 33&#8212;The county of Dallas shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>Number 34&#8212;The county of Tarrant shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 35&#8212;The counties of Dallas, Tarrant and Rockwall shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 36&#8212;The county of Johnson shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 37&#8212;The county of Ellis shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 38&#8212;The county of Hill shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 39&#8212;The counties of Johnson, Hill, Ellis and Navarro shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 40&#8212;The counties of Hood, Erath, Bosque and Somervell shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>Number 41&#8212;The counties of Young, Wise and Jack shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 42&#8212;The counties of Palo Pinto, Stephens and Eastland shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 43&#8212;The counties of Throckmorton, Shackelford, Callahan, Taylor, Jones, Nolan, Mitchell, Haskell, Stonewall, Kent, Garza, Lynn, Terry, Yoakum, Gaines, Dawson, Borden, Scurry, Fisher, Howard, Mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin, Andrews, Archer, Wichita, Baylor, Wheeler, Oldham, Knox, King, Dickens, Crosby, Lubbock, Hockley, Cochran, Bailey, Lamb, Hale, Floyd, Motley, Cottle, Wilbarger, Childress, Hall, Briscoe, Swisher, Castro, Parmer, Greer, Deaf Smith, Randall, Armstrong, Donley, Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lingsworth, Gray, Carson, Potter, Hutchinson, Hartley, Moore, Roberts, Hemphill, Lipscomb, Ochiltree, Hansford, Sherman, Hardeman and Dallam shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 44&#8212;The counties oi Montague and Clay shall elect one rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentative.</p>
<p>Number 45&#8212;The county of Wise shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 46&#8212;The county of Parker shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 47&#8212;The county of Kaufman shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 48&#8212;The county of Robertson shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 49&#8212;The counties of Leon and Madison shall elect one rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentative.</p>
<p>Number 50&#8212;The county of Brazos shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 51&#8212;The counties of Bell, Milam and Robertson shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 52&#8212;The county of Grimes shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 53&#8212;The counties of Fort Bend and Waller shall elect one representative.</p>
<pb n="273" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Number 54&#8212;The counties of Montgomery, Walker, Trinity and Har<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ris shall elect three representatives.</p>
<p>Number 55&#8212;The county of Falls shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 56&#8212;The county of Bell shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 57&#8212;The county of Milam shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 58&#8212;The county of Limestone shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 59&#8212;The county of Freestone shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 60&#8212;The county of Navarro shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 61&#8212;The county of McLennan shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 62&#8212;The counties of McLennan, Limestone and Falls shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 63&#8212;The counties of Coryell and Hamilton shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 64&#8212;The counties of Galveston and Brazoria shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 65&#8212;The county of Galveston shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 66&#8212;The counties of Brazoria, Galveston, Matagorda and Wharton shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 67&#8212;The county of Colorado shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 68&#8212;The county of Austin shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 69&#8212;The county of Lavaca shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 70&#8212;The county of Fayette shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>Number 71&#8212;The county of Washington shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 72&#8212;The counties of Washington, Burleson and Lee shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 73&#8212;The counties of Burleson and Lee shall elect one repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentative.</p>
<p>Number 74&#8212;The county of Bastrop shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 75&#8212;The county of Travis shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>Number 76&#8212;The counties of Burnet and Lampasas shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 77&#8212;The counties of Brown and Comanche shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 78&#8212;The county of Williamson shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 79&#8212;The counties of Llano, San Saba, Concho, McCulloch, Coleman and Runnels shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 80&#8212;The counties of El Paso, Edwards, Menard, Pecos, Pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sidio, Crockett and Tom Green shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 81&#8212;The counties of Kinney, Dimmit, Frio, Maverick, Uvalde and Zavalla shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 82&#8212;The counties of Atascosa, Karnes and Wilson shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 83&#8212;The counties of Duval, Encinal, Hidalgo, Starr, Webb and Zapata shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>Number 84&#8212;The counties of Bandera, Kerr, Kimble, Mason, Kendall and Medina shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 85&#8212;The counties of Bee, LaSalle, Live Oak, McMullen, Nue<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ces and San Patricio shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 86&#8212;The county of Bexar shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>Number 87&#8212;The counties of Aransas, Calhoun, De Witt, Goliad, Jack<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, Refugio and Victoria shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>Number 88&#8212;The county of Cameron shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 89&#8212;The counties of Blanco, Comal and Gillespie shall elect one representative.</p>
<pb n="274" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Number 90&#8212;The county of Gonzales shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 91&#8212;The counties of Caldwell, Guadalupe and Hays shall elect two representatives.</p>
<p>Number 92&#8212;The county of Harris shall elect one representative.</p>
<p>Number 93&#8212;The counties of Smith and Gregg shall elect one rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentative.</p>
<p>Number 94&#8212;The counties of Wood and Rains shall elect one repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentative.</p>
<p>In the several representative districts composed of more counties than one, the county judges of the following named counties shall receive the returns and issue certificates of election to the representatives elected in their respective districts; and article 14 of the Revised Civil Statutess shall read as follows:</p>
<p>In the first district&#8212;Jefferson county.</p>
<p>In the second district&#8212;Polk county.</p>
<p>In the third district&#8212;Tyler county.</p>
<p>In the fourth district&#8212;Nacogdoches county.</p>
<p>In the fifth district&#8212;Shelby county.</p>
<p>In the tenth district&#8212;Henderson county.</p>
<p>In the eleventh district&#8212;Upshur county.</p>
<p>In the fifteenth district&#8212;Rusk county.</p>
<p>In the seventeenth district&#8212;Bowie county.</p>
<p>In the nineteenth district&#8212;Titus county.</p>
<p>In the twenty-second district&#8212;Lamar county.</p>
<p>In the twenty-third district&#8212;Lamar county.</p>
<p>In the twenty-ninth district&#8212;Collin county.</p>
<p>In the thirty-first district&#8212;Grayson county.</p>
<p>In the thirty-fifth district&#8212;Dallas county.</p>
<p>In the thirty-ninth district&#8212;Ellis county.</p>
<p>In the fortieth district&#8212;Hood county.</p>
<p>In the forty-first district&#8212;Wise county.</p>
<p>In the forty-second district&#8212;Eastland county.</p>
<p>In the forty-third district&#8212;Shackelford county.</p>
<p>In the forty-fourth district&#8212;Montague county.</p>
<p>In the forty-ninth district&#8212;Leon county.</p>
<p>In the fifty-first district&#8212;Bell county.</p>
<p>In the fifty-third district&#8212;Waller county.</p>
<p>In the fifty-fourth district&#8212;Montgomery county.</p>
<p>In the sixty-second district&#8212;MeLennan county.</p>
<p>In the sixty-third district&#8212;Coryell county.</p>
<p>In the sixty-fourth district&#8212;Galveston county.</p>
<p>In the sixty-sixth district&#8212;Galveston county.</p>
<p>In the seventy-second district&#8212;Burleson county.</p>
<p>In the seventy-third district&#8212;Burleson county.</p>
<p>In the seventy-sixth district&#8212;Burnet county.</p>
<p>In the seventy-seventh district&#8212;Brown county.</p>
<p>In the seventy-ninth district&#8212;Llano county.</p>
<p>In the eightieth district&#8212;El Paso county.</p>
<p>In the eighty-first district&#8212;Kinney county.</p>
<p>In the eighty-second district&#8212;Karnes county.</p>
<p>In the eighty-third district&#8212;Webb county.</p>
<p>In the eighty-fourth district&#8212;Bandera county.</p>
<p>In the eighty-fifth district&#8212;Live Oak county.</p>
<p>In the eighty-seventh district&#8212;Aransas county.</p>
<pb n="275" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>In the eighty-ninth district&#8212;Blanco county.</p>
<p>In the ninety-first district&#8212;Caldwell county.</p>
<p>In the ninety-third district&#8212;Gregg county.</p>
<p>In the ninety-fourth district&#8212;Wood county.</p>
<p>Article 15. In all senatorial or representative districts comprised of but one county, the county judge of that county shall receive the returns and issue the certificate of election to the senator or representative elected, as provided in article 12.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the close of the session, and the large amount of business undisposed of, creates an imperative public necessity justifying the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and it is so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 3, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the destruction of certain en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />graved bonds of the State, which were never used, engraved under acts approved August 5, 1870, and April 21, 1879, and to make an appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Treasurer of the State shall, in the presence of the Governor and Comptroller, burn the engraved four and five per cent bonds, with coupons attached, which were engraved under an act approved April 21, 1879, and which were never used, aggregating in amount about one mil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lion eight hundred and fifty-one thousand and eighty dollars. That the six hundred bonds for one thousand each, now stored in the vaults of the Bank of Yew York, shall, under the direction of the State Treasurer, be canceled in Yew York before their return to the Treasury Department of the State and final burning.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor, Treasurer and Comptroller shall sign a written statement specifying all the bonds destroyed under this act, with the date of their burning, specifying the numbers, which shall be filed by the Treasurer, and be safely deposited and kept in the vault of the treasury.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Treasurer shall also, in the presence of the Governor and Comptroller, burn the engraved bonds with coupons attached now stored in the Governor&#8217;s office, known as the International Railroad bonds, said bonds reciting, on their face, to have been issued by virtue of &#8220;An act to incorporate the International Railroad Company, and to provide for the add of the State in constructing the same,&#8221; approved August 5, 1870; some of said bonds being unsigned and some having on them the signa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture of Edmund J. Davis and G. W. Honey; and the Treasurer shall also keep and file a record of these bonds so destroyed, as provided in section two above.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the sum of two hundred dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated to carry out the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Whereas, The coupons of the five hundred dollar bonds issued under said act bear the lithograph signature of the Governor of the State, and the interest of the State requires their immediate de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction, an emergency and an imperative public necessity exists for<pb n="276" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>suspending the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and for the immediate passage of this act; therefore, said rule is hereby sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended, and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 4, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend article 3602, chapter 10, title 71, of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, relating to the hiring of county convicts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That article 3602, chapter 10, title 71, of the Revised Civil Statutes, shall be amended so as to read hereafter as follows:</p>
<p>Article 3602. Any person who may be convicted of a misdemeanor or petty offense, and who shall be committed to jail in default of the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the fine and costs adjudged against him, shall be hired out to any individual, company or corporation within the county of conviction, to remain in said county; and the proceeds of said hiring, when collected, shall be applied, first, to the payment of the costs, and second, to the payment of the fine, and every convict shall be entitled to a credit of fifty cents on his fine and costs for each day he may serve under such hiring, including Sundays, and he shall be discharged at any time upon payment of the balance due on his fine and costs, or upon the expiration of his term of service; his term of service in no event to be greater than one day for each fifty cents of fine and costs; provided, that in no case shall the counties be responsible to the officers for their costs. And in no case shall such convict be hired out for a longer period than two years for failure to pay a fine and costs, and on the expiration of said time, unless by his hire such fine and costs have been sooner paid off, said con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vict shall be finally discharged.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the end of the session creates an imper<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ative public necessity that the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 4, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to provide for temporary capitol buildings for the use of the several departments and branches of the State govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, and to make an appropriation therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Capitol Board, consisting of the Governor, Comptroller, Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, Attorney-General and Commissioner of the General Land Office, be and they are hereby fully authorized and empowered to purchase or rent suitable property and buildings, or to contract with some suitable person or persons for the erection, in the city of Austin, of a suitable building or buildings for the use of the Legislature, Supreme Court, Court of Appeals, Commissioners of Appeals, Treasurer, Comptroller,<pb n="277" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Governor, and Secretary of State, Attorney-General, Adjutant-General, Commissioner of Insurance, Statistics and History, and all the other necessary offices and places of business for the different branches of the State government (except for the Commissioner of the General Land Office); such building or buildings to be fitted up so as to be safe and comfortable for the use of such departments and officers until such time as the new State capitol building now being erected is ready for occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pancy; provided, that if the board shall purchase any building the owner of said building shall execute to the Secretary of State a good bond in the amount of $20,000, to be approved by the Secretary of State, condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned that the said owner, or owners will repurchase the same building or buildings from the State upon the completion of the new capitol building, at the same price paid by the State for the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The said Capitol Board, in arranging for such temporary capi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tol building or buildings, are hereby fully empowered to sell, or to use in any way that they may determine is for the best interest of the State, all the rock and other building material now contained in the ruins of the old capitol building, the Supreme Court building and the Treasurer&#8217;s and Comptroller&#8217;s building, and they are authorized to have all such build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings removed, if they think best to do so, the material, or the proceeds to be used in the construction, repair, or purchase of such temporary capi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tol buildings mentioned in section 1 of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That it such Capitol Board shall purchase property upon which to establish such temporary capitol building or buildings, or any part thereof, before making such purchase they shall cause the title to such property to be carefully examined, and all encumbrances, if any, to be removed from such title; and they shall be fully satisfied that the buildings erected, or to be erected upon such property, can be protected from fires, and can be made reasonably comfortable during all seasons of the year.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the sum of fifty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated, out of any money in the treasury not heretofore appropriated for other purposes, in order to carry out the provisions of this act; and whenever it may be nec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />essary to pay out any of said money, the Capitol Board shall direct the Comptroller to issue his warrants upon the Treasurer for the amounts di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rected to be paid out, and the Treasurer shall pay such warrants upon presentation; and said Capitol Board shall make no contract involving a greater expense to the State than the amount herein appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The facts that the present session of the Legislature is near its close, and that no arrangement has been made for the temporary capi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tol building, or buildings, for the different branches of the State govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, while the new capitol building is being erected, create an impera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring that bills shall be read on three several days, be suspended, and an emergency that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 4, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="278" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend articles 4662, 4664 and 4665, chap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter 1, title 95, of the Revised Statutes, as amended March 24, 1881.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That article 4662 of the Revised Statutes shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 4662. There shall be levied and collected an annual ad valorem State tax of three-tenths of one per centum of the cash value thereof, es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />timated in lawful currency of the United States, on all real property situated, and on all movable property owned, in this State on the first day of January of each and every year, except so much thereof as may be exempted by the Constitution and laws of this State, which cash value shall be estimated in lawful currency of the United States.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That article 4664 of the Revised Statutes shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 4664. There shall be levied and collected from every male person between the ages of twenty-one and sixty years, resident within this State, on the first day of January of each year (Indians not taxed, and persons insane, blind, deaf and dumb, or those who have lost one hand or one foot, excepted), an annual poll tax of one dollar and fifty cents, one dollar for the benefit of free schools and fifty cents for general revenue purposes; provided, that no county shall levy more than twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five cents poll tax for county purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That article 4665 be so amended as to hereafter read as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows:</p>
<p>Article 4665. That there shall be levied on and collected from every person, firm, company or association of persons pursuing any of the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing named occupations, an annual tax, except when herein otherwise provided, on every such occupation or separate establishment as follows:</p>
<p>From every merchant whose purchases amount to one hundred thous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />and dollars annually, one hundred and twenty-five dollars; from every merchant whose annual purchases amount to fifty thousand dollars, sixty dollars; from every merchant whose annual purchases amount to twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five thousand dollars, twenty-five dollars; from every merchant whose annual purchases amount to fifteen thousand dollars, twenty dollars; from every merchant whose annual purchases amount to ten thousand dollars, twelve dollars; from every merchant whose annual purchases amount to five thousand dollars, six dollars; from every merchant whose annual purchases amount to two thousand dollars or less, three dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars; from every commercial traveler, drummer, salesman, or solicitor of trade, by sample or otherwise, an annual occupation tax of thirty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />five dollars, payable in advance; provided, that the tax herein re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to be paid by such commercial traveler, drummer, salesman or solicitor shall be paid to the Comptroller of Public Accounts, whose receipts, under seal, shall be evidence of the payment of such tax; and provided further, that no county, city or town shall levy or collect any occupation tax upon such commercial traveler, drummer, sales<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man or solicitor; provided, that nothing herein contained shall apply to any one soliciting subscriptions for religious, literary or historical books or maps, or to persons soliciting for nurseries, newspapers and gravestones; provided further, that every commercial traveler, drum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mer, salesman or solicitor of trade shall, on demand of the tax col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lector of any county of the State, or of any peace officer of said county,<pb n="279" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>exhibit to such officer the Comptroller&#8217;s receipt above mentioned; and every commercial traveler, drummer, salesman or solicitor of trade who shall fail or refuse to exhibit said receipt to such officer on demand by him, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and fined in a sum not less than twenty-five nor more than one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>A merchant, in the meaning of this act, is any person, firm or associa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of persons engaged in buying and selling goods, wares and mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chandise, of any kind whatever.</p>
<p>From every traveling person selling patent or other medicines, one hundred and seventy-five dollars; and no traveling person shall so sell until said tax is paid; provided, that this tax shall not apply to commer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial travelers, drummers, or salesmen, making sales or soliciting trade for merchants engaged in selling drugs or medicines, who shall be taxed as other commercial drummers.</p>
<p>From every fortune-teller one hundred and seventy-five dollars.</p>
<p>From every clairvoyant or mesmerist who plies his or her vocation for money, five dollars for each and every county in which such vocation is carried on.</p>
<p>From every person, firm or association of persons engaged in discount<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and shaving paper, or engaged in business as money brokers or bank<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers, or dealers in stocks, securities or bills of exchange, or in buying and selling bonds, State or county warrants, or other claims against the State, an annual tax of sixteen dollars in a city or town of not more than two thousand inhabitants; in a city or town of five thousand and not less than two thousand inhabitants, an annual tax of forty dollars; in a city or town of ten thousand and not less than five thousand inhabitants, an an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nual tax of eighty dollars; in a city or town of twenty thousand and not less than ten thousand inhabitants an annual tax of one hundred and twenty dollars; in a city or town of more than twenty thousand inhabi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tants, an annual tax of one hundred and sixty dollars.</p>
<p>From every operator or owner of any daguerrean, photograph, or other such like gallery, by whatever name called, if in any incorporated city or town of less than five thousand inhabitants, six dollars; if more than five thousand inhabitants, fourteen dollars; and if elsewhere, four dollars; and from every person soliciting work for any daguerrean, photograph or such like gallery, or for persons engaged in the business of copying or enlarging pictures or photographs of any character, where such gallery is not situated in, or such business is not in the county in which he so<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />licits such work, seven dollars.</p>
<p>From every auctioneer doing business in a city of ten thousand inhabi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tants or more, an annual tax of forty-five dollars; from every auctioneer in a city or town of five thousand and not more than ten thousand in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />habitants, thirty dollars; from every auctioneer in a city or town of two thousand inhabitants and not more than five thousand, eighteen dollars; from auctioneers in all other towns or villages, twelve dollars.</p>
<p>From every person, firm or association of persons following the occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pation of ship brokers or ship agents, if in a city or town of ten thous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />and inhabitants, or more, twenty dollars; if in a city or town of less than ten thousand inhabitants, seven dollars.</p>
<p>From every keeper of a toll-bridge, an annual tax of seven dollars.</p>
<p>From every person, firm or association of persons selling upon commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion, an annual tax of seven dollars.</p>
<p>From every land agent there shall be collected an annual tax of five dollars.</p>
<pb n="280" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>The term &#8220;land agent&#8221; shall be construed to mean any person, firm or association of persons performing, for compensation, any of the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing services: Purchasing or selling real estate for others; purchasing or selling land certificates for others. But this term &#8220;land agent&#8221; shall not be so construed as to levy tax upon attorneys in addition to the one here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inafter levied.</p>
<p>From every person practicing law and from every conveyancer, five dollars; provided, that attorneys at law shall only pay county occupation tax in the county of his or their residence.</p>
<p>From every physician, surgeon, occulist or medical specialist of any kind, traveling from place to place in the practice of his profession, an annual tax of forty dollars in each county where he may practice his profession.</p>
<p>From every dentist, five dollars.</p>
<p>From every other person, firm or association of persons pursuing the occupation of posting up advertising bills or notices, tacking up adver<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tising cards or notices of tin, wood or other material, printing or letter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing words or pictures on fences or other places, as a means of advertising, the sum of twenty dollars per annum for the State; and in each county in which the occupation may be pursued an annual tax of four dollars; provided, that this clause shall not be so construed as to tax persons ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vertising their own business.</p>
<p>From every person or firm keeping a shooting gallery at which a fee is paid or demanded, an annual tax of sixteen dollars in each county.</p>
<p>For every billiard, bagatelle, pigeon-hole, devil-among-the-tailors, or jenny-lind table, or anything of the kind used for profit, twenty dollars; and any such table used in connection with any drinking saloon or other place of business where intoxicating liquors are sold or given away, or upon which any money or other thing of value is paid, shall be regarded as used for profit.</p>
<p>From every person, firm or association of persons selling or offering for sale the illustrated Police News, Police Gazette, and other illustrated publications of like character, the sum of five hundred dollars in each county in which such sale may be made or offered to be made.</p>
<p>For any person or persons who shall sell pools on horse races, five dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars for each and every day they may so sell said pools.</p>
<p>For every nine or ten pin alley, or any other alley used for profit, by whatever name called, constructed or operated upon the principle of a bowling alley and upon which balls are rolled, without regard to the number of pins used, or whether pins are used or not, or whether the balls are rolled by hand or with a cue, one thousand dollars. Any such alley used in connection with any drinking saloon or any drug store, or with any drug store where intoxicating liquors are sold or given away, or upon which any money or thing of value is paid, shall be regarded as used for profit.</p>
<p>From all persons keeping or using for profit any hobby-horse or flying jenny, or device of that character, with or without name, sixteen dollars for each county wherein the same are kept or used.</p>
<p>From every foot peddler, five dollars in each county where he peddles. For every peddler with one horse or one pair of oxen, the sum or fifteen dollars in each county where he peddles. For every peddler with two horses or two pairs of oxen, thirty dollars in each county in which he may pursue such occupation; provided, nothing herein contained shall be so construed as to include traveling vendors of tin or earthen ware; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="281" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>vided further, that nothing herein contained shall be so construed as to include traveling vendors of literature exclusively religious in character, or traveling vendors of fruit and fruit trees exclusively.</p>
<p>For every theater or dramatic representation from which pay for ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission is demanded or received, two dollars for each day they may per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form, or fifty dollars per quarter; provided, that theatrical or dramatic representations given by performers for instruction only, or entirely for charitable purposes shall not be herein included.</p>
<p>For every circus, where equestrian or acrobatic feats and perform<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ances are exhibited, for which pay for admission is demanded or received, for each performance thereof, fifty dollars, notwithstanding more than one such performance may take place daily.</p>
<p>For every exhibition where acrobatic [feats] are performed for profit, not connected with the circus, ten dollars for each performance.</p>
<p>For every sleight-of-hand performance, or exhibition of legerdemain, ten dollars.</p>
<p>For every fight between men and bulls, or between dogs and bulls, or between bears and dogs, or between bulls and any other animals, five hundred dollars for each performance per year.</p>
<p>For every cock-pit, when kept for profit, or upon which any money or thing of value is bet or paid, twenty-five dollars.</p>
<p>For every menagerie, wax work, or exhibition of any kind, where a separate fee for admission is demanded or received, ten dollars for every day on which fees for such admission are received; provided, that exhi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bitions by associations organized for promotion of art, science, charity, or benevolence, shall be exempt from taxation.</p>
<p>For every concert, where a fee for admission is demanded or received, two dollars; provided, that entertainments when given by the citizens for charitable purposes, or for the support or aid of literary or cemetery asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciations, are excepted.</p>
<p>For every livery or feed stable, thirty cents for each stall, and thirty cents for each hack, buggy or other vehicle; for every hack, buggy or other vehicle let for hire, not connected with a livery Stable, two dollars; for every wagon yard used for profit, not connected with a livery, feed or sale stable, five dollars.</p>
<p>From every life insurance company doing business in this State, an an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nual tax of three hundred dollars; and in every county in which they may do business, seven dollars as county tax.</p>
<p>From every fire, marine or guarantee insurance company doing busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness in this State, an annual tax of two hundred dollars; and in every county in which they may do business, seven dollars as county tax.</p>
<p>The State tax due from insurance companies shall be paid by such companies to the Comptroller of Public Accounts, whose receipt, under seal, shall be evidence of payment of State tax, and the county collector&#8217;s receipt shall be authority to work in any county of this State for which such company has a receipt.</p>
<p>From every person, firm or association of persons dealing in lightning<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rods, an annual tax of thirty-six dollars to the State, and eighteen dollars as county tax to the county in which such business is carried on; upon every person canvassing for the sale of lightning-rods, an annual tax of thirty-six dollars, and eighteen dollars as county tax to each county in which such canvassing is done.</p>
<p>From every person, firm or association of persons following the occupa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of cotton broker, cotton factor or commission merchant, in a city of<pb n="282" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>more than five thousand inhabitants, an annual tax of thirty-five dollars, and in all other cases an annual tax of eighteen dollars; provided, that a merchant who pays an occupation tax as under section 3 of this act shall not be considered as a &#8220;cotton broker.&#8221;</p>
<p>From every pawnbroker, an annual tax of seventy-five dollars.</p>
<p>From every person pursuing the occupation of a cotton buyer, five dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars; provided, that a merchant who pays an occupation tax as herein prescribed shall not be considered as a cotton buyer.</p>
<p>From every person, firm, agency, or association of persons, dealing in sewing machines, an annual tax of fifteen dollars to the State, and seven dollars as county tax in every county where such business may be carried on; and upon every person canvassing for the sale of sewing machines, an annual tax of fifteen dollars to the State, and seven dollars as county tax, in every county where such business may be carried on; provided, that a merchant who pays an occupation tax, as required by this section, shall not be required to pay this special tax for selling sewing machines.</p>
<p>From any person, firm, or association of persons, doing an express bus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iness in this State, an annual tax of five hundred dollars shall be levied and collected, this tax to be paid by such person, firm, or association of persons, doing an express business, to the Comptroller of Public Ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />counts, whose receipt, under seal, shall be issued to the company or com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />panies, certified copies of which shall be evidence of the payment of the State, county and municipal occupation tax.</p>
<p>From every person, firm, or association of persons owning or running any palace, sleeping or dining room cars, on any railroad in this State, there shall be collected an annual tax of fifty cents per mile for each and every mile of any and all railroads in this State over which such cars may run. The tax herein due shall be paid by such person, firm, or asso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ciation of persons, to the Comptroller of Public Accounts, whose receipt under seal shall be issued to the person, company or firm, certified copies of which shall be evidence of the payment of State tax; provided, that nothing herein contained shall authorize the levy of any county or muni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cipal tax upon such person, firm or association of persons.</p>
<p>From every person, firm or association of persons owning or running any railroad cars, steamboats or stage coaches in this State there shall be collected quarterly on the first days of January, April, July and October of each year, a tax of three-fourths of one per centum on steamboats and stage coaches, and one-half of one per centum on railroads upon their gross receipts from all passenger travel within this State, the said gross receipts to be returned under oath by said owner, agent or manager to the Comptroller, and said tax to be collected by the Comptroller under such regulations as he may prescribe; provided, that nothing herein con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained shall authorize the levy of any county or municipal tax upon such person, firm or association of persons.</p>
<p>From every chartered telegraphic company, doing business within this State, there shall be collected one cent for every full-rate message sent by any person within this State to any person within this State, and one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />half that for any message less than a full rate message so sent. This tax to be paid quarterly to the Comptroller, on the sworn statement of the chief manager of said company or companies, or any other officer authorized by said company to make said statement, who shall keep a record of such messages; and the receipts of the Comptroller, under seal, shall be issued to said company or companies, certified copies of which shall be evidence of the payment of the State tax; provided, railroad messages for run<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="283" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ning their trains and for company use shall not be taxed; provided fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ther, that nothing herein contained shall authorize the levy or collection of any county or municipal tax upon such chartered companies for mes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sages sent and messages sent on official business by officers of the United States.</p>
<p>For each telephone company doing business in this State, an annual tax of fifty dollars, and for each county in which they may do business a county tax of ten dollars.</p>
<p>From each gas company, manufacturing gas in towns and cities of ten thousand inhabitants or more, thirty-five dollars; in towns and cities having less than ten thousand inhabitants, twenty dollars. Provided, that the fact that a tax is levied by this article upon bagatelle, pigeon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hole, devil-among-the-tailors, jenny-lind table or any thing of the kind used for profit, and upon any nine or ten-pin alley or other alley used for profit shall not be construed to exempt from the punishment prescribed by law any person who may violate any of the provisions of chapter three of the Penal Code; provided further, that this act shall not be construed to prevent persons or firms of persons who pay an occupation tax under this act for pursuing the occupation of a merchant in a city or town from soliciting trade within the corporation limits of said city or town where they may reside.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Whereas, The various county commissioners&#8217; courts through<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out the State are about to levy taxes for the present year, therefore an emergency exists that so much of this act as relates to the ad valorem and poll rate of taxation shall take effect from and after its passage, and so much as relates to occupation taxes shall take effect July 1, 1882; and an imperative public necessity requires that the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days in each house should be suspended, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 4, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>The foregoing act received a two-thirds vote in both houses.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to ascertain the deficiencies of the several departments of the State government for the year ending February 28, 1882, and for previous years, and amounts due individuals, and to make appropriations to pay the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following sums, or so much thereof as may be necessary, are hereby appropriated out of any money in the State Treasury not other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise appropriated, to pay the following deficiencies in the several depart<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments of the State government for the year ending February 28, 1882, and allowance to individuals named herein, to-wit:</p>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Judiciary Department.</head>
<p>To pay salaries of special judges......................... $913 62</p>
<p>To pay registered claims for costs due sheriffs, clerks and attorneys......................... 166,970 42</p>
<p>For services in attending on the Commissioners of Appeals for the years 1881 and 1882, to be paid in equal pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />portions to the sheriffs of Galveston, Smith and Travis counties......................... 300 00</p>
<pb n="284" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>For purchase and rebinding of law books for Supreme Court library......................... $1,200 00</p>
<p>To pay for removing Supreme Court library......................... 61 50</p>
<p>To pay librarian for extra work of removal......................... 25 00</p>
<p>To pay for purchase of safe......................... 200 00</p>
<p>To pay for purchase of matting for Supreme Court build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing,......................... 151 00</p>
<p>For furniture for Supreme Court rooms......................... 62 50</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">State Department.</head>
<p>For rent of book room from November 15, 1881, to Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 28, 1882, at $20 per month......................... 70 00</p>
<p>To pay Gammel Bros. for recovering damaged books from ruins of capitol......................... 80 00</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Adjutant-General&#8217;s Office.</head>
<p>To pay for removing and guarding records and furniture saved from the burning of the capitol......................... 67 75</p>
<p>For supplying tables, shelving and other office furniture.. 257 00</p>
<p>For repairs on safe......................... 25 00</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Legislative.</head>
<p>To pay Will Lambert for indexing journals of House of Representatives for regular session of Seventeenth Legislature......................... 150 00</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Penitentiaries.</head>
<p>For conveying prisoners to penitentiaries, to be credited on claims of the State against the sheriffs entitled to the same......................... 76,215 75</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Quarantine.</head>
<p>To pay quarantine claims......................... 2,421 85</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Executive.</head>
<p>For payment of rewards......................... 6,308 92</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Fish Commissioner.</head>
<p>To pay the widow of J. H. Dinkins his salary as &#8220;Fish Commissioner&#8221; from April 1, 1881, to December 18, 1881, 8 months and 18 days, at $1500 per annum......................... 1,075 00</p>
<p>To pay salary of Fish Commissioner R. R. Robertson from December 21, 1881, to February 28, 1882, at $1500 per annum......................... 262 50</p>
</div3>
<pb n="285" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Pensions.</head>
<p>To pay pensions to Texas veterans, under special acts for year 1881......................... $1,200 00</p>
<p>To pay members of Veteran Board their accounts, to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the Governor......................... 1,500 00</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the close of the session, and the fact that many of these claims are past due and the several departments seri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ously hindered for want of an appropriation to pay others of them, cre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ates an emergency and an imperative public necessity that the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days be sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 4, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from its passage.</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution providing for an election to be held for the location of a branch of the University, for the instruction of the colored youths of the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, The Constitution of the State provides that there shall be a branch of the University of Texas established for the instruction of the colored youths of the State, and that the same shall be located by a vote of the people:</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it Resolved [by the Legislature of the State of Texas,] That the Governor is hereby instructed to issue his proclamation order<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing an election to be held throughout the State, upon the day of the next general election, to-wit, on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in November, 1882, for the location of a branch of the State University, for the instruction of colored youth; and returns of said election to be made in the manner prescribed by the general election law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All localities put in nomination for the location of the colored branch of the State University shall be forwarded to the Governor at least forty days before the holding of said election, and the Governor shall embrace in his proclamation ordering said election the names of said localities; provided, that any citizen may vote for any locality not named in said proclamation.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The locality receiving the largest number of votes shall be declared selected as the location of the branch of the University for the instruction of the colored youth of the State, and said institution shall be located at such place.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The near approach of the end of the session creates an im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perative public necessity that the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 5, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="286" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act making appropriations for support of the State government for the period of time beginning March 1, 1882, and end<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing February 28, 1883.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following sums, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and they are hereby appropriated one of any moneys in the treasury not otherwise appropriated for the support of the State government, for the period of time beginning March 1, 1882, and ending February 28, 1883:</p>
<p>For completing work at and buying machinery for the Rusk penitentiary, one hundred thousand dollars......................... $100,000 00</p>
<p>For completing work at and buying machinery for the Huntsville penitentiary, fifty thousand dollars......................... 50,000 00</p>
<p>To enable the Penitentiary Board to carry on and pay the expenses of the penitentiary, should the State resume control of same, but the appropriation to be expended in no other event, forty thousand dollars......................... 40,000 00</p>
<p>For settling with Messrs. Cunningham and Ellis, peniten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tiary lessees, such amount, as may be due them upon ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />justment at the termination of their present lease, forty thousand dollars......................... 40,000 00</p>
<p>For library at Huntsville penitentiary, the unexpended ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriation made for 1881, five hundred dollars......................... 500 00</p>
<p>For three additional clerks in Treasurer&#8217;s office, to attend to the sale, etc., of school, University and asylum lands, one clerk to receive per year twelve hundred dollars......................... 1200 00</p>
<p>one clerk to receive per year, one thousand dollars......................... 1000 00</p>
<p>one clerk to receive per year, nine hundred dollars......................... 900 00</p>
<p>For making fire-proof ceiling in General Land Office, six thousand dollars......................... 6,000 00</p>
<p>For the purchase of such legal elementary works as may be necessary, to be selected by the judges of the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of Appeals, five hundred dollars......................... 500 00</p>
<p>For books, furniture and safe for the Attorney-General&#8217;s office, to supply place of those lost by recent fires, five hundred dollars......................... 500 00</p>
<p>To pay Tom Murrah, agent for owner, for rent of rooms Nos. 6 and 8, second floor Brueggerhoff building, to April 30, 1882, occupied by Adjutant-General, one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and six dollars sixty-six and two-thirds cents......................... $106 66&#8532;</p>
<p>And for room No. 11, same floor; occupied same length of time by Capitol Commissioners, fifty three dollars and thirty- three and one-third cents......................... 53 33&#8531;</p>
<p>And for store-room in Krohn building, same time, occupied by Secretary of State, one hundred and six dollars and sixty-six and two-thirds cents......................... 106 66&#8532;</p>
<p>Two hundred and sixty-six dollars and sixty-six and two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds cents......................... 266 66&#8532;</p>
<p>For additional room rent for books for Secretary of State, sixty dollars......................... 60 00</p>
<p>For purchase of iron safe, Secretary of State&#8217;s office, three hundred dollars......................... 300 00</p>
<p>For purchase of furniture, Secretary of State&#8217;s office, two hundred and fifty dollars......................... 250 00</p>
<pb n="287" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>For salary of Fish Commissioner, fifteen hundred dollars.. $1,500 00</p>
<p>For building a disinfecting warehouse at Galveston for quarantine purposes, to be expended by State Health Offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cer, and the warehouse to remain under his control, six<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teen thousand dollars. 16,000 00</p>
<p>provided, the citizens of Galveston shall contribute an additional amount sufficient to erect such warehouse as in the judgment of the Health Officer will subserve the purpose intended, otherwise the sixteen thousand dollars here appropriated shall not be expended.</p>
<p>For construction and repairs of quarantine stations at Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston, Brazos Santiago, Aransas Pass, Pass Cavallo, Orange, Sabine Pass, and such other points as may be found necessary, the unexpended balance of last year&#8217;s appropriation for same purpose, four thousand dollars.. 4,000 00</p>
<p>For purchasing provisions and supplies for Lunatic Asylum in addition to the appropriation for the year ending Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary 28, 1883, six thousand five hundred dollars......................... 6,500 00</p>
<p>To C. F. Millett, for fixing up Senate chamber, and for furniture for same, thirteen hundred and eighty-nine dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars and sixty-six cents......................... 1,389 66</p>
<p>To Travis Lodge 1005, Knights of Honor, and Lone Star Lodge No. 1, Ancient Order of United Workmen, for rent of Senate chamber, and repairs, from March 27 to May 10, 1882, seven hundred and thirty-seven dollars and fifty cents......................... 737 50</p>
<p>For completing improvements at Rusk penitentiary, water supply, drainage and heating, it being the unexpended balance of the appropriation for same purpose, made in 1881, twenty-seven thousand dollars......................... $27,000 00</p>
<p>For the payment of teachers to be employed by the State board of education for the purpose of teaching the sum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mer normal schools, the sum of three thousand dollars.. 3,000 00</p>
<p>For paying pensions to Texas veterans under special acts, twelve hundred dollars......................... 1,200 00</p>
<p>For roofing the uncovered galleries of the new building of the blind asylum, and for furnishing blinds for windows, nineteen hundred and forty-five dollars......................... 1,945 00</p>
<p>To provide efficient sewerage for the lunatic asylum, State University, State Capitol, and institute for the blind, forty-five thousand dollars......................... 45,000 00</p>
<p>To purchase hot-air apparatus for heating the institute for the blind, to be expended under direction of board of managers and superintendent, twenty-five hundred dollars 2,500 00</p>
<p>For additional porter hire for Supreme Court, one hundred and eighty dollars......................... 180 00</p>
<p>For furniture for Supreme Court room and library, one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and twenty-five dollars......................... 125 00</p>
<p>For watchman of such building or buildings as may be pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for the State government, said watchman to be un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der direction of the superintendent of public build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings and grounds, who shall have charge of such building or buildings, one hundred and eighty dollars......................... 180 00</p>
<p>To C. F. Millett for rent of Representative Hall from first of April to ninth of May, 1882, inclusive......................... 800 00</p>
<pb n="288" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>To C. F. Millett for fitting up Opera House, and for furni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture constructed, two thousand three hundred and four<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teen dollars and six and two-third cents......................... $2,314 06&#8532;</p>
<p>For purchase of safe for Department of Insurance, Statis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tics and History, two hundred dollars......................... 200 00</p>
<p>For payment of clerical assistance in compiling statistics to be taken out of the unexpended balance of appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for dissemination of statistics made by act approved April 1, 1881, seven hundred and fifty dollars......................... 750 00</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas, the near approach of the close of this session of the Legislature and the fact that these appropriations are made neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary by the recent disastrous fire which destroyed much public property, and because the public institutions here provided for are needed at once for the public good, creates an imperative public necessity and emergency that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended and that the act take immediate effect and it is so en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />acted that said rule be suspended and that this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 5, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to further provide for the supervision and management of the construction of the new State Capitol building and to make an appropriation therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Capitol building Commissioners shall be required to give their constant supervision to the construction of the new State capitol build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, and to perform all duties required of them by the contract existing between the State of Texas and the contractors.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. It shall be the duty of the commissioners to employ compe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tent draughtsmen who, in the presence of the commissioner, shall make tracings from the original plans of the capitol buildings for the use of the contractors, which tracings shall be approved in writing by the design<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing architect and the commissioners. The cost of said tracings shall be paid upon the certificate of the commissioners, with the approval of the Governor, out of any money in the treasury not otherwise appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The commissioners shall purchase such necessary books and stationery as will be required in the full performance of their duties. They shall also purchase a suitable fire-proof safe, in which all records and samples of materials shall be kept. They shall also be authorized, when it may be necessary, to rent a suitable room, or rooms, for their office. To carry out the provisions of this section, the sum of five hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated out of any money in the treasury not otherwise appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. There shall be appointed by the Governor, Comptroller, State Treasurer, Attorney-General and Commissioner of the General Land Office, acting as a board, a secretary, who shall be a competant account<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ant, who, before entering upon the duties of his office, shall enter into bond, with two or more good securities, in the sum of ten thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars, conditioned for the faithful performance of his duties under this act, payable to the State of Texas, to be approved by the Governor and<pb n="289" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>filed in the office of the Comptroller, and shall also take and subscribe the following oath, to be endorsed on said bond, to be administered by any one authorized to administer oaths, to-wit: &#8220;I, A. B., do solemnly swear that I will not, directly or indirectly, be interested or concerned with any contractor or contractors for the erection of the State capitol, or any por<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion thereof, or in the proceeds or profits growing out of the same, or any work or labor done thereon, or material furnished in the erection of the same, or any part thereof, during the term for which I am appointed, so help me God.&#8221; And, should the said officer offend against the true in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tent and meaning of this oath, he shall, upon indictment and conviction, suffer all the pains and penalties of perjury; and in case of a violation of the conditions of the bond provided for, he shall be liable to an action thereon in the district court of Travis county and a judgment for such damages as may be awarded against the obligors thereto by the reason of the failure of the principal.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. It shall be the duty of said secretary, as soon as he shall have qualified as provided for in the foregoing section, to keep a full record of all the proceedings of said commissioners. He shall be custodian of all the papers and samples of material, and shall exam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ine all the accounts that the contractors are required by the contract to exhibit to the State. He shall carry on all correspondence, in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cluding that between the contractors and commissioners, and shall keep a true and correct copy of the same. He shall also be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to keep an accurate account of all material delivered upon the capitol grounds, and shall accompany the commissioners in their exami<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation of the same, and make a written description in detail of the material examined by the commissioners and record the same in a well bound book. He shall be required to furnish the contractors with a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tified statement showing the materials that the commissioners deem to be in accordance with the specifications and contract, and to inform the contractors in writing of any material not suitable for the uses and pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses intended and required by the contract. He shall perform such other duties as may be required of him by the commissioners for the purpose of strictly and fully enforcing all the provisions of the plans, specifications and contract between the State and the contractors. He shall prepare for and furnish to each regular session of the Legislature a printed report and history of the proceedings and work of the commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners in every particular. The papers, accounts and books of said sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />retary shall at all times be open to the inspection of any member of the Legislature, the heads of departments and the commissioners.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The superintendent of construction shall be required to give a bond, conditioned in the same terms, payable to the State of Texas, and for the same amount as required of the secretary in this act. He shall also take and subscribe the same oath as required of the secretary by this act. He shall at all times act under the directions of and be subject to the control of the commissioners. The superintendent shall devote his whole time to the performance of his duties hereunder, and shall, during the time of his employment hereunder, take no work nor employment from other persons.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The superintendent of construction shall receive an annual salary of twenty-five hundred dollars, the commissioners shall receive a like salary of eighteen hundred dollars each, and the secretary a like salary of eighteen hundred dollars, to be paid only while the work of con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structing the capitol is in progress.</p>
<pb n="290" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 8. The sum of twelve thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated for the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of carrying out the objects of this bill.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. All laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act are hereby repealed; provided, this act shall not be construed to relieve any one of any duty imposed by the act to provide for building the new State capitol, approved April 18, 1879.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Whereas, the progress of this important work now requires constant attention, and there is an imperative public necessity that an ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curate record of the same be kept, and that the State may not be the cause of any delay in the constructing and completion of the capitol building, an emergency is created requiring the constitutional rule which requires a bill to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 5, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to provide for the publication and binding of one thousand copies of the Revised Statutes, Penal Code, and Code of Criminal Procedure of the State of Texas, with the Constitutions and appendix thereto, and to make an appropriation therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Secretary of State be and he is hereby authorized to have print<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed and bound one thousand copies of the Revised Statutes, Penal Code, and Code of Criminal Procedure of the State of Texas, with the Constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions and appendix thereto; provided, that the same be done in a good and workmanlike manner, and of material equal to the fifty-fourth vol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ume of Texas Reports, and at a price not to exceed two dollars per copy.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the sum of two thousand dollars be and is hereby ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated, out of any moneys in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, to defray the expenses of such publication.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The fact that the first edition of the Revised Statutes has been destroyed by fire in the burning of the State capitol, creates an im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perative public necessity and an emergency requiring the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, be suspended, the same is hereby suspended, and that this act take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 5, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of persons, firms or associa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of persons who have procured license and complied with the law authorizing them to pursue the occupation of liquor dealers where they have been, or may be, prevented from pursuing such occupation on account of the adoption of local option, and to make an appropriation therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in all cases where, under the acts of the Seventeenth Legislature,<pb n="291" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>approved March 11, 1881, and April 4, 1881, any person, firm or associ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ation of persons have procured a license authorizing them to pursue the occupation of liquor dealers, and before the expiration of the time for which such license was granted, they have been or shall be prevented from pursuing such occupation by the adoption of local option in any county, justice&#8217;s precinct, town or city, a proportionate amount of the taxes paid by them for the unexpired time of such license shall be refunded to them.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any person entitled to the benefit of this act may apply to the commissioners&#8217; court of the county where such license was issued for relief, and upon satisfactory proof before said court, an order shall be made for his or their relief, and a certified copy of said order by the clerk to the applicant for relief, stating amounts of State, county and city taxes due, shall be sufficient voucher to the Comptroller, county and city treasurer, to refund the amount certified to be due by virtue of said order.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the sum of five thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the State Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Whereas, Many persons in this State are entitled to have money refunded to them under the provisions of this act, and will be compelled to do without the amounts to which they are entitled for three months unless this act takes effect from passage; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, The early adjournment of this session renders it impossible to read this bill on three several days, therefore an emergency exists, and an imperative public necessity requires that the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 5, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to release certain inhabitants of Plano, county of Collin, from the payment of taxes assessed and now due for the year A. D. 1881, in consequence of a great public calamity.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, On the night of the twenty-seventh day of August, 1881, there occurred in the village of Plano, in Collin county, State of Texas, a terrible public calamity, the same being a sweeping and destructive con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />flagration, such as seldom occurred; within a few short hours every busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness house in the town, save one, and nine-tenths of the dwelling houses of said town succumbed to the fury of the flames, and the inhabitants thereof, almost in the twinkling of an eye, were robbed by the fiery ele<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of every vestige of property, household goods and clothing, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prived of their habitations and left with only the consolation of their good names; and</p>
<p>Whereas, The deluge of fire, in proportion to the Size of the visitation, was even more terrible than that which razed to the ground Chicago, the great metropolis of the northwest, and was almost as disastrous in the effects of its ravages as the showers of flame and lava that overwhelmed<pb n="292" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the cities of Herculaneum and Pompeii, and it is the duty of all govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments to alleviate the distress of its citizens, occasioned by act of Provi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence and otherwise than by sloth; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, (two-thirds of each house, by a vote, concurring therein), That the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing named inhabitants of said county, to-wit, in the town of Plano, Collin county, the same being sufferers from the conflagration, be and they are hereby released from the payment of the several sums named, the same being the amount of State and county taxes assessed against them and now due for the year A. D. 1881, to-wit:</p>
<p>G. F. Flowers......................... $ 2 50</p>
<p>L. Butler......................... 40 90</p>
<p>Harvey Graham......................... 2 50</p>
<p>Floyd Bros. &#38; Moore......................... 18 75</p>
<p>C. M. Rice......................... 22 60</p>
<p>H. S. Murray......................... 37 90</p>
<p>J. M. Skelton &#38; Co.......................... 3 75</p>
<p>J. M. Skelton......................... 3 00</p>
<p>W. S. Skelton......................... 20 15</p>
<p>F. M. Bowen......................... $20 50</p>
<p>L. W. Oglesby......................... 46 62</p>
<p>L. W. Oglesby, for M. M. O.......................... 13 50</p>
<p>L. W. Oglesby, for Gaston &#38; Thomas......................... 15 75</p>
<p>C. C. Dewey......................... 6 55</p>
<p>Chaddict &#38; Williams......................... 41 25</p>
<p>D. O. Williams......................... 12 18</p>
<p>B. F. Word......................... 2 40</p>
<p>J. T. Kendrick......................... 28 68</p>
<p>W. A. Honaker......................... 28 75</p>
<p>Mrs. Amanda Hays......................... &#8212;</p>
<p>L. N. Housewright......................... 37 55</p>
<p>W. B. Blaylock......................... 23 13</p>
<p>Fred. Schemeffing......................... 20 73</p>
<p>Livingston &#38; Co.......................... 17 65</p>
<p>C. J. E. Kellner......................... 26 13</p>
<p>W. A. Florence......................... 4 98</p>
<p>B. B. Fowler......................... 14 88</p>
<p>W. L. Maroney......................... 33 33</p>
<p>Plano Lodge, F. A. M.......................... 6 00</p>
<p>N. A. Moore......................... 3 55</p>
<p>J. M. Gee......................... 7 00</p>
<p>H. B. Baldridge......................... 4 72</p>
<p>M. M. Fagan......................... 14 13</p>
<p>John B. Kelper......................... 4 78</p>
<p>John Hardeman......................... 3 75</p>
<p>John T. Martin......................... 14 58</p>
<p>John Alexander......................... 5 63</p>
<p>Lona Forman......................... 11 20</p>
<p>Rogers &#38; Harrington......................... 4 50</p>
<p>Luke Parmer......................... 7 50</p>
<p>J. O. Flock......................... 23 44</p>
<p>F. J. Vance......................... 16 74</p>
<p>Chas. Lamm......................... 27 55</p>
<pb n="293" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Lovelace &#38; Hudson......................... $46 63</p>
<p>Andrew Wetzel......................... 19 53</p>
<p>Mrs. L. M. Dewey......................... 8 85</p>
<p>W. H. Chaddict......................... 12 78</p>
<p>R. T. Shelton......................... 4 60</p>
<p>Kendrick, Oston &#38; Hucker......................... 133 28</p>
<p>Kendrick &#38; Oston......................... 24 00</p>
<p>John Hayes......................... 3 40</p>
<p>Chaddict &#38; Sherwood......................... 12 50</p>
<p>R. P. Coffer......................... 7 75</p>
<p>W. B. Blalock &#38; Bro......................... 18 75</p>
<p>Mrs. P. R. Rudy......................... 7 88</p>
<p>J. R. Kepler......................... 14 87</p>
<p>S. B. Chamberlain......................... 9 55</p>
<p>W. S. Forman &#38; Bro......................... 16 45</p>
<p>J. P. Coffey......................... 18 78</p>
<p>Plano Lodge, No. 114......................... 1 50</p>
<p>Fred. Metzer......................... 5 58</p>
<p>Mrs. S. A. Lyles......................... 1 12</p>
<p>John Bell......................... 1 50</p>
<p>A. Y. Lewis......................... 8 80</p>
<p>John A. Mormon......................... 82 55</p>
<p>H. C. Overaker......................... 33 18</p>
<p>J. S. Chaddict......................... 4 75</p>
<p>D. R. McCulloch......................... 19 15</p>
<p>W. Byrd......................... 1 12</p>
<p>C. N. Yancey......................... 25 08</p>
<p>S. L. Harrington......................... 71 70</p>
<p>And that the several sums of taxes against said persons respectively be and the same are hereby remitted.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Comptroller of Public Accounts of this State and the county treasurer and commissioners&#8217; court of Collin county be, and they are hereby authorized and required, to credit the tax collector of Collin county with the several sums herein and hereby released; the said Comptroller to credit him with the said several amounts of State tax, and said treasurer and commissioner&#8217;s court to credit him with the several amounts of county tax, in his settlement with them for taxes collected by him for the year 1881, by deducting the same from the aggregate of the tax lists now in his hands for collection for the said year; and said tax collector be and he is hereby released from collecting said several sums, or any part thereof, from the said several persons hereby relieved; and if the said tax, or any part of the same, shall have been collected by the said collector of taxes for Collin county, then and in that case the said collector is hereby required to refund said amounts of the said tax to the persons having paid the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. An imperative necessity and emergency exists which requires the immediate passage and taking effect of this act, as the tax collector is required by law to collect said several sums of taxes by seizure and levy from the said persons if the same be not paid by the first day of &#8212;, 1882, and the several inhabitants may not, in consequence there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of, be benefited by this act, as intended; therefore, be it enacted that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 6, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="294" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Secretary of State to pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase for the use of the State, the Texas Reports, and to contract for the relinquishment of the copyright of said reports with persons own<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the same, and to prevent the copyrighting of future volumes of said reports to the exclusion of the State, and to make an appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Secretary of the State of Texas be and he is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to purchase for the use of the State a sufficient number of the volumes of the Texas Reports, including Dallam&#8217;s Decisions, now in print, which, together with those now on hand and belonging to the State, will make complete sets of three hundred volumes of each of the reports for which there are no plates in existence, and two hundred volumes each of those for which plates are in existence.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the character of work, binding, style of type, weight and quality of paper, shall be as in volume fifty-two of the Texas Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ports, except volumes four to fourteen inclusive, which may be Sayles edition.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Secretary of State be and he is hereby authorized to pay not exceeding four dollars per volume for each of said reports; provided, that reports from plates of the thirty volumes now in existence shall not cost exceeding three dollars per volume, and the Secretary of State shall not purchase exceeding two hundred copies of said volumes; and that before making said contract, the Secretary be and he is hereby authorized to require that said publishing house file in his office a relin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quishment to the State of Texas of the copyright on each volume of said reports, to take effect three years after the date of such contract, so that thereafter no person shall have the exclusive copyright of said reports, but the right to print, publish and sell the same shall thereafter be free to all; and that no person shall hereafter be authorized to take out a copyright to any of said reports, or to any Texas Reports hereafter to be issued, except for the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That said reports shall be delivered by said publishing house within three years after the making of said contract, in such quantities and at such times as may be required by the Secretary of State, and the same shall be paid for when delivered, out of any funds in the treasury not otherwise appropriated. The sum of thirty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated for the purpose of paying for said reports; provided, that the publisher contract with the Secretary of State that after the execution of the contract mentioned, he will, for all time to come, supply all purchasers with the reports at a sum not exceeding four dollars per volume.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. In order to carry into effect the provisions of this act, and to secure the State in its faithful execution, the Secretary of State is author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to require of said publishing house the execution and filing in his office of a bond, payable to the State, in the sum of fifteen thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars, with two or more good and sufficient securities, conditioned for the faithful performance of the conditions of his contract under this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. There being no complete set of Texas Reports now on hand in the office of the Secretary of State, and there being a demand therefor, creates an emergency that this act take effect and in force from and after its passage; and the fact that the session of the Legislure is rap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="295" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>idly drawing to a close, and the necessity that some measure be provided to supply the State with reports, creates an imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house be suspended, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 6, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute><pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />An act to prohibit railroad companies, their offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers, agents and employees from making excessive charges for carrying and transporting freight, goods, wares and merchandise, and to require said companies, their officers, agents and employees to deliver freight, goods, wares and merchandise on the payment of the freight charges due as shown by the bill of lading, and provide penalties for the viola<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of this act.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be unlawful for any railroad company in this State, its officers, agents or employees, to charge and collect, or to endeavor to charge and collect, from the owner, agent or consignee of any freight, goods, wares and merchandise, of any kind or character whatever, a greater sum for transporting said freight, goods, wares and merchandise than is specified in the bill of lading.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any railroad company, its officers, agents or employees having possession of any goods, wares and merchandise, of any kind or character whatever, shall deliver the same to the owner, his agent or con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signee, upon payment of the freight charges as shown by the bill of lad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That any railroad company, its officers, agents or employees that shall refuse to deliver to the owner, agent or consignee, any freight, goods, wares and merchandise, of any kind or character whatever, upon the payment, or tender of payment, of the freight charges due as shown by the bill of lading, the said railroad company shall be liable in dam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ages to the owner of said freight, goods, wares or merchandise, to an amount equal to the amount of the freight charges for every day said freight, goods, wares and merchandise is held after payment, or tender of payment, of the charges due as shown by the bill of lading, to be recov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ered in any court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 6, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="296" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend section eight of an act to amend the caption and sections one, two, three, four, five, six, seven and eight of an act entitled &#8220;An act to provide for the sale of alternate sections of lands in organized counties, as surveyed by railroad companies and other works of internal improvements, and set apart for the benefit of the common school fund; to provide for the investment of the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeds, and to repeal all laws in conflict therewith,&#8221; approved July 8, 1879, and to provide for the sale of such land in unorganized counties.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section 8 of the above entitled act, approved April 6, 1881, be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 8. That so soon as the application above named has been re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived by the surveyor, the applicant shall execute his obligation or prom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />issory note for the balance of the appraised value of the land he desires to purchase, agreeing and stipulating to pay to the Governor of the State of Texas, and his successors in office, on the first day of January of each year, one-twentieth of the amount of his obligation or promissory note, with eight per cent interest on the full amount of the principal unpaid at the date of each payment of interest, giving in said obligation such de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scription of the land purchased as is contained in his application; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that the purchaser may have the privilege of paying the entire amount of the appraised value of said land at the date of purchase, or such amount of principal and interest as may be due at any time subse<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quent to the execution of his obligation or promissory note; and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided further, that any payment of principal may be deferred for one or more years except the first one-twentieth; but all payments of both principal and interest must be paid inside of twenty years, and all inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est must be paid annually on or before the first day of March of each day [year]. When any land sold under the provisions of this act shall be timbered land, no person shall have the right to cut and remove any of the timber therefrom until the purchase money has been paid in full; and no pine timbered land shall be sold for less than five dollars per acre; and so much of any laws now in force as authorize the sale of pine timbered lands for less than five dollars per acre, is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the close of the present session of the Legislature creates an imperative public necessity and an emergency that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 6, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution granting leave of absence to the Hon. J. D. McAdoo, County Judge of Washington county, and the Hon. J. H. Davis, County Judge of Franklin county, and the Hon. John C. Robertson, Judge of the Seventh Judicial District, and the Hon. William Charlton, County Judge of Kaufman county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Hon. J. D. McAdoo, County Judge of Washington county, and<pb n="297" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the Hon. J. H. Davis, County Judge of Franklin county, and the Hon. John C. Robertson, Judge of the Seventh Judicial District, and the Hon. William Charlton, County Judge of Kaufman county, be and they are hereby granted leave of absence from the State of Texas from the date of the passage of this joint resolution until the first day of September, A. D. 1882.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The precarious state of the heath of the said judges, and the importance that they receive the benefits of this joint resolution at once, creates an imperative public necessity justifying the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring this joint resolution to be read on three several days, and said rule is suspended; and an emergency exists that this resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>May 5, 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
<p>The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proval on the fifth day of May, 1882, and was not signed by him nor returned to the house in which it originated with his objections thereto within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.</p>
<closer>
<signed>(Signed) T. H. BOWMAN, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to supply the deficiency for the support and maintenance of the Prairie View Normal Institute, and to pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase library, wagon, mules and cows, and to pay for repairs heretofore made, and for damages to said institute caused by the late storm, and to make an appropriation therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of four thousand, five hundred and thirty-seven dollars and thirty-two cents be appropriated out of any moneys in the State treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ury, not otherwise appropriated, for the support and maintenance of the Prairie View Normal Institute for the year ending August 31, 1882; the sum of six thousand dollars for the year ending August 31, 1883, same being the balance of the appropriation unpaid, heretofore made out of the University fund, and being in lieu thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the sum of two thousand dollars be appropriated out of any moneys in the State treasury, not otherwise appropriated, to pay for library, wagon and mules, and for repairs to the said building of said in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute that existed prior to the late storm, and that this appropriation is in lieu of an appropriation heretofore made for the same purpose by act approved April 1, 1881.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That, the sum of twelve hundred dollars be appropriated out of any moneys in the State Treasury, not otherwise appropriated, to pay for repairs of said institute for damages sustained by the late storm, and the further sum of one hundred and fifty dollars, for the purchase of milch cows for the use of the institution, is hereby appropriated out of any money in the treasury not otherwise appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The several sums herein appropriated may be drawn by war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant of the Comptroller on the treasury, on proper vouchers, approved by the directors of said institution.</p>
<pb n="298" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 5. The fact that said institute is without the means requisite for its maintenance and support for the present session, and without the funds to pay for said repairs, creates an imperative public necessity that the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days prior to their passage be suspended, and an emergency exists that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>May 3, 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
<p>The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proval on the third day of May, A. D. 1882, and was not signed by him, nor returned to the house in which it originated with his objections thereto within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.</p>
<closer>
<signed>(Signed) T. H. BOWMAN, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to apportion the State of Texas into con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gressional districts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That until otherwise provided by law the State of Texas shall be apportioned into the following congressional districts, each of which shall be entitled to elect one member to the Congress of the United States.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The following counties shall compose the first district, to-wit: Harris, Chambers, Liberty, Jefferson, Orange, Hardin, Waller, Mont<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gomery, Grimes, Walker, Polk, Tyler, Jasper, Newton, San Jacinto, Brazos, Madison, Trinity and Angelina.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The following counties shall compose the second district, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: Robertson, Leon, Houston, San Augustine, Sabine, Freestone, An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />derson, Cherokeee, Nacogdoches and Henderson.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The following counties shall compose the third district, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: Panola, Harrison, Rusk, Gregg, Smith, Wood, VanZandt, Upshur, Camp, Hunt, Shelby and Rains.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The following counties shall compose the fourth district, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: Cass, Marion, Bowie, Red River, Morris, Titus, Franklin, Lamar, Delta, Fannin and Hopkins.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The following counties shall compose the fifth district, to-wit: Grayson, Collin, Cooke, Denton, Wise, Montague, Clay, Rockwall, Wichita, Wilbarger, Archer and Baylor.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The following counties shall compose the sixth district, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: Ellis, Kaufman, Dallas, Tarrant, Hill, Johnson and Bosque.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The following counties shall compose the seventh district, to-wit: Galveston, Brazoria, Fort Bend, Wharton, Matagorda, Jackson, Calhoun, Victoria, Goliad, Refugio, Bee, San Patricio, Nueces, Duval, Cameron, Hidalgo, Starr, Zapata, Encinal, Webb, McMullen, LaSalle, Dimmit, Aransas, Maverick, Zavalla, DeWitt and Frio.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The following counties shall compose the eighth district, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: Austin, Lee, Fayette, Colorado, Lavaca, Gonzales, Caldwell, Hays, Guadalupe, Wilson, Karnes, Live Oak and Atascosa.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The following counties shall compose the ninth district, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: Washington, Burleson, Milam, Bell, Falls, McLennan, Limestone and Navarro.</p>
<pb n="299" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 11. The following counties shall compose the tenth district, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wit: Travis, Comal, Blanco, Bexar, Medina, Bandera, Uvalde, Kinney, Edwards, Kerr, Kendall, Gillespie, Kimble, Burnet, Llano, Mason, Me<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nard, Lampasas, McCulloch, Concho, Coleman, Runnels, Bastrop, Wil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liamson, Crockett and San Saba.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. The following counties shall compose the eleventh district, to-wit: Parker, Hood, Somervell, Coryell, Hamilton, Brown, Comanche, Erath, Eastland, Palo Pinto, Stephens, Jack, Young, Throckmorton, Shackleford, Callahan, Taylor, Jones, Haskell, Knox, Nolan, Mitchell, Howard, Martin, Andrews, Gaines, Dawson, Borden, Scurry, Fisher, Stonewall, Kent, Garza, Lynn, Terry, Yoakum, Cochran, Hockley, Lub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bock, Crosby, Dickens, King, Cottle, Motley, Floyd, Hale, Lamb, Bailey, Tom Green, Pecos, Presidio, Childress, Swisher, Deaf Smith, Donley, Gray, Oldham, Hutchinson, Lipscomb, Sherman, Hall, Castro, Randall, Collingsworth, Carson, Hartley, Roberts, Ochiltree, Dallam, Greer, Bris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />coe, Parmer, Armstrong, Wheeler, Potter, Moore, Hemphill, Hardeman, Hansford and El Paso.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>April 29, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
<p>The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proval on the twenty-ninth day of April, A. D. 1882, and was not signed by him, nor returned to the house in which it originated with his objec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions thereto, within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />upon became a law without his signature.</p>
<closer>
<signed>(Signed) T. H. BOWMAN, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to suspend the collection of taxes due in the organized counties from the year 1871 to 1876, inclusive.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the list of lands furnished by the Comptroller to collectors upon taxes assessed from the year 1871 to 1876 were compiled from old and inaccurate records; and, whereas, the taxes have been paid on many of these lands by the owners in good faith, who, through ignorance, have rendered the name of the original grantee incorrectly; and, whereas, if relief be not had from these forced sales by legislative action, owners who have paid their taxes in good faith will be forced to expensive liti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gation to remove clouds from their titles; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of Public Accounts be, and he is hereby required, to suspend further collection of taxes apparently due in the organized counties from the years 1871 to 1876, inclusive, until accurate lists of taxes for said years can be furnished the county collectors.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that about forty counties have been furnished their lists and are proceeding to collect this tax, creates an imperative public necessity justifying the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days, and said rule is suspended; and an emergency exists that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>May 16, 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="300" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for supplying the public build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings and grounds of the State with water, and to make an appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section. 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas; That the Governor of said State, the presidents of each of the boards of managers or trustees of the lunatic, deaf and dumb, and blind asylums, the two commissioners for the building of the capitol, and the president of the board of regents of the State University, be and they are hereby fully empowered and authorized to contract, subject to the terms and conditions hereinafter stated, with responsible parties, for supplying the lunatic, deaf and dumb, and blind asylums, the Governor&#8217;s mansion, the General Land Office, and the State cemetery, with water, and also for sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plying the new capitol and university buildings, and grounds belonging thereto, as soon as these buildings are completed, or a necessity for water thereat arises.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The contract hereby authorized to be made shall not extend for a longer period than ten years from the date of its execution.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the contractors shall guarantee not less than four effec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tive fire streams, one hundred feet high, at the same time at each of said asylums, and shall further guarantee the mains and pipes to be of suffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient size and strength to produce these fire streams, and that the ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chinery shall be such as to deliver all the water necessary at each of said asylums for these fire streams, without interfering with the supply of water for other purposes at the same time these fire streams are used.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the amount to be paid for fire protection, and for all other purposes at all of the asylums and at the other public buildings and grounds mentioned in section 1 of this act, shall not exceed seven thousand dollars per annum.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The water supply shall be filtered and suitable for culinary and other domestic purposes, and shall be delivered in sufficient quanti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties for the purposes desired, and with such pressure as to be available at all times at each of the places hereinbefore mentioned.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the contractor shall execute a satisfactory bond to the State of Texas, which shall be approved by the Governor, for the faith<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful performance of the conditions and provisions of any contract that may be executed under the provisions of this act. The consent of a ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jority of the persons named in section one of this act shall be necessary to the execution of said contract, and the same shall be signed by such majority.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The contract shall designate some time, not exceeding one year, when such water supply shall be ready for use at each of the asy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lum buildings and public grounds.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. There is hereby appropriated for the purpose of carrying out this contract, and paying the contractors the amount to which they may be entitled under their contract, the sum of seven thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, to be paid quarterly on accounts to be approved by the Governor of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The liability of the said buildings to be destroyed, and the near approach of the close of the present session of the Legislature, creates an imperative public necessity requiring the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and it<pb n="301" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>is so suspended, and an emergency that the same take effect from passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>May 5, A. D. 1882</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
<p>The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proval on the fifth day of May, 1882, and was not signed by him, nor returned to the house in which it originated, with his objections thereto, within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.</p>
<closer>
<signed>(Signed) T. H. BOWMAN, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>THE STATE OF TEXAS, <lb/>D<smcap>EPARTMENT OF</smcap> S<smcap>TATE</smcap>.</p>
<p>I, T. H. Bowman, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, do hereby certify that I have compared the foregoing laws, passed by the Seven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth Legislature, with the originals now on file in this department, and that they are true copies thereof. I further certify that the Seventeenth Legislature of the State of Texas convened in special session at the city of Austin on the sixth day of April, A. D. 1882, and adjourned on the fifth day of May, A. D. 1882.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof I hereunto sign my name and affix <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L. S.]</p></body></floatingText>the seal of the State of Texas, at the city of Austin, on this the sixteenth day of May, A. D. 1882.</p>
<closer>
<signed>T. H. BOWMAN, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="302" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX.</head>
<p>Appeals, Court of&#8212;decisions, how reported and published......................... 7</p>
<p>Apportionment&#8212;of State into senatorial and representative districts......................... 9 of State into congressional districts......................... 38</p>
<p>Appropriations&#8212;for mileage and per diem of members and officers of the Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature......................... 1</p>
<p>to defray contingent expenses of the Legislature......................... 1</p>
<p>for rent of portion of Bruegeerhoff building for courts......................... 2</p>
<p>for temporary lunatic asylum building......................... 4</p>
<p>to run boundary line of Greer county......................... 5</p>
<p>in reference to destroying and canceling bonds......................... 15</p>
<p>for temporary capital......................... 16</p>
<p>deficiency for year ending February 28, 1882, and for previous years......................... 23</p>
<p>for support of State government from March 1, 1882, to February 28, 1883 26</p>
<p>for capitol commissioners......................... 28</p>
<p>for reprint of Revised Statutes......................... 30</p>
<p>for relief of certain liquor dealers.........................</p>
<p>to purchase Texas Reports.........................</p>
<p>for Prairie View Normal School......................... 37</p>
<p>for supplying public buildings with water......................... 40</p>
<p>Asylum, Lunatic&#8212;erection of temporary building provided for......................... 4</p>
<p>Bonds&#8212;of the State, certain ones to be destroyed......................... 15</p>
<p>certain, to be canceled in New York......................... 15</p>
<p>Brueggerhoff Building&#8212;rent of portion of, for courts......................... 2</p>
<p>Capitol&#8212;temporary, to be provided......................... 16</p>
<p>further provisions in reference to construction of new......................... 28</p>
<p>Capitol Board&#8212;to provide temporary capitol......................... 16</p>
<p>duty of, in regard to new capital......................... 28</p>
<p>Canals and Ditches&#8212;act granting lands or certificates for construction of, repealed......................... 3</p>
<p>Certificates, Land&#8212;act grafting, repealed......................... 3</p>
<p>Charlton, William, Judge&#8212;leave of absence granted to......................... 36</p>
<p>Commissioners&#8212;to run State boundary line of Greer county......................... 5</p>
<p>capitol, duty of......................... 28</p>
<p>Comptroller of Public Accounts&#8212;to make regulations in reference to payment of taxes on land sold to the State......................... 3</p>
<p>required to suspend collection of certain taxes......................... 39</p>
<p>Congressional&#8212;districts......................... 38</p>
<p>Collin County&#8212;certain inhabitants of Plano, released from payment of taxes.. 31</p>
<p>Counties&#8212;when organized, judge to fix time of holding courts......................... 4</p>
<p>Crockett county attached, to Kinney county for judicial purposes......................... 5</p>
<p>Convicts, County&#8212;act relating to hiring of......................... 16</p>
<p>Courts, Supreme and Appellate&#8212;temporary rooms for, provided......................... 2</p>
<p>decisions, haw reported......................... 7</p>
<p>reports, how published......................... 7</p>
<p>Court, District&#8212;time of holding in newly organized counties to be fixed by judge......................... 4</p>
<p>Court, Commissioners&#8212;to give relief to certain liquor dealers......................... 31</p>
<p>Crockett County&#8212;attacked to Kinney county for judicial purposes......................... 5</p>
<p>Davis. J. H., Judge.&#8212;leave of absence granted to......................... 36</p>
<p>Districts&#8212;State apportioned into senatorial and representative......................... 9</p>
<p>State apportioned into congressional......................... 38</p>
<p>Election&#8212;for location of branch of University......................... 25</p>
<p>Greer County&#8212;Commissioners to be appointed to run boundary line......................... 5</p>
<pb n="303" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Governor&#8212;to appoint commissioners to run line between U. S. territories and Texas......................... 5</p>
<p>to order election for location of branch University......................... 25</p>
<p>Judges, District&#8212;to fix time of holding court in newly organized counties......................... 4</p>
<p>Lands&#8212;sold for taxes, time in which, to redeem extended......................... 3</p>
<p>act granting, for construction of railroads, canals ana ditches repealed... 3</p>
<p>school, act providing for sale of amended......................... 36</p>
<p>pine timbered, price......................... 36</p>
<p>Land Certificates&#8212;act granting repealed......................... 3</p>
<p>Liquor Dealers&#8212;taxes to be refunded to......................... 30</p>
<p>Millett, C. F.&#8212;appropriation for rent of opera house, etc.......................... 27</p>
<p>McAdoo, J. D., Judge&#8212;leave of absence granted to......................... 36</p>
<p>Passengers&#8212;fare on railroads regulated......................... 3</p>
<p>Penitentiary&#8212;appropriations......................... 26</p>
<p>Plana&#8212;certain inhabitants of released from payment of taxes......................... 31</p>
<p>Prairie View School&#8212;appropriations for......................... 37</p>
<p>quarantine&#8212;appropriations......................... 26</p>
<p>Railroads&#8212;passenger fare regulated......................... 3</p>
<p>act granting land or certificates to, repealed......................... 3</p>
<p>prohibited from making greater charge for freight than specified in bill of lading......................... 35</p>
<p>Robertson, John C., Judge&#8212;leave of absence granted to......................... 36</p>
<p>Secretary of State&#8212;authorized to contract for rent of rooms for Supreme Court 2</p>
<p>to sell future volumes of Texas Reports and Court of Appeals Reports... 7</p>
<p>to have reprint of Revised Statutes......................... 30</p>
<p>authorized to purchase Texas Reports, and to contract for relinquish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of copyright......................... 34</p>
<p>Senatorial and Representative&#8212;districts......................... 9</p>
<p>Statistics&#8212;board of, to apply certain appropriation for payment of clerks.... 4</p>
<p>Statutes, Revised&#8212;article 4256 amended......................... 3</p>
<p>articles 1026, 1027, 1028, 1020, 1030, 1031, 1032, chapter 5, title 26, and articles 1077, 1078, 1079, 1080, 1081, 1082, chapter 15, title 26, of Civil Statutes, amended......................... 7</p>
<p>title 4 of Civil Statutes, amended......................... 9</p>
<p>art. 3602, chap. 10, title 71, of Civil Statutes, amended......................... 16</p>
<p>articles 4662, 4664, 4665, chapter 1, title 95, amended......................... 18</p>
<p>publication of second edition provided for......................... 30</p>
<p>Supreme Court&#8212;decisions, how reported......................... 7</p>
<p>reports, how published.......................... 7</p>
<p>Secretary of State to purchase reports and contract for relinquishment of copyright......................... 34</p>
<p>Taxes&#8212;time extended for redemption of lands, sold for......................... 3</p>
<p>occupation......................... 18</p>
<p>certain citizens released from payment of......................... 31</p>
<p>of certain liquor dealers to be refunded......................... 30</p>
<p>collections in organized counties from 1871 to 1876 suspended......................... 39</p>
<p>Tax&#8212;ad valorem......................... 18</p>
<p>poll......................... 18</p>
<p>occupation......................... 18</p>
<p>Texas Reports&#8212;how published, by whom sold......................... 7</p>
<p>Secretary of State to purchase......................... 7</p>
<p>copyright of......................... 34</p>
<p>Treasurer, State&#8212;to destroy certain bonds......................... 15</p>
<p>to have certain bonds cancelled......................... 15</p>
<p>University&#8212;branch of, for colored youths, to be located......................... 25</p>
<p>United States&#8212;territories and Texas, boundary line between to be run......................... 5</p>
<p>veteran Board&#8212;-appropriation for......................... 25</p>
<p>Veterans, Texas&#8212;pensions under special acts 1881......................... 25</p>
<p>Water&#8212;supply for public buildings provided for......................... 40</p>
<pb n="304" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" />
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
