<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="31" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="I" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>PASSED AT THE <lb/>SPECIAL SESSION OF THE SIXTEENTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>CONVENED <lb/>AT THE CITY OF AUSTIN</head>
<byline>JUNE 10<smcap>TH</smcap>, 1879, AND ADJOURNED JULY 9<smcap>TH</smcap>, 1879.</byline>
<byline>BY AUTHORITY.</byline>
<byline>GALVESTON 1879</byline>
<pb n="32" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="II" />
<pb n="33" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<head type="sub">GENERAL LAWS OF TEXAS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act making an appropriation for mileage and per diem pay of members, and per diem pay of officers and employees of the first called session of the Sixteenth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of forty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated out of any moneys in the treasury not otherwise appropriated for the payment of mileage and per diem pay of the members, and the payment of the per diem pay of the officers and employees of the first called session of the Sixteenth Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the certificate of the secretary of the senate, approved by the president thereof, or the certificate of the chief clerk of the House, approved by the speaker thereof, shall be sufficient evidence to the comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller, upon which he shall audit the claims and issue his warrants upon the treasurer for the respective amounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the balance of moneys remaining in the treasury, here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tofore appropriated for the per diem pay and mileage of the members, and the per diem pay of officers and employees of any preceding session of the Legislature of the State of Texas, be and the same is hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />appropriated for the purposes specified in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. And, whereas, the first called session of the Sixteenth Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature, for the payment of the members and officers of which this law is enacted, is now in session, and public policy requires their payment; therefore, an imperative public necessity exists that the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days be suspended and it is so enacted, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>June 18, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act making an appropriation to defray the contin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gent expenses of the Sixteenth Legislature, convened on June 10th, 1879, in extra session, by proclamation of the governor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, It is of sufficient public importance that the contingent ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses of the extra session of the Sixteenth Legislature be promptly paid in order that the material furnished and labor performed may be pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cured at cash prices; therefore,</p>
<pb n="34" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of ten thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated out of any moneys in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, to pay the contingent expenses of the extra ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of the Sixteenth Legislature; and that the approval by the chairman of the committee on contingent expenses of either house, countersigned by the president of the Senate or speaker of the House, as the case may be, shall be sufficient authority to authorize the comptroller to issue his warrant on the state treasurer for the payment of any account against said fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the public importance of the objects herein contem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plated, and the peculiar circumstances of the members and the em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployees of the Sixteenth Legislature creates an imperative public neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity and emergency fully authorizing the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring the reading of bills upon three several days, and the said rule is hereby suspended, and this act shall be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>June 18, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act supplementary to &#8220;an act to establish a State Normal School," approved April 21, 1879.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, The citizens of Huntsville, Walker county, have tendered to the state a warrantee title to the buildings and grounds lately known as &#8220;Austin College,&#8221; located at Huntsville, at which place the &#8220;Sam Houston Normal Institute&#8221; has been established by the fore-recited act, but the chain of title is not perfect so as to vest a clearly legal title in the state, and further time is required to formally perfect the title; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, the said citizens have paid the purchase money due on said buildings and grounds, and have been placed in possession of the same and are desirous of delivering possession of the same in good repair to the state for the establishment of said institute, and propose to guarantee to the state a perfect title to the same; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, it is important that said institute be opened at the earliest day practicable, which creates an emergency for the immediate passage and taking effect of this act; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the state board of education is authorized and required to accept possession of said buildings and grounds from the citizens of Huntsville, on receiving from them such bond or guarantee of a valid legal title to the same in the state within twelve months from the passage of this act, the bond or guarantee to be payable to the state, and in such sum, not to exceed fifty thousand dollars, and conditioned as the governor and attorney general shall prescribe; and a further guarantee from said citizens that said buildings shall be placed in such reasonable repair as the board of education may require, including a new plank fence around the grounds.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That on receiving such guarantees and possession of said buildings and grounds, it shall be the duty of said board to establish rules and regulations, appoint a local board of directors and open said<pb n="35" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>institute for students, as provided in the act approved April 21, 1879, entitled &#8220;An act to establish a state normal school.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>June 23, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to define the times of holding the terms of the district courts in the fifth judicial district of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That hereafter the terms of the district courts of the fifth judicial dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict of the State of Texas, shall be holden at the times hereinafter speci<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied, to wit: In the county of Cass, on the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session three weeks; in the county of Bowie, on the third Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Morris, on the fifth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Titus, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Franklin, on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Camp, on the tenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Marion, on the twelfth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session six weeks; provided, that no jury shall be em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />panneled after the fourth week of said terms.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all writs and process returnable to said courts, shall be returnable to the terms of said courts as herein defined, and all such writs and process as have been issued, executed and returned, shall be as valid as if no change had been made in said courts by the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all laws in conflict herewith be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>June 26, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act making an appropriation to pay the interest on the public debt and to pay the sinking fund.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following sums of money, or so much thereof as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to pay the interest and sinking fund on the public debt, are hereby appropriated:</p>
<p>1. For payment of interest on the public debt, due July 1,</p>
<p>1879 .......................................................................................$157,912 75</p>
<p>2. Interest due September 1, 1879........................................... 26,470 00</p>
<p>3. Interest due January 1, 1880................................................ 157,713 00</p>
<p>4. Interest due March 1, 1880................................................... 26,470 00</p>
<pb n="36" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>5. Interest due July 1, 1880.......................................................$157,912 75</p>
<p>6. Interest due September 1, 1880............................................ 26,470 00</p>
<p>7. Interest due January 1, 1881................................................. 157,713 00</p>
<p>Total interest .......................................... $710,661 50</p>
<p>1. For sinking fund from September 1, 1878, to August 31, 1879 .........................................................................................$100,000 00</p>
<p>2. For sinking fund for year ending August 31, 1880............. 100,000 00</p>
<p>3. For sinking fund from August 31, 1880, to February 28, 1881 ........................................................................................ 50,000 00</p>
<p>Total sinking fund.....................................'..................$250,000 00</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that a large amount of the public interest will be due on the first day of July, 1879, creates an imperative public necessity for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, said rule is therefore suspended; and the same fact creates an emergency that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, it is therefore so enacted that this bill shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>June 28, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act defining and describing what funds shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute the available school fund, and repealing all laws in conflict therewith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the one dollar poll tax levied and collected for the use of public free schools, exclusive of the costs of collection, the interest arising from any bonds or funds belonging to the permanent school fund, and all the interest derivable from the proceeds of sales of land heretofore set apart for the permanent school fund which have hitherto or may hereafter come into the state treasury, and such amount of the general revenue levied and collected after the thirty-first day of December, A. D. 1878, as the Legislature shall, from time to time, appropriate, shall constitute the available school fund, and shall be appropriated to the support and maintenance of the public free schools of this state.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That section twelve (12) of &#8220;An act to establish and provide for the support and maintenance of an efficient system of public free schools," approved August 19, 1876, and so much of &#8220;An act amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and supplementing articles 4662, 4663, 4664, 4665, 4666, 4667 and 4668, inclusive, of chapter one, title 95 of the Revised Civil Statutes,&#8221; adopted February 21, 1879, approved April 22, 1879, as amends article 4663 of Revised Civil Statutes, and article 3704, chapter three, title seventy-eight, and article 4663, chapter one, title ninety-five of &#8220;An act to adopt and establish the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas,&#8221; passed February 21, 1879, and all laws or parts of laws levying or col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lecting, segregating or setting apart any part of the revenue for the sup<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port of public free schools, except as stated and provided for in the first section of this act, and all laws or parts of laws in conflict with this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<pb n="37" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. That the limited period permitted for the session creates an emergency and imperative public necessity that requires the suspension of the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days, and it is so enacted, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 2, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to change and fix the times of holding the terms of the district courts in the eleventh judicial district of this state.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the district courts of the eleventh judicial district shall be holden at the times hereinafter specified to wit: In the county of Ellis on the first Mondays in February and September, and may continue in session five (5) weeks; in the county of Dallas, on the second Mondays in March, May, October and December, and may continue in session until the busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all writs and process returnable to said courts shall be returnable to the terms of said courts as herein defined; and all such writs and process as have been issued, executed and returned, shall be as valid as if no change had been made in the time of holding said courts by the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all laws and parts or laws in conflict with the provisions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The near approach of the close of the present session of the Legislature creates an emergency which requires the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring all bills to be read upon three several days, and it is therefore suspended; and the further fact that the docket of Dallas county is crowded with business, and that the terms of the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict court of Ellis county are, by this act, made to commence on the first Mondays in February and September, creates an imperative public necessity that this act take effect and be in force within ninety days, it is therefore enacted that this act take effect and be in force from and after the thirty-first day of August, A. D. 1879.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 2, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after the thirty-first day of August, 1879.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to better provide for the prompt accounting for and payment of public moneys by tax collectors to the proper re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceiving officers.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all tax collectors and other officers or appointees authorized to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive public moneys shall account for all moneys in their hands belonging to the state, and pay the same over to the state treasurer whenever and as often as they may be directed so to do by the comptroller of public accounts; provided, that tax collectors shall have thirty days from the date of such direction within which to comply with the same.</p>
<pb n="38" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That all tax collectors and other officers or appointees author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to receive public moneys, shall account for all moneys in their hands belonging to their respective counties, cities or towns, and pay the same over to the respective county treasurers or city treasurers, whenever and as often as they may be directed so to do by the respective county judges, or county commissioners&#8217; courts, or mayor or board of aldermen; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that tax collectors shall have ten days from the date of such di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rection within which to comply with the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The notification and direction provided for in the two pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceding sections may be verbal, written or by telegram; and if written or by telegram, proof of the deposit in the postoffice or telegraph office of such notification and direction, with postage or charges duly prepaid and correctly addressed, shall be prima facie evidence of the fact of such notification and direction having been given, and of the time when the same was given.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Every tax collector, or other officer or appointee, authorized to receive public moneys, failing wilfully or negligently to comply with such direction and notification, as prescribed in sections one and two of this act shall be deemed guilty of a felony, and shall be punished by im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prisonment in the penitentiary for not less than three nor more than ten years.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Prosecutions for failing to account for and pay over public moneys belonging to the state, as required by this act, shall be conducted in Travis county.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Prosecutions for failing to account for and pay over public moneys belonging to the respective counties, cities or towns, as required by this act, shall be conducted in the county to which such public moneys may belong, or in the county where such city or town is situated.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The provisions of this act shall be cumulative to the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of title ninety-five, chapter four of the Revised Civil Statutes, concerning the collection of taxes, and of title four, chapter three of the Criminal Code, concerning the mis-application of public moneys, except where the latter may be in conflict with this act; and the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of said titles and chapters when in conflict with this act, and all other acts in conflict with this act, are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Whereas, there exists an imperative public necessity that the revenues of the state and counties shall at once become available; be it further enacted, that this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 2, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to postpone the time for the forced collection of taxes by levy and sale, until the 31st day of October, A. D. 1879, in such county or counties in this state as had no legal collector of taxes for the twelve months prior to the first day of March, A. D. 1879.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the time for the collection of all back taxes by seizure, levy or sale, in each and every county in this state which had no legal collector of taxes for twelve months prior to the first day of March, A. D. 1879, is hereby extended until the thirty-first day of October, A. D. 1879.</p>
<pb n="39" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. It shall be the duty of the collector of taxes, in such county or counties as come under the provisions of section one of this act, to use all necessary diligence to collect the taxes due and unpaid in his county, but he is hereby prohibited from the seizure or sale of property until the said thirty-first day of October, A. D. 1879.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. If any person, firm, corporation or association of persons, shall fail or refuse to pay the taxes imposed by law and which are due and un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paid, in such county or counties as are mentioned in the caption and first section of this act, until the said thirty-first day of October, A. D. 1879, the collector of taxes in said county shall forthwith and promptly seize, levy upon and sell so much property belonging to such person, firm, corporation or association of persons, whether residents or non-resi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dents, as may be sufficient to pay his or their taxes and penalties due, together with all costs accruing thereon in accordance with the law then in force for the collection of delinquent taxes.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Whereas, the time for the forced collection of taxes is already at hand, therefore, an imperative public necessity and an emergency ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ists demanding the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring a bill to be read on three several days, it is therefore suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 2, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to diminish the civil jurisdiction of the county court of Navarro county and to conform the jurisdiction of the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict court of said county to such change.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the county court of Navarro county shall have and exercise the general jurisdiction of a probate court; shall probate wills, appoint guardians of minors, idiots, lunatics, persons non compos mentis and common drunkards, grant letters testamentary and of administration, settle accounts of executors, administrators and guardians, transact all business appertaining to the estates of deceased persons, minors, idiots, lunatics, persons non compos mentis and common drunkards, including the settlement, partition and distribution of estates of deceased persons, and to apprentice minors as provided by law, and to issue all writs neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to the enforcement of its said jurisdiction, to punish contempts un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der such provisions as are or may be provided by general law governing county courts throughout the state; but said county court of Navarro county shall have no other civil jurisdiction whatsoever.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said county court shall have and exercise such jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion over and pertaining to criminal matters and proceedings as by gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral laws of this state is conferred upon county courts.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the district court of said Navarro county shall have and exercise jurisdiction in all civil matters and causes over which, by the general laws of this state, the county court of said county would have jurisdiction, except as provided in section one of this act; and that all causes other than probate matters, and such as are provided by sections one and two of this act, be and the same are hereby transferred to<pb n="40" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the district court of said Navarro county, and all writs and process relat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to civil matters heretofore issued by, or out of, said county court of Navarro county other than those pertaining to matters over which by section one of this act jurisdiction is given to said county court of said county, be and the same are hereby made returnable to the next term of the said district court of Navarro county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the county clerk of said Navarro county be and he is hereby required within twenty days after the passage of this act, to make a fair and complete transcript of all entries upon his civil dockets heretofore made in causes which by section three of this act are trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred to the district court of said county, and deliver the same to the district clerk of said county, together with all papers to such causes per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining, and all such cases shall immediately be docketed by said district clerk, and such civil cases so transferred shall stand on the docket of said court as appearance cases for the next succeeding term of said court.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act shall not be construed to in any manner affect judgments heretofore rendered by said county court of Navarro county, pertaining to matters and causes which by section three of this act are transferred to the district court of said county, but the county clerk of said county shall issue all executions and orders of sale as the judgments in such cases require, and such executions and orders of sale and the proceedings thereunder shall be as valid and binding to all intents and purposes as though no change had been made, as by section three of this act is contemplated.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act be and they are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The limited time allotted to the present session of this Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature and the urgent need of the provisions of this act, creates an im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perative public necessity that the rules be suspended and that this act be put upon its immediate and final passage; and the fact that the benefits to be derived from it by Navarro county will be greatly enhanced by its immediate action and effect, creates an emergency, and it is there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore enacted that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 2, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend the ninth section of &#8220;an act estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lishing the tenth, twelfth, thirtieth, twenty-eighth, twenty-ninth and thirteenth judicial districts, prescribing the times of holding the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict courts therein, and providing for the appointment of district judges for the twenty-eighth, twenty-ninth and thirtieth judicial dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricts," approved February 22, 1879.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the ninth section of the above recited act be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 9. That the district courts in the counties composing the thirteenth judicial district shall be holden as follows: In the county of Freestone, on the first Mondays in April and December, and may continue in session four weeks; in the county of Navarro, on the fifth Mondays<pb n="41" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>after the first Mondays in April, August, and December, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session six weeks; in the county of Limestone, on the eleventh Mondays after the first Mondays in April, August, and December, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.&#8221;</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 2, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to enable the municipal authorities of towns, cities, and the commissioners&#8217; courts of the counties wherein such towns and cities are situated, to co-operate with each other in improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments connected with the town or city and county necessary to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mote the sanitary regulations thereof.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the municipal authorities of towns and cities, and commissioners&#8217; courts of the counties wherein such towns and cities are situated, may co-operate with each other in making such improvements connected with said towns, cities and counties as may be deemed by said authorities and courts necessary to improve the public health and to promote efficient sanitary regulations; and, by mutual arrangement, they may provide for the construction of said improvements and the payment therefor.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Owing to the amount of business now pending before this extra session, there exists an imperative public necessity for dispensing with the rule which requires this bill to be read on three several days, and the near approach of the epidemic season in some portions of the state creates an emergency requiring this act to be in force from and after its passage; and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 4, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to better provide for and facilitate the col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lection of all judgments in favor of the state or any county thereof.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in any case wherein any property shall be sold by virtue of any execution or order of sale issued upon any judgment in favor of the state, except executions issued upon judgments in cases of scire facias, the agent or attorney representing the state by and with the advice and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent of the attorney general of the state, is hereby authorized and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to attend such sales, and bid on and buy in for the state said prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty, when it shall be deemed proper to protect the interest of the state in the collection of such judgment; provided, that in no case shall the amount bid by him exceed the amount necessary to satisfy said judgment and all costs due thereon.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That in all cases where property is so purchased by the state, the officer selling the same shall execute and deliver to the state a deed of conveyance to the same, such as is prescribed for individuals in similar cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The agent or attorney of the state buying for the state any such property at such sale, shall be authorized by and with the advice<pb n="42" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and consent of the attorney general, at any time to sell or otherwise dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of said property so purchased, in the manner and upon such terms and conditions as he may deem most advantageous to the state; and if sold or disposed of for a greater amount than is necessary to pay off the amount due upon the judgment and all costs, the remainder shall be paid into the state treasury and placed to the credit of the general rev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />enue; and when such sale is made the attorney general shall, in the name of the state, execute and deliver to the purchaser a deed of conveyance to said property, which deed when, so signed by him, shall vest all the right and title to the same in the purchaser thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. When any such property is sold under execution or order of sale issued upon any judgment in favor of the county, including execu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions issued upon judgments in cases of scire facias in the name of the state, the attorney or agent so representing the county, by and with the advice and consent of the commissioners&#8217; court, shall have the same authority to buy in and dispose of such property for the county, as the agent or attorney for the state is given in this act in similar cases; and when any property is so purchased by the agent or attorney of the county, the officer so selling the same shall execute and deliver to the county a deed of conveyance to the same; and whenever the property so bought in for the county is sold, the county commissioners&#8217; court shall execute and deliver to the purchaser thereof a deed of conveyance in the name of the county to such property.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That whenever the principal and sureties upon any judgment held by the state are insolvent so that under any existing process of law said judgment or any part thereof cannot be collected, there shall be and is hereby constituted a board consisting of the attorney general, comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller and treasurer of the state, who are hereby empowered and author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized by such advertising as they may deem necessary to offer for sale at public outcry, or by private sale, as they may deem to the best interest of the state, all the right of the state to such judgment; and if by public sale, if the amount bid on the same should not be deemed sufficient, they shall refuse to accept the same, and dispose of the same in any manner deemed by them most advantageous to the interest of the state, and upon sale shall make a proper assignment of said judgment to the purchaser.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Upon any like judgment, the proceeds of which revert to and belong to any county, the county commissioners&#8217; court shall constitute a board to dispose of the same for the county in the same manner, and shall have the same power in the premises as the state board has under the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. There being in force no efficient law upon this subject in this state, this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 4, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to provide for the transfer of judgments ren<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dered in the county courts where the civil and criminal jurisdiction (or either) has been transferred to the district courts, and to authorize the enforcement thereof.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be the duty of the clerks of the county courts of the several counties in this state, where the civil and criminal jurisdiction<pb n="43" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>(or either) of the county court has been transferred to the district court, to make out a certified copy of all judgments remaining unsatisfied, which have been rendered in civil or criminal cases in the county court, and transmit the same to the clerk of the district court of their respective counties.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. When the clerk of the district court of any county in the state, where the civil and criminal jurisdiction (or either) of the county court has been transferred to the district court, shall receive from the clerk of the county court a certified copy of a judgment rendered in any civil or criminal case in the county court, he shall immediately record such judgment in the minutes of the district court; and thereupon the said district court shall have the power to enforce said judgments by execution or otherwise, as other judgments rendered in said district court are or may be enforced.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Whereas, the Sixteenth Legislature passed an act diminish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the civil and criminal jurisdiction of the county courts of certain counties in this state, which will take effect on the twenty-fourth day of July, A. D. 1879; and whereas, it is necessary, and public policy requires, that this act should take effect at the same time; therefore, an emergency exists that this act take effect and be in force from and after the twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fourth day of July, A. D. 1879, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The great amount of business now before the Legislature, and the short time remaining to this session, renders it doubtful whether this bill can be read on three several days; therefore an imperative neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity exists which authorizes the suspension of the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and said rule is therefore suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 4, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect on the twenty-fourth day of July, 1879.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to equalize and regulate the pay and arming of all military or police companies organized and operated under any law of this state, except those organized under the militia law.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the pay of officers and men in any military or police company or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganized under any law of this state, except those organized under the militia law, shall be as follows: For captains, one hundred dollars; for lieutenants, seventy-five dollars; for first sergeants, fifty dollars; for other duty sergeants, forty dollars; for corporals, thirty-five dollars; for privates, thirty dollars per month for each month of actual service, and nothing shall be paid by way of commutation.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The state shall furnish necessary ammunition, and to each officer, non-commissioned officer and private, all necessary arms at cost, the price of which shall be deducted from the first money due them by the state; provided, that when any of the forces in service in this state shall be regularly discharged from said companies, any arms in their pos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />session may be returned to the state at their reasonable value at the time of their return, said value to be determined by the adjutant general, pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided said arms be in good condition; provided further, that any person enlisting in said service may have the right to furnish their own arms, provided they be of the same kind and calibre.</p>
<pb n="44" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. The provisions of any law in any way conflicting with this act, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Whereas, there are now laws in force making a difference be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween the pay and arming of the military forces of this state, thereby discriminating between said forces, an emergency exists that this act take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 4, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend article 1136, chapter one, title twenty-eight of the Revised Civil Statutes, adopted Feb. 21, 1879.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the above recited article shall be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 1136. County judges in those counties wherein the civil or criminal jurisdiction of the county courts has been or may hereafter be diminished shall have the right to practice as attorneys in all justices&#8217; and county courts in cases wherein the courts over which they preside have neither original nor appellate jurisdiction, provided they are li<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />censed lawyers.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas, under the constitution the present session of the Legislature is limited to thirty days, a great portion of which has already expired; and whereas, under existing laws county judges are deprived of practicing in county and other inferior courts; therefore, an emergency exists and an imperative public necessity demands the suspension of the constitutional rule which requires a bill to be read on three several days and that this law take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 4, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">Chapter XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to enforce the collection of delinquent taxes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the comptroller of public accounts be and he is hereby required to prepare and forward to the county commissioners&#8217; court of the several counties of this state, a full and complete abstract of the yearly delin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quent list of taxes upon lands in their respective counties, assessed since the first day of January, 1870, showing upon what lands such taxes are due, the year the same was assessed, the amount due the state for each year and the amount due the county for each year; and he shall describe each tract in the same manner as it is described on the tax rolls by the party assessing the same, and shall also state by and for whom rendered, and shall certify officially to the facts set forth in said list.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Upon receipt of said list, the county commissioners&#8217; court shall carefully examine the same, and see that the taxes, both general and special, due said county, are accurately stated and correct any inac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curacies or omissions that may have been made therein, and shall attach<pb n="45" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>to the same a certificate that it is correct so far as it relates to the county taxes, and shall thereupon deliver the same to the collector of taxes for such county, who shall at once post a copy of said delinquent list at the court house door and at least two other public places in the county, in different justices&#8217; precincts, requiring the owners of said land to come forward and pay said taxes.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. All lands and town lots rendered in one county and situated in another county, shall be made out by the comptroller on a separate list and forwarded to the commissioners&#8217; court of the county where such lands are situated; and if any of such lands are situated in any unorgan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized county, then the comptroller shall forward a list of such lands to the commissioners&#8217; court of the county to which such unorganized county is attached for judicial purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. At the expiration of sixty days after posting said notices, if said taxes, or any part of them, are unpaid, or satisfactory evidence fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nished the collector of taxes that the taxes have been paid, the collector of taxes shall, by virtue of his roll, seize, levy upon and sell so much property belonging to the person, firm, company or corporation, whether residents or non-residents, against whom the taxes were assessed and due and unpaid as may be sufficient to pay his, her or their taxes and penal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties due, together with all costs accruing thereon; provided, however, that if such person, firm, company or corporation, his, her or their agent or attorney, shall point out to the collector of taxes sufficient property belonging to the party assessed, in said county, to pay said taxes before the expiration of the sixty days, as above provided, then the collector of taxes shall levy upon and sell the property so pointed out; and in case the property seized and levied upon is personal property, the col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lector shall proceed to take into his possession so much thereof as will pay the taxes assessed and due, together with all penalties due and costs accruing thereon.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Every collector of taxes, for personal property, shall give notice of the time and place of the sale of the property so levied on, at least ten days previous to the day of sale, by advertisement in writing, to be posted up, one at the court house door of his county, and one in two other public places in the county; and such sale shall take place at the court house door of the county in which the property is situated, by public auction; and if the property so levied upon proves to be insufficient to satisfy the taxes and penalties due and costs accruing thereon, the collector shall seize and levy upon and sell so much other taxable property belonging to the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, firm, company or corporation, as will be sufficient to satisfy such tax, penalties and costs, in the manner prescribed in the preceding part of this section; provided, should the property sold bring more than the taxes, penalties and costs, the remainder shall be paid to the owner by the collector, or deposited by him in the county treasurer&#8217;s office, subject to the order of the party or parties owning said property.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. If the taxes upon any land or town lots in this state are not paid before the expiration of the sixty days provided for in section four of this act, the collector of taxes shall seize, levy upon and sell such land or town lots, whether belonging to residents or non-residents, for the payment of all taxes and penalties due thereon, together with all costs which have or may accrue thereon; and he shall advertise the same for sale in some newspaper published in the county for three successive weeks, if there be one, and if there be no newspaper in the county, then by posting said advertisement for thirty days at the court house door<pb n="46" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and three other public places in the county where the land or lots are situated, giving in said advertisement such description as is given to the same on the certified statements furnished him by the commissioners&#8217; court, as furnished the court by the comptroller of public accounts; giving the name of the owner if known, and if unknown, say &#8220;unknown,&#8221; together with time, place and terms of said sale; said sale to be for cash, to the highest bidder at public outcry, at the court house door; which sales shall be between legal hours, on the first Tuesday of the month; provided, if the sale of all the lands and town lots advertised is not made in one day, the sale shall be continued from day to day. The collector of taxes shall make proclamation at the close of each day of the continu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of the sale the following day, and as far as practicable all the lands and town lots seized shall be advertised in one notice; provided, that the owner of such lands, or his agent, shall, upon the payment of all delinquent taxes due upon said lands since January 1, A. D. 1873, prior to the day upon which said land is advertised to be sold, he shall receive a full and complete acquittance from all delinquent taxes due upon such land.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The collector of taxes, in making sales for taxes due upon real estate, shall sell at auction at the time and place appointed so much of said real estate as may be necessary to pay the taxes and penalties due, and all costs accruing thereon; and shall offer said real estate to the bidder who will pay the taxes and penalties due and costs of sale and execution of deed for the least amount of said real estate, which bidder shall be considered the highest bidder. Should a less amount of said real estate than the whole tract or parcel of said real estate levied upon be sold for the taxes and penalties due and all costs of sale and execution of deed, the collector shall, in making his deed to the purchaser, begin at some corner of said tract or parcel of land or town lot, and designate the same in a square as near as practicable.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The collector of taxes shall execute and deliver to the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chaser, upon the payment of the amount for which the estate was sold, and costs and penalties, a deed for the real estate sold; which deed shall vest a good and absolute fee in said lands or lots to the purchaser, if not redeemed in two years as herein provided for; which deed shall state the cause of sale, the amount sold, the price for which the real estate was sold, the name of the person, firm, company or corporation against whom the taxes were assessed provided the name is known, and if unknown, say &#8220;unknown;&#8221; and when real estate has been sold, he shall convey, subject to the right of redemption provided for in the following section, all the right and interest which the former owner had therein at the time when the assessment was made, or when the sale was made.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The owner of real estate sold for the payment of taxes, or his heirs or assigns, or legal representative, may, within two years from the date of sale, redeem the estate sold by paying or tendering to the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chaser, his heirs or legal representative, double the amount of money paid for the land or lots, together with all the subsequent taxes that the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chaser has paid on the same from the day of purchase to the day of re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demption. The collector of taxes shall give in said deed such descrip<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the real estate as is given on the certified roll or list as shall be furnished him as is required by the provisions of this act, and such other descriptions as may be necessary to the better identification of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The provisions of this act in reference to the seizure and sale of real and personal property for taxes, penalties and costs due thereon,<pb n="47" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall apply as well to collectors of taxes for towns and cities as for col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lectors of taxes for counties, and they shall be governed in selling real and personal property by the same rules and regulations in all respects as to time, place, manner and terms, and making deeds as are provided for collectors of taxes for counties.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Should the collector of taxes for any city or town fail to make sale of any real estate for want of a purchaser, he shall bid the same off to the city or town for the taxes and penalties and costs thereon, and make due return thereof to the city council or board of mayor and aldermen, and said collector shall, on final settlement of his accounts with the municipal authorities of such city or town, be entitled to a credit for the amount of taxes due the city or town, for the amount for which the land or lots were bid off to the city or town; provided, that the rolls of delinquent taxpayers in any city or town, when duly certified to by the recorder or clerk of said city or town, and placed in the hands of said tax collectors, shall be authority to said tax collectors to seize and sell the property, as provided in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Should the collector of taxes fail to make sale of any real estate for want of a purchaser, he shall hid the same off to the state for the taxes and penalties due, and all costs accruing thereon, and make due return thereof, under such forms and directions as the comptroller may furnish and direct, and he shall, on final settlement of his accounts with the commissioners&#8217; court and the comptroller of public accounts, be entitled to a credit for the amount of taxes due the state and county, respectively, for which the land or lots were bid off to the state.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. The collector of taxes shall make duplicate lists of all real estate sold for taxes, and file one copy in the county clerk&#8217;s office for record and forward a certified copy to the comptroller of public accounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. All lands and town lots sold to the state, or to a city or town, shall be subject to redemption in the manner and under the same regula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions as land sold to individuals, and in case of collectors of taxes for cities or towns, said collectors shall make duplicate lists of all real estate sold by them for taxes, and file one copy thereof with the clerk or recor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der of said cities or towns.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. When lands upon which there are back taxes due, were as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessed at the comptroller&#8217;s office upon the basis for value of an average of the value of all lands in the county, it shall be lawful for the party pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing such back taxes, to pay at the rate of the assessed value for the year 1876.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. No delinquent taxpayer shall have the right to plead in any court or in any manner rely upon any statute of limitation by way of de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fense against the payment of any taxes due from him or her, either to the state or any county, city or town.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That whenever it shall appear to the collector of taxes in any county in this state, that any person who is a delinquent in the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of his or her taxes, has no property in his county out of which said amount of taxes can be collected, it shall be the duty of such collector to make out from the assessment list a true and complete list or schedule of the taxes due by said delinquent, which shall be certified to under the official seal and signature of said collector, and to forward the same to the collector of taxes of any county or counties where he shall have reason to believe said delinquent has property of any description, and if said property is in any of the unorganized counties of this state, then to the collector of the county to which said unorganized county is<pb n="48" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>attached for judicial purposes, and when received by said collector, he shall at once proceed to the collection of said tax by seizure and sale in the same manner as if said taxes were originally assessed and due in his said county, and shall report to the collector from whom said list was re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived the taxes so collected by him.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. Whenever the assessment list of the assessor is approved by the commissioners&#8217; court, if any person who has listed any personal prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty for taxation shall be about to remove said property from the county, the taxes so assessed shall in such case become due and the collector of taxes shall be required to proceed at once to the collection of said tax in the same manner as other taxes when due.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. There being no law now in force for the collection of delin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quent taxes creates a necessity that this act shall take effect from its pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 4, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to change the form of certain securities therein named.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the coupon bonds in the state treasury to the credit of the Uni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />versity fund, University land sales, the permanent school fund, the Agri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cultural and Mechanical College fund, the Deaf and Dumb Asylum fund, the Blind Asylum fund and the Lunatic Asylum fund, be changed into manuscript-registered bonds, so framed as to include in each bond as large an amount of each series, belonging to each fund, as may be prac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticable and convenient, to be executed and signed by the governor and treasurer and countersigned by the comptroller, payable to each of these several funds, bearing the same rate of interest and payable at the same periods as set forth in the coupon bonds; and that said bonds, so executed, after being compared and found correct as to amounts due the several funds, and so certified to by the governor, comptroller and treasurer, shall be registered in the comptroller&#8217;s and treasurer&#8217;s offices.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That after the coupon bonds are so substituted by the manu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />script-registered bonds, the said coupon bonds shall be burned by the comptroller and treasurer in the presence of the governor, and a list of the bonds so destroyed shall be filed in the office of the comptroller and treasurer.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That hereafter whenever coupon bonds, to the amount of ten thousand dollars, shall come into the treasury to the credit of either of the funds named in this bill, they shall be substituted by registered-man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uscript bonds as provided for in the first section of this act, and the coupon bonds destroyed as provided in section two.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The late hour in the session at which this bill receives consid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eration, creates an emergency and imperative public necessity that the rule be suspended requiring this bill to be read on three several days, and that it take effect from and after its passage, and it is therefore so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 5, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="49" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act amending article 896, chapter one, title eleven of the Code of Criminal Procedure, approved April 24, 1879.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That hereafter article 896, chapter one, title eleven of the Code of Crimi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nal Procedure, shall read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 896. The jurisdiction given to mayors and recorders of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporated towns and cities shall not prevent justices of the peace from exercising the criminal jurisdiction conferred upon them; but in all cases where there is an incorporated town or city within the bounds of a county, the justice and the mayor or recorder shall have concurrent jurisdiction within the limits of such town or city. And no person shall be pun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ished twice for the same act or omission, although such act or omission may be an offense against the penal laws of the state as well as against the ordinances of such city or town; provided, that no ordinance of a city or town shall be valid which provides a less penalty for any act, omis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion or offense, than is prescribed by the Statutes, where such act or omis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion is an offense against the state.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That injustice in the past, and the certainty of its continu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance in the future in this matter, unless remedied, creates an emergency and great public necessity authorizing the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and said rule is hereby suspended, and this act shall be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 5, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend section two of an act entitled &#8220;an act to provide for the printing, binding and distribution of the Revised Civil Statutes, Penal Code and Code of Criminal Procedure,&#8221; approved April 26, 1879.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section two of an act entitled &#8220;An act to provide for the printing, binding and distribution of the Revised Civil Statutes, Penal Code and Code of Criminal Procedure, approved April 26, 1879,&#8221; be amended and re-enacted so as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Sec. 2. Said Revised Civil Statutes, Penal Code and Code of Crimi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nal Procedure, and the amendments thereto passed by the Sixteenth Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature, shall, together with the constitution of the United States and of this state, be published in a volume to be entitled the &#8220;Revised Statutes of Texas,&#8221; and in the publication thereof, the head and marginal indices and references, titles, chapters and articles as contained and numbered in the acts by which the same were adopted and established, shall be retained and published therein, together with a full and accurate index to each Code and the Revised Statutes, in the preparation of which the index to the bills reported by the commissioners appointed to revise the laws shall be conformed to the volume to be published and adopted as the index thereto, so far as the same shall be found to be correct; and the governor shall appoint a codifier, whose duty it shall be to select from the acts passed at the reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ular session of the Sixteenth Legislature all amendments to said Codes and Revised Statutes, and insert the amended articles in the place<pb n="50" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of the original articles of the acts adopting the Codes and Revised Stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />utes, and when new articles have been added to any chapter and title, he shall insert the new articles in their proper places, and shall note by marginal or foot references to the page of an act amending an article; or by which a new article was enacted; and where any general law passed by the Sixteenth Legislature modifies an article, but the same is not amended and re-enacted in said law, he shall leave the article of the Codes and Revised Statutes as it was adopted, but shall by note refer to the law so modifying the article. He shall complete this part of his work by the time the publisher contracted with under this act is ready for the copy. And the codifier appointed under the section of which this is an amendment shall copy all amendments to said Codes and Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vised Statutes passed at the present extra session of the Sixteenth Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature, so soon as signed by the governor, and insert them in their proper places and shall note all laws passed at said session that may modify, but do not in terms amend an article or chapter of said Codes and Revised Statutes. He shall prepare an accurate index of each Code and the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vised Statutes as amended, and shall read and revise the proof of the Statutes, indices, etc., as printed. For his services he shall receive the same compensation as was allowed the commissioners who revised the Codes and Revised Statutes for the time he is necessarily engaged in the duties required of him, the same to be paid from time to time, not to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed six hundred dollars, upon certificate of the governor. That the sum of two hundred and fifty dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ury not otherwise appropriated to carry this act into effect. The print<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing board may, in their discretion, cause said volume of Revised Stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />utes to be electrotyped or sereotyped (stereotyped) as may seem best; provided, that nothing contained in this amendment shall be so con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strued as to in any wise interfere with the contract already made for the publication of said Revised Statutes further than to secure the insertion of the amendments aforesaid; and provided further, that the contractors for the publication thereof will insert the amended articles of the pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent extra session as herein provided at not exceeding fifty dollars of ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ditional cost to the state and above the present contract price therefor.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2 (3). The necessity for the publication of the Revised Statutes of Texas in as complete a form as possible, and their early distribution among the people create a public necessity and emergency that the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage; and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 5, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act prescribing the times of holding the district courts in the several counties composing the twenty-second judicial district.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the terms of the district court for the twenty-second judicial dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict shall be held in the several counties thereof at the times hereinafter specified, in each year, to wit:</p>
<pb n="51" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>In the county of Atascosa, beginning on the first Mondays in May and November, and to continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Bexar, beginning on the first Monday in March and to continue in session eight weeks; on the first Monday in June, and to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tiue in session four weeks; on the first Monday in September, and to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session eight weeks; and on the first Monday in December, and to continue in session eight weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Comal, beginning on the third Mondays of May and November, and to continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All writs and process returnable to the said district courts as heretofore fixed shall be returnable to the several terms as fixed by this act, and shall be as valid and binding as if no change had been made.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. All laws and parts of laws heretofore enacted which conflict with any of the provisions of this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. And whereas the changes herein made of the times of hold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the district courts in the twenty-second judicial district would cause a conflict between the existing law and this act, should this act not take effect until ninety days after the adjournment of this session of the Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature, and the September term of the district court in the county of Bexar coming on prior to the expiration of the said ninety days, an emergency exists such as is contemplated by the constitution in such cases, and it is therefore enacted that this act take effect and be in force from and after the first day of August, 1879.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The short duration of the present session of the Legislature, and the vast amount of business before the same creates an imperative public necessity that the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be, in case of this act, suspended, and that the same be passed at once, and it is accordingly so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 5, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after first day of August.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend article 4653, chapter five, of title ninety-three of the Revised Civil Statutes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That article 4652, chapter 5 of title 93 of the Revised Civil Statutes shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 4652. Whenever any person shall be about to drive or ship any stock out of the state, if the inspector shall believe, or is informed by any credible person that said person has other stock in his herd than those covered by his original certificate of inspection, or by subsequent purchase duly attested by proper bill of sale, the inspector at said point of shipment or border county where said person leaves the state, shall be authorized to inspect said stock in the same manner as in the original inspection; and if any stock is found in said herd other than those covered by his original certificate of inspection, or by subsequent purchase duly and properly authenticated by bill of sale, the fees of said inspector shall be paid as provided in article 4635 of this chapter; provided, that the said inspector shall in no case be authorized to receive or demand more than three cents per head for each head of cattle inspected, but if not, then said fees shall be paid by the person at whose instance said inspec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion was made; and if said inspection is made by the inspector, at his<pb n="52" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>own instance, and no stock is found in said herd except those properly accounted for under the provisions of this article, then said inspector shall receive no fees for said inspection.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that the present session of the Legislature is near its close, and the further fact that the cattle drive from this state to the north is now upon us, creates an imperative public necessity and emer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gency for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days and for the immediate passage of this act; therefore said rule is suspended, and this act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 5, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend article 3888, chapter five, title seventy-nine, of the Revised Civil Statutes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That article 3888, chapter five, title seventy-nine of the Revised Civil Statutes, shall be amended to read hereafter as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 3888. Whenever the field notes of a survey have been re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turned to the general land office, and upon examination the same are found to be in conflict with previous claims, it shall be lawful for the rightful claimant of the certificate, so located in conflict, to file his affi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />davit with the commissioner, setting forth that the certificate was not intentionally so located in conflict, but that he believed at the date of such location that the land covered thereby was vacant and unappropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated public domain; to abandon said survey and surrender all claim thereto by reason of the file, entry and survey made by him, and to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive from the commissioner a copy of the certificate on which the same was based, if such certificate be valid and genuine; and it shall be the duty of the commissioner to indorse upon the said copy that the original certificate is floated, and the county where the land is situated which is covered by such floated certificate, and that the copy is given in lieu of the original, but without any prejudice to the rights of any person by virtue of said certificate, and that the said copy may be located upon any unappropriated or vacant land.&#8221;</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 5, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to validate the titles to land reserved from location or patent at the time titles issued thereto.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Harrassing and vexatious litigation is likely to arise that may result in dispossessing many of the people of the state of their lands acquired in good faith, on account of patents having been issued thereto at the time reservations existed, withholding the same from such appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation, there exists an urgent public necessity for a law giving imme<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diate security and protection to such titles; and it is therefore enacted that this law go into effect from and after its passage.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the titles to all lands already patented by virtue of any genuine land certificate or other legal evidence of claim to land be and the same<pb n="53" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>are hereby validated, notwithstanding the existence of any reservation at the time the same were either located or patented.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. There is reserved and excepted from the operation of this law all conflicting vested rights that have accrued before the passage of this law; provided, that this act shall not apply to reservations which under the constitution or existing laws of this state revert to the state for public free schools upon forfeiture of grants or failure of the conditions of the reservation, nor to locations or patents made or issued upon alter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nate sections surveyed for the state within said reservations.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The near approach of the close of the session creates an im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perative public necessity, that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 5, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend the first section of &#8220;an act pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribing the times of holding the district courts of the second judicial district.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section one of the above recited act be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 1. That the district courts of the second judicial district shall be holden at the times hereinafter specified, to wit: In the county of Rusk, on the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session six weeks; in the county of Panola, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session four weeks; in the county of Shelby, on the tenth Mondays after the first Mondays in January and July, and may continue in session three weeks; in the county of Harrison, on the sixteenth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in January and July, and may continue in session until the busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness is disposed of.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas, the near approach of the adjournment of the present session of the Legislature, and the necessity for the passage of this bill creates an emergency and public necessity for the suspension of the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house so that this bill take effect and be in force from and after its pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age, therefore said rule is hereby suspended and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July, 8, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to diminish the civil and criminal juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction of the county courts of Erath, Comanche, Eastland, Red River, Palo Pinto, Stephens, Throckmorton, Taylor, Callahan, Panola, Cass and Bowie counties, and conform the jurisdiction of the district courts of said counties to such change.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the county courts of Erath, Comanche, Eastland, Red River, Palo Pinto, Stephens, Throckmorton, Taylor, Callahan, Panola, Cass and Bowie counties shall have and exercise the general jurisdiction of pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="54" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>bate courts, shall probate wills, appoint guardians of minors, idiots, lu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />natics, persons non compos mentis and common drunkards, grant letters testamentary and of administration, settle accounts of executors, adminis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trators and guardians, transact all business appertaining to the estates of deceased persons, minors, idiots, lunatics, persons non compos mentis and common drunkards, including the partition settlement and distribu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of estates of deceased persons, and to apprentice minors as prescribed by law, and to issue all writs necessary to the enforcement of their ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />risdiction, and to punish contempts under such provisions as are or may be provided by general law governing county courts throughout the state; but said county courts shall have no other jurisdiction, civil or criminal.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the district courts of said counties shall have and exer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cise jurisdiction in all matters and causes, civil and criminal, over which by the general laws of the State the county courts of said counties would have jurisdiction except as provided in section one of this act, and that all cases other than probate matters and such as are provided in sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion one of this act be and the same are hereby transferred to the district courts of said counties, and all writs and process, civil and criminal, here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tofore issued by or out of said county court, other than those per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining to matters over which by section one of this act jurisdiction is given to the county courts of said counties, be and the same are hereby made returnable to the next term of the district courts in and for said counties.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the clerks of the county courts of the counties afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said be and they are hereby required, within twenty days after the pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age of this act, to make a full and complete transcript of all the entries on their dockets, civil and criminal, heretofore made in causes which by section two of this act are transferred to the district courts of said coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties, and file the same, together with all original paper of all said causes and proceedings, with the clerks of the district courts of said counties; and all such causes shall immediately be docketed by the clerks of the district courts of said counties, and shall stand on the dockets of said courts as appearance causes for the next term of said courts; and for each of said transcripts the county clerk shall receive twenty cents per one hundred words, and fifty cents for certificate thereto, to be taxed as cost against the party cast in the suit, if a civil suit, and if criminal, against the defendant, if convicted; provided, the change of civil jurisdiction provided for in this act shall not apply to Red River county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Whereas, the immediate operation of the provisions of this act will save the counties herein named a large and unnecessary expense, and thereby an emergency exists which justifies that this act take effect thirty days after its passage, and it is so enacted. And whereas, the time is short which remains to this session, and there is a large amount of legislative business pending, creates an imperative public necessity which authorizes the suspension of the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days, and said rule is so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 8, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect thirty days after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="55" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend article 3962, chapter ten, title seventy-nine of the Revised Statutes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That article 3962, chapter ten, title seventy-nine of the Revised Statutes shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 3962. The commissioner of the general land office is author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized and required to patent surveys in the order in which they may be made ready for patenting without regard to the order of filing in the general land office or the order of application; provided, that when appli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation is made for patent on any claim and the office fees therefor have been paid, such claim shall have preference over claims for which no application has been made; provided, such surveys shall have been regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />larly mapped, or there be sufficient evidence that no previous survey has been legally filed in the land office covering the same ground as repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sented on the maps of the office.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the large amount of revenue to be secured to the state by this act and the near approach of the close of this extra session creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, be suspended, and it is therefore so suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 8, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to provide for the sale of the alternate sections of land in organized counties, as surveyed by railroad com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />panies and other works of internal improvement and set apart for the benefit of the common school fund; to provide for the investment of the proceeds, and to repeal all laws in conflict therewith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the alternate sections of land in organized counties heretofore surveyed, or which may be hereafter surveyed by any railroad company or other work of internal improvement and set apart for the benefit of common schools, shall be brought into market and disposed of in the manner hereinafter provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The county surveyor of the county in which said lands are located shall view and appraise the same, under oath, and make return of the same to the county commissioners&#8217; court, which court shall exam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ine, approve or disapprove of the same, and may take other evidence to ascertain the true value of the land, and, in case of disapproval, said court shall fix a value thereto, and the valuation of said lands, in no case, shall be less than one dollar per acre. County surveyors acting as ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />praisers of lands in their respective counties shall each receive the sum of one dollar per section, and in no event to exceed fifty dollars for the appraisement of all the lands in any one county, to be paid out of the proceeds of the first sales of the land under the provisions of this act. Any person having improvements upon any of such lands, prior to the taking effect of this act, shall have the preference in the purchase thereof<pb n="56" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>for the period of six months next after taking effect hereof, at the valua<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion exclusive of the value of such improvements.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That as soon as the appraisement is completed, the county commissioners&#8217; court shall prepare tabulated reports of their action, set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ting forth the following, viz: Number of survey, block, quantity in each survey, name of company or individual to whom the certificate was granted, price per acre of each section or quarter thereof, if differences exist, value of improvements, remarks giving general description of soil and water. One copy of the above report shall be filed in the office of the county surveyor, and shall constitute an archive of his office. One copy shall be forwarded to the commissioner of the general land office, and one copy to the treasurer of the state.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That upon the receipt of the above report by the commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the general land office, he shall examine the same, and if made in conformity with this act he shall notify the county surveyor of the fact; and until he receives such notice the surveyor shall not entertain any proposition for the purchase of said land.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That so soon as the surveyor shall receive the notice provided for in section four of this act, he shall be authorized to receive applica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for the purchase of said lands in any quantity not less than one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and sixty acres, except fractions of less than one hundred and sixty acres that may now exist in said counties, provided, that one person or corporation shall not be allowed to purchase more than one section of said land when the same is classed as arable land suitable for farming purposes; but when the same is classed as land suitable only for grazing purposes, it shall be sold in quantities to suit the purchaser, but no per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son shall be permitted to purchase less than one hundred and sixty acres nor more than three sections.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That any person desiring to purchase any of the above lands shall make application in writing to the county surveyor, designating the number of the survey, block, name of company or individual to whom the certificate, by virtue of which such survey was made, was issued, the quantity he or she wishes to purchase, and, if less than a whole sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, the particular part of such section; provided, that no fraction of any section of less than one hundred and sixty acres shall be left by any such selection, and that no fractional section of less than three hundred and twenty acres shall be divided. The surveyor shall be entitled to a fee of one dollar for each application, to be paid by the applicant; and he shall, upon payment of said fee, record said application in a well bound book to be kept by him for that purpose; he shall endorse such appli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation &#8220;Recorded,&#8221; giving the date, page and volume of the record, and sign his name thereto, and deliver said application to the proposed pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chaser.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the purchaser shall immediately forward to the state treasurer the above application, together with one-tenth of the appraised value of the land therein designated; provided, that one-fourth of the purchase money shall be paid in advance on all lands valuable only for the timber thereon. The treasurer shall enter a credit on his books in the name of the purchaser for the amount so received, giving such description of the land as will identify the same. He shall then issue his receipt for said amount and forward it, with the above named application, to the commissioner of the general land office, who shall file said appli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation and receipt in his office, and issue his certificate in lieu thereof, setting forth the amount paid to the treasurer and the quantity and<pb n="57" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>valuation of the land applied for; which certificate shall authorize the county surveyor to survey the land embraced in the original application, and to enter the same on his books as sold, and he shall not entertain another application to purchase said lands until notified of their for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />feiture as hereinafter specified; provided, that should the applicant fail to make his first payment of one-tenth of the appraised value of the land embraced in his application to the treasurer, and present the certificate of the commissioner of the general land office to the surveyor or his deputy within ninety days from the date of the record of his applica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, then and in that case the said land shall be again for sale and the surveyor shall be authorized to receive application for the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That so soon as the application above named has been received by the surveyor, the applicant shall execute his obligation or promissory note for the balance of the appraised value of the land he desires to pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase, agreeing and stipulating to pay to the governor of the State of Texas and his successors in office, on the first day of January of each year, one-tenth of the amount of his obligation or promissory note, with ten per cent. interest on such amount of the principal as may be due at the date of each payment, giving in said obligation such description of the land purchased as is contained in his application; provided, that the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chaser may have the privilege of paying the entire amount of the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />praised value of such land at the date of purchase, or such amount of principal and interest as may be due at any time subsequent to the execu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of his obligation or promissory note; provided, that any payment of principal may be deferred for one or more years, except the first one<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tenth or one-fourth, but all payments of both principal and interest must be paid inside of ten years, and all interest must be paid annually on or before the first day of March of each year. Where any land sold under the provisions of this act shall be timbered land, no person shall have the right to cut and remove any of the timber therefrom for the purpose of selling the same until the purchase money for said land has been paid in full.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the note or obligation so executed by the purchaser, shall be forwarded to the commissioner of the general land office, and he shall have the same registered in a well bound book kept for that purpose, setting forth the name of the purchaser, the amount and date of the obligation or note, the tract or tracts for which it is given, and the county in which situated; and shall then endorse the same &#8220;Registered,&#8221; with the date of such registry, sign his name thereto, and deliver the same to the treasurer of the state who shall carefully file the same in his office.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That upon presentation of the certificate of the commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the general land office provided for in section seven of this act, to the surveyor or his deputy, the said surveyor shall immediately proceed to survey the land embraced in the original application of the purchaser; he shall record the field notes of such survey or surveys in his office and forward the same, duly certified, to the commissioner of the general land office, who shall file the same with the application and treasurer&#8217;s receipt of said purchaser. For the surveying and recording herein provided for, the surveyor shall be entitled to the legal fees pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided by law, to be paid by the purchaser; provided, that when the field notes are on file in the general land office, the applicant shall not be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to have the same surveyed.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the commissioner of the general land office shall pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="58" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>cure a well bound book in which shall be kept an account with the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chaser of said lands, showing the amount for which the original obliga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion was given and the interest accruing thereon; and it shall be the duty of the state treasurer, upon the payment of the amount due by any purchaser of these lands, to execute his receipt for the same in the name of the purchaser, and deliver said receipt to the commissioner of the general land office, who shall credit the account of said purchaser with the amount so paid, and forward his certificate of such payment to the purchaser.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. If, upon the first day of March following the maturity of any payment, the interest on money due has not been paid to the state treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, and his receipt filed with the commissioner of the general land of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fice, as provided in section eleven of this act, it shall be the duty of said commissioner to notify the county or district attorney of the county in which such land is situated of such failure, giving the name of the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chaser so failing to make payment, with the amount and date of his note, and the amount of principal and interest due at the time of such fail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ure; and upon the receipt of such notice it shall be the duty of the county or district attorney to cause a writ to be issued and served on the purchaser, or, in case of his death, upon his heirs or legal representatives, requiring him or them to show cause why he or they should not be ejected from such land; and upon his or their failure to show that the annual installments of interest have been paid, as above provided, a judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment shall be rendered against him or them, and a writ of possession shall be issued in favor of the state. That a copy of such judgment, un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der the signature and seal of the clerk of the court rendering the judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment, shall be forwarded to the state treasurer, who shall immediately indorse the obligation of such purchaser &#8220;forfeited,&#8221; note the fact of such endorsement on the copy of judgment aforesaid, and forward the same to the commissioner of the general land office. The said commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner shall file said copy of judgment with the claim of such defaulting purchaser, and shall note such forfeiture on the account kept with said purchaser, and shall notify the surveyor of the county in which said land is situated that said land is again for sale.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That such forfeited tracts shall be sold in the same manner as hereinbefore provided for the original sale of such lands; provided, however, that any improvements on said land shall be paid for by the purchaser, and the value of said improvements shall be assessed by the board of appraisers hereinbefore provided for, or such other persons as the governor may designate, when the same proceedings may be had as provided in this act for the original appraisement and purchase.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That should any purchaser die before the payment of any one installment, and interest thereon falls due, his administrator, execu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tor or heirs shall have an extension of twelve months within which to pay the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That in case any purchaser desires to sell said land after he has made his first payment on the same, he may do so, but in that event his vendee shall file in the general land office a properly authenticated transfer from said purchaser, and said vendee shall be liable to the obli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gations and penalties imposed upon said original purchaser; and upon final and full payment on any purchase made under the provisions of this act, the commissioner of the general land office shall issue a patent to the purchaser making the same, or to his vendee or heirs; provided,<pb n="59" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>no one patent so issued shall include more than one section of land, nor portions of any two sections.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Said lands shall be subject to taxation from the date of the first payment into the treasury of the state.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That the proceeds arising from the sale of these lands shall be paid into the common school funds; the principal to be invested in United States or state bonds, and the interest arising therefrom shall be applied to the use of common schools.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. The commissioner of the general land office and the attorney general shall prescribe such minute details as may be necessary to carry out the objects of this act, and necessary instructions to surveyors and appraisers.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict herewith are hereby repealed; provided, nothing herein contained shall effect the rights or obligations of purchasers of these lands under former laws.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. That whereas, the present session of the Legislature is so near final adjournment, and the existing law would operate almost to the destruction of the school fund and entail unreasonable expense upon the state, an emergency exists for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house, and said rule is hereby suspended, and as a public necessity requires that this act should take effect and be in force from and after its passage, it is there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 8, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend &#8220;an act to authorize the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor, attorney general and superintendent of the penitentiary to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tract for conveying convicts from the places where sentenced to the <sup>penitentiary," approved April 22, 1879.</sup></salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section two of the above recited act be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 2. That the operation of all laws concerning the transpor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tation of convicts be and the same are hereby declared to be suspended during the existence of any such contract as that provided in the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceding section, and the governor shall by proclamation give notice for the making of such contract, and a copy of such proclamation shall be forwarded by the secretary of state to each sheriff in the state, and each sheriff shall, after the issuance of said proclamation, upon demand, deliver to the order of the party contracting with the state, all convicts, together with a copy of the decree of the court before which said convict or con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />victs were tried, convicted and sentenced, taking and filing among the papers in his office a receipt therefor. When a contract is made according to the terms of this act, the contractors shall enter into a bond in the sum of twenty thousand dollars, payable to the governor and his successors in office, with two or more securities, to be approved by said board, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ditioned that said contractor will faithfully and fully carry out and comply with said contract; provided, that should the person making such contract fail or refuse to call on the sheriff of any county for any convicts where the place of confinement of the prisoner or prisoners is<pb n="60" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>within fifteen miles of a point having railroad connection with the peni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tentiary, within seven days, or where the place of confinement of the prisoner or prisoners in (is) not less than fifteen nor more than sixty miles from a point having railroad connection with the penitentiary within ten days, or where the place of confinement of the prisoner or prisoners is not less than sixty nor more than one hundred and fifty miles from a point hav9ing railroad connection with the penitentiary within fifteen days, or where the place of confinement of the prisoner or prisoners is not less than one hundred and fifty miles from a point having railroad connection with the penitentiary within twenty days after the adjournment of the court in which said convict or convicts were tried, then the sheriff shall proceed at once to convey such convicts to the penitentiary as though no such contract had been entered into; and when he does so convey convicts to the penitentiary, he shall receive such compensation for so doing as he would be allowed by law if no con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tract existed; the same to be paid by such contractor upon the delivery of such convict by the sheriff inside the walls of the penitentiary, and should such contractor fail or refuse to pay the sheriff it shall be the duty of the comptroller to draw his warrant for the amount due in favor of the sheriff on the appropriation to carry out the contract, and the same shall be paid out of said appropriation and deducted from the moneys paid such contractor for conveying convicts to the penitentiary.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that a contract is already made for carrying convicts to the penitentiary, creates an imperative public necessity that this bill go into immediate effect and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 8, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to reorganize the tenth judicial district of this state, to fix the times of holding the terms of the district courts therein, and attaching certain counties to the county of Wheeler for judicial purposes and for purposes of organization.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the counties of Cooke, Denton, Wise, Archer, Wichita, Clay, Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tague and Wheeler be and the same are hereby constituted the tenth judicial district.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the district courts in the counties comprising the tenth judicial district shall be holden as follows: In the county of Cooke, on the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session six weeks; in the county of Denton, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session six weeks; in the county of Wise, on the twelfth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session four weeks; in the county of Archer, on the sixteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Wichita, on the seventeenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Clay, on the eighteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Montague, on the twentieth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session three weeks; in the<pb n="61" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>county of Wheeler, on the twenty-fourth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in February and August, and may continue in session until the busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the unorganized counties of Childress, Hall, Briscoe, Swisher, Castro, Parmer, Deaf Smith, Randall, Armstrong, Donley, Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lingsworth, Gray, Carson, Potter, Oldham, Hartley, Moore, Hutchison, Roberts, Hemphill, Lipscomb, Ochiltree, Hansford, Sherman, Dallam and Greer are hereby attached to Wheeler county for judicial purposes and for purposes of organization.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The near approach of the close of the present session of this Legislature creates an imperative public necessity for the suspension of the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days, and said rule is therefore so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 8, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act defining the manner in which lands sold at tax sales, to individuals, may be redeemed by the owner.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any person having the right to redeem any land sold at tax sale may do so by payment, within the time prescribed by law, to the col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lector of taxes of the county in which the said land was sold of the amount which the law requires to be paid; provided, that the owner of said land, or his agent, shall first have made affidavit before some officer authorized by law to administer oaths, that he has made diligent search in the county where said land is situated for the purchaser thereof at the tax sale, and has failed to find him; or that the purchaser at such tax sale is not a resident of the county in which the land is situated, or that he and the purchaser cannot agree on the amount of redemption money. In such cases only shall the owner or agent be authorized to redeem the same by the payment to the collector of taxes.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. It shall be the duty of any collector of taxes, to whom pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment is made under the provisions of this act, to give a receipt therefor, signed by him officially, in the presence of two witnesses, which said receipt, when duly recorded, shall be notice to all persons that the land therein described has been redeemed; and the collector of taxes shall, on demand, pay over to the purchaser at said tax sale the money thus received by him.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The fact that the time given for redemption in tax sales for the year 1877 expires in a few weeks, whereby many parties may suffer by litigation and otherwise if no speedy remedy is provided, creates such a public necessity and emergency as to justify the suspension of the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days; therefore, said rule is suspended, and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 8, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="62" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to exempt from taxation horse racing when run over a distance of four hundred and forty yards.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all laws and parts of laws which impose a tax on the privilege of running a horse race over a distance of four hundred and forty yards, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that the existing law tends to discourage the trial of the of speed horses at the approaching fairs and agricultural associa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity that the rule should be suspended which requires bills to be read on three several days, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 8, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to repeal &#8220;an act to provide for the record of contracts relating to land in a manner that will distinguish com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />munity from separate property," approved April 21, 1879.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That an act entitled &#8220;An act to provide for the record of contracts relating to land in a manner that mil distinguish community from separ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate property,&#8221; approved April 21, 1879, be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The confusion and injustice that will be occasioned by the existence of the law repealed by this act, creates an emergency for its immediate repeal, and it is therefore enacted that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage; and from the late hour of the session an imperative public necessity exists that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is therefore so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to create a commission of arbitration and award and define the powers and duties thereof, and to make appropriation to pay the salaries of the judges thereof.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That a commission of arbitration and award to consist of three persons learned in the law, to be appointed by the governor, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, if in session, who shall hold their offices for two years from the date of their appointment and receive for their services the same salary as judges of the supreme court, be and the same is hereby created to be styled the &#8220;commissioners of appeals of the State of Texas.&#8221; In case of a vacancy on said commission by the death or res<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ignation of any member thereof, during a vacancy of the Legislature, it shall be the duty of the governor to fill the same by appointment, the<pb n="63" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>person appointed to continue in office until the nest session of the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature after the appointment.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said commission shall have the power to head and pronounce award upon all civil cases now or hereafter pending in the supreme court or the court of appeals, wherein the parties or their attorneys may file consent in writing to the reference thereof to said commission.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Said commission shall hold its sessions at the same times and places as the supreme court, and shall appoint one clerk if necessary, and if no such clerk be appointed, the duties of that office shall be per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formed by the clerks of the supreme court and of the court of appeals respectively, at the different branches thereof, who shall receive in either case the same fees as are allowed by law to the clerks of the supreme court for like services.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Said commission shall have a seal, being a star with five points and the words &#8220;Commissioners of Appeals of the State of Texas&#8221; around the same. Regular dockets and minutes of all proceedings by or before said commission shall be kept, and the records and proceedings thereof shall be entitled to the same verity as are records and proceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings of courts of record, and all cases shall be docketed in the order of date of filing of written consent provided in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Said commission shall have the right to issue writs of certiorari to perfect the record and such process as the supreme court might issue to make parties, and shall have the power to punish for contempt.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. All laws and rules regulating the practice and procedure in the supreme court shall be of force in the practice and proceedings of said commission so far as the same are applicable, and all applications for re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hearing in cases referred to said commission shall be made before and determined by the commission.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Said commission shall reports its conclusions or award to the supreme court or court of appeals, as the case may be, in the cases so referred, and may accompany the same with a brief synopsis of the ease and their opinion thereon; and the conclusions or award aforesaid shall be and become the judgment of the said supreme court or the court of appeals aforesaid, and said courts shall make and render such further order, judgment or decree thereon as may be necessary or proper to make said award effective.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The opinions of said commission shall not be published in the reports of the decisions of the supreme court nor the court of appeals, nor shall the same have any further or other effect than to determine the particular cause wherein rendered, and shall have no force or effect or authority as precedent in other causes.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. And the sum of seventeen thousand seven hundred and fifty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />four dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated out of any moneys in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the payment of the salaries of the judges of said commission for the period ending first of March, 1881.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Whereas, the near approach of the close of the present session of this Legislature and the limited time allowed to legislation, and an imperative public necessity exists for the suspension of the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and it is hereby enacted that said rule is suspended, and the fact that the accu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mulation of business in the supreme court and in the court of appeals is so great as to prevent, in ordinary course, that speedy determination to litigation which is essential to justice, creates an emergency that requires<pb n="64" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>this act to take effect at once, and it is therefore enacted that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety clays after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act making provision for the return to the comptroller&#8217;s office, before the meeting of each regular session of the Legislature, of all sheriffs&#8217;, attorneys&#8217; or other valid claims against the state, for which warrants may not have been issued, so that correct estimates may be made of any deficiencies in the appropriations, and to provide against issuance of &#8220;O K&#8221; certificates.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all sheriffs, attorneys and all other parties holding claims against the State of Texas for which no warrants have been issued, and the appropriation for which has been exhausted, shall present the same to the comptroller of the State of Texas for his consideration at least thirty days before the meeting of each regular session of the Legislature of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The comptroller of the State of Texas is authorized and di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rected to audit no claims against the state not presented in the time prescribed in section one of this act, until all claims presented prior to that time have been considered and passed upon by him.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The comptroller of the State of Texas shall keep a book for the purpose of registering and indexing all audited claims against the state, and on the meeting of the regular session of the Legislature, shall make a minute report of the same to the two houses thereof, giving the names and amounts of all audited claims.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to define who are agents of insurance companies and to fix their liability for acting without authority of law.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any person who solicits insurance on behalf of any insurance com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, whether incorporated under the laws of this or any other state or foreign government, or who takes or transmits other than for himself any application for insurance or any policy of insurance to or from such company, or who advertises or otherwise gives notice that he will receive or transmit the same, or who shall receive or deliver a policy of insurance of any such company, or who shall examine or inspect any risk, or re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive, or collect, or transmit any premium of insurance, or make or for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ward any diagram of any building or buildings, or do or perform any other act or thing in the making or consummating of any contract of insurance for or with any such insurance company other than for himself, or who shall examine into, or adjust or aid in adjusting any loss for or on behalf of any such insurance company, whether any of such acts shall be done at the instance or request, or by the employment of such insurance<pb n="65" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>company, or of or by any broker or other person, shall be held to be the agent of the company for which the act is done, or the risk is taken, as far as relates to all the liabilities, duties, requirements and penalties set forth in this act; provided, that the provisions, of this act shall not apply to citizens of this state who arbitrate in the adjustment of losses between the insurers and the assured, nor to the adjustment of particular or gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral average losses of vessels or cargoes by marine adjusters who have paid an occupation tax of two hundred dollars for the year in which the adjustment is made; provided further, that the provisions of this act shall not apply to practicing attorneys-at-law in the State of Texas, acting in the regular transaction of their business as such attorneys-at-law, and who are not local agents, nor acting as adjusters for any insurance company.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any person who shall do or perform any of the acts or things mentioned in the preceding section for any insurance company hereinbefore referred to without such company having first complied with the requirements of the laws of this state, or having received the cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate of authority from the commissioner of insurance, statistics and history of the State of Texas, as required by law, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction by any court of competent jurisdiction for the first offense be fined five hundred dollars, and also a sum equal to the state, county and municipal licenses required to be paid by such in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />surance company for doing business in this state, and shall be imprisoned in the county jail where the offense is committed, for the period of three months, unless the fine assessed against him and the sum of licenses herein mentioned, and the cost of the court be sooner paid, and for any second or other offense such person shall be fined in the sum of one thousand dollars, and shall be imprisoned in the county jail for the period of six months, unless the fine assessed against him and the cost of the court be sooner paid.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That whenever any person shall do or perform within this state any of the acts mentioned in the first section of this act, for or on behalf of any insurance company therein referred to, such company shall be held to be doing business in this state, and shall be subject to the same taxes, state, county and municipal, as insurance companies that have been legally qualified and admitted to do business in this state by agents of otherwise, are subject, the same to be assessed and collected as taxes are assessed and collected against such companies; and such persons so doing or performing any of such acts or things shall be personally liable for such taxes.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That any person who shall do any of the acts mentioned in the first section of this act, for or on behalf of any insurance company, without such company has first complied with the requirements of the laws of this state, shall be personally liable to the holder of any policy of insurance in respect of which such act was done for any loss covered by the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That all laws and parts of laws inconsistent with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That an imperative public emergency exists for the immedi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate passage of this act, and that the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that a necessity exists that this act take effect, from and after its passage that the interests of the state may be more fully protected, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="66" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act supplementary to and amendatory of an act entitled &#8220;an act to amend and supplement the existing quarantine laws of the State of Texas, title eighty-three of Revised Statutes, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved April 10, A. D. 1879,&#8221; and to repeal article 4096 of Revised Statutes, title eighty-three, and to make an appropriation therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it is hereby made the duty of the county courts of the several counties on the borders or coast of Texas, when required by the circular or proclamation of the governor, where there shall be no corporate town or city within such county requiring quarantine, to appoint competent quarantine guards or health officers at such place or places as may be designated by the governor; and should said duty be disregarded by the officers of such counties, then it shall be the duty of the governor to appoint such guards or quarantine officers, and whenever any local board fails or refuses to carry out an effective system of quarantine, the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor is authorized and required to enforce the same in such manner as may be necessary; said guards and health officers shall receive such pay, and in such manner as is provided for in section two of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whenever the governor appoints any health or quarantine officers or guards, as provided for in article 4092, title 83 of the Revised Civil Statutes, such officer or officers or guards shall be paid not more than one hundred dollars per month, whilst on duty, for such services; said amount per month shall be approved by the state health officer and the governor, and when so approved, the comptroller shall draw his war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant on the treasurer for the amount so approved in the name of the party performing said quarantine services.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That article 4090k, of an act entitled &#8220;An act to amend and supplement the existing quarantine laws of the State of Texas, title 83 of the Revised Statutes,&#8221; approved April 10, A. D. 1879, shall hereafter read as follows: &#8220;It shall be the duty of the quarantine officer of the state, county or city authorities, as the case may be, to furnish persons detained by them at quarantine stations with subsistance and shelter, not includ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the crews of vessels, except such as are removed by the quarantine officers; and said subsistence account, and all contracts for the construc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of quarantine stations and wharves, and hire or purchase of boats or vessels accepted by the state health officer and the governor, and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived by them after completion, and all accounts for the same and for all other expenses shall be approved by the governor, and when so ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved the comptroller shall draw his warrant upon the treasurer in favor of the same for the amount specified;&#8221; and article 4096 of the Revised Statutes, title 83, is hereby repealed, and the sum of seven thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated, in addition to the appropriation made at the regular session of the Six<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth Legislature, out of any moneys in the treasury not otherwise ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated, for the erection and construction of the necessary buildings, wharves, etc., for quarantine purposes; provided, that said moneys as well as the sum of five thousand dollars appropriated for like purposes at the regular session of the Sixteenth Legislature, be used at the follow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing points and places; Brazos Santiago, Corpus Christi, Galveston, In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dianola, Sabine Pass, Orange, Denison, Texarkana and Marshall.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The near approach of the close of this session creates an im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perative public necessity that the rule requiring a bill to be read on three several days be suspended, and therefore it is so suspended; and<pb n="67" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the necessity to make effective the quarantine proclamation of the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor requires this bill to take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act supplementary to an act entitled &#8220;an act to provide for the organization of the state penitentiaries, and to regulate the management of the convicts therein,&#8221; approved March 24, 1879.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the governor shall appoint by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, when in session, one additional assistant superintendent of the state penitentiaries, who shall hold his office during the term of the governor, unless sooner discharged by the governor, who shall perform such duties and have such powers as are required of and authorized by the assistant superintendent in the act entitled &#8220;An act to provide for the organization of the state penitentiaries, and to regulate the management of the convicts therein, approved March 24, 1879,&#8221; and said assistant superintendent shall receive the same salary and emoluments as fixed by said act for the assistant superintendent.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The additional assistant superintendent, together with the present assistant superintendent, shall divide the convict camps or places where convicts are employed into two divisions, and assign one assistant superintendent to each of said divisions; and said officers shall visit such camps or places where convicts are employed at least twice in each month and examine into and report to the governor all complaints preferred by convicts or by citizens, which may have been substantiated by satisfac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tory evidence, and they may exchange districts with each other in their discretion.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Said assistant superintendents snail make reports of the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dition of the convicts, their names and how treated and clothed, etc., in their respective divisions, as is now required by law of the assistant superintendent.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. It shall be the duty of the superintendent and assistant super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />intendent to have all convicts who may die while in custody, decently buried, and have each grave marked by a board with a suitable inscrip<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, giving the name of the convict, what county he resided in, the date of his death, and his age, if known.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The importance of the immediate passage of this bill, there being now only one assistant superintendent, and the welfare of the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />victs and the interests of the state requiring one more such officer, and the fact that this session of the Legislature is limited to thirty days and the greater portion of the time having already expired, creates an emer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gency and an imperative public necessity for the immediate taking effect of this act, and for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several [days]; and it is therefore enacted, that said rule is suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="68" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to provide for the sale, exchange or de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction of useless or injured property belonging to the state.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of insurance, statistics and history, the state treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer and the comptroller of public accounts be and they are hereby consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tuted a board to inspect and condemn for sale, exchange or destruction, such useless or injured property belonging to or controlled by either of the executive departments, state institutions or state boards, as to the majority of said board may be deemed proper for such disposition.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said board shall, immediately upon the taking effect, of this act, enter upon the performance of the duties herein prescribed, and shall keep a record of all its proceedings, which shall be kept and deposited in the office of the comptroller of public accounts; and the financial operations of said board shall be included in the annual reports of said officer. The proceeds arising from the sale or exchange of prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty described in the preceding section shall be, by said board, disposed of as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>First&#8212;all property acquired by exchange shall be delivered to the officer in charge of and used for the benefit of the department or institu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion from which the effects may have been taken that were used in mak<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the said exchange. Second&#8212;all money realized from the sale of property received from either of the state institutions or state boards, shall be deposited in the state treasury to the credit of such institution or board furnishing the same, and shall be deemed a part of the fund for its support, during the current fiscal year, and shall be subject to the control of and disbursement by such institution or board. Third&#8212;all money re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alized from the sale of surplus cord-wood or other surplus of property on hand, purchased by either house of the Legislature, and from property re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived from any of the executive departments of the state, shall be depos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ited in the state treasury to the credit of the fund for the preservation and improvement of public buildings and grounds; and shall be used for the benefit and preservation of the same by the officer having supervision thereof, and subject to disbursement upon his certificate for labor per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formed or material furnished.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. All laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. There being no law in force for the rescue or preservation of public property contemplated by this act, an imperative public necessity and emergency exists for the passage of this act, it is therefore ordered that the rule be suspended, and it is enacted that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend an act to amend article 4759 of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, adopted on the 21st day of February, 1879, approved April 22, 1879, and to add article 4759a, article 4759b, article 4759c.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Tesas, That article 4759 of the above recited act be amended as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 4759. Should the collector of taxes fail to make sale of any real estate for want of a purchaser, he shall bid the same off for the state<pb n="69" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>for the taxes and penalties due and all costs accruing thereon, and exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cute a deed to the state; and one deed shall include all tracts of land bid off to the state at such tax sale, and make due return thereof, under such forms and directions as the comptroller may furnish and direct; and after sale and purchase by the state of any real estate, it shall not be lawful for said collector to levy upon or advertise or sell the same for any remaining or accrued taxes due thereon until the same shall have been redeemed by the owner or is sold by the state. Said collector shall, on final settlement of his accounts with the commissioners&#8217; conrt, and the comptroller of public accounts, be entitled to a credit for the amount of taxes due the state and county, respectively, for which the land and lots were bid off to the state.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 4759a. That the owner, or his agent, of any lands that may have been conveyed to the state under the provisions of the foregoing article, desiring to redeem the same, may do so by depositing with the collector of the county in which the lands were sold, double the amount of the purchase money, and all accrued taxes thereon within two years from the date of the deed to the state, and it shall be the duty of such collector to execute a receipt to such owner, or agents, giving therein the amount of money received, and a description of the land so as to identify the same, and sign and seal the same officially, and upon presentation of such receipt to the comptroller of public accounts, he shall execute to the owner a relinquishment under his signature and seal of office, which may be admitted to record in like manner with other conveyances of land.</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 4759b. In case said land shall not, have been redeemed as pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided in article 4759a, then the same may be sold as provided by an act entitled &#8216;An act to provide for the sale of all real estate bid off to the state by collectors of taxes at tax sales, the owners of which have not redeemed the same,&#8217; approved April 7, 1879.</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 4759c. All laws and parts of laws in conflict with, the fore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />going articles are hereby repealed, and particularly &#8216;An act to amend sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion twenty-one of an act regulating the duties of tax collectors in refer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence to the seizure and sale of property of delinquent taxpayers, and to define the further duties, powers, qualifications and liabilities of collectors of taxes and to regulate their compensation, approved August 21, 1876,&#8217; approved April 19, 1879, be and the same are hereby repealed.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas, the near approach of the close of this, session of the Legislature and the limited time for legislation, create an imperative public necessity authorizing the suspension of the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days, and said rule is suspended, and the im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />portance to the state of the legislation afforded by this act creates an emergency that this act should go into effect at once; therefore, this act shall take effect, and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize the governor, comptroller and attorney general of the state to purchase additional lands for the use of penitentiaries, and to make an appropriation therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the governor, comptroller and attorney general, when they deem it to the interest of the state, are authorized and empowered to purchase or exchange adjacent state lands for additional lots or parcels of lands<pb n="70" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>for the use and benefit of one or both of the penitentiaries of the state, and the sum of five hundred dollars, or so much thereof as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary, to be paid out of the moneys received from the lessees of the peni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tentiary, be and the same is hereby appropriated to carry this act into effect; provided, they shall make no contract which involves the payment of a larger amount than that herein specified.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that we are near the close of this session of the Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature, and the great necessity for the organization of the penitentiaries, create an imperative public necessity and emergency that the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is so enacted, and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend article 1333 of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, passed at the regular session of the Sixteenth Legislature, as amended by the. act amendatory thereof, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved April 19, 1879.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That article 1333 of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, as amended by the act amendatory thereof, approved April 19, 1879, be amended so that said article shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 1333. The jury shall render a general or special verdict as may be directed by the court, and the verdict shall comprehend the whole issue or all the issues submitted to them; and upon a trial by the court, the judge shall, at the request of either of the parties, also state in writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the conclusions of fact found by him separately from the conclusions of law, which conclusions of fact and law shall be filed with the clerk and shall constitute a part of the record; and in all cases where a special ver<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dict of the jury is rendered, or the conclusions of fact found by the judge are separately stated, the court shall, unless the same be set aside, and new trial granted, render judgment thereon, and it shall be sufficient for the party excepting to the conclusions of law or judgment of the court, to cause it to be noted on the record in the judgment entry that he excepts thereto; and such party may thereupon take his appeal or writ of error without a statement of facts or further exceptions in the transcript, but the transcript shall in such case contain the special verdict or conclusions of fact and law aforesaid and the judgment rendered thereon.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that the passage of this act will facilitate the admin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />istration of justice, and the certainty of an early adjournment of the Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature renders it doubtful whether this bill can be read on three several days; it is therefore enacted that the constitutional rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days be suspended and it is so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="71" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to provide for the assessment of sleeping, dining-room, palace and parlor cars assigned upon the railroads of this state, and to prescribe the method for levying and collecting the tax hereby imposed upon the same, and to repeal all former laws in conflict therewith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any person, firm, company or corporation, owning or using in this state, sleeping, dining-room, palace or parlor cars, and run over the rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />roads therein, shall, in person or by their agent, report to the comptroller of this state, on or before the first day of January of each and every year, the number and valuation of sleeping, dining-room, palace or parlor cars so owned or assigned in this state at the time of said report. Said report of the number and value of said cars to be made under oath and to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain a clause to the effect that none of said cars have been temporarily withdrawn from said state before the date of said report, on the first day of January of each year, so as to avoid taxation. And in default of the person, firm, company or corporation making such report within thirty days after the time herein required to be made by themselves or agents, that the said comptroller is hereby empowered to make such assessment of the number and value thereof for the purpose of taxation; provided, that no greater number of cars shall be taxed than that number which shall be regularly or usually in the state.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That there shall be levied and collected an annual direct ad valorem tax of one-half of one per cent. upon the value of the sleeping, dining-room, palace or parlor cars at the time of said assessment, in lieu of all other taxes upon said property, to be paid by said persons, firm, company or corporation to the comptroller of public accounts, on or be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore the first day of July in each and every year, and in default of such payment, the comptroller shall proceed to collect the same under the laws now in force for the collection of taxes; and the taxes herein imposed shall be and remain in lieu upon all the property of such persons, firm, company or corporation found in this state, and the comptroller is hereby empowered and directed to issue process upon the failure of such person, firm, company or corporation to pay the said tax, within the time herein specified, to the tax collector of any county in this state, in which the property of such persons, firm, company or corporation may be found, for purpose of enforcing the collection of the taxes herein imposed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That within thirty days after this act shall have taken effect, the persons, firm, company or corporation liable to tax under the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceding sections, shall make report of the cars and their value, as herein<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />before provided, to the comptroller of this state, and shall pay the ad valorem tax of one-half of one per cent. hereby imposed upon the same, on or before the first day of January thereafter, subject to the same penalties for default as provided for in the second section of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Should the comptroller and the persons, firm, company or corporations liable to tax under the provisions of this act, their agents or attorneys, fail to agree as to the valuation which shall be made of the property taxed hereunder, then they shall each select one disinterested person to make a valuation of such property. Should the two persons so selected fail to agree upon a valuation to be made, then they shall select a third disinterested person to act with them, and the valuation made by such persons so selected shall be accepted by all parties and the property rendered thereat.</p>
<pb n="72" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 5. That all former laws imposing and levying any occupation taxes upon the property enumerated in this act for the purposes of state or county taxes, and all laws and parts of laws in conflict with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The near approach of the close of the present session of the Legislature, and the fact that the state should not delay any legislation that would enforce the collection of the taxes for the present year upon the property enumerated in this act, creates an imperative public neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity and an emergency for the suspension of the constitutional rule re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quiring this bill to be read on three several days, and for the immediate passage of this act said rule is therefore suspended, and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9. A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend chapter three, title fifteen of the Code of Criminal Procedure of the State of Texas, passed at the first session of the Sixteenth Legislature in the year 1879, by creating arti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cles 1075 and 1076 thereof, relating to costs paid by counties.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That chapter three, title fifteen of the Code of Criminal Procedure of the State of Texas, passed at the first session of the Sixteenth Legislature in the year 1879, shall be so amended that it shall contain articles 1075 and 1076, and so that said articles shall read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 1075. There shall be paid to the county judge, by the county, the sum of three dollars for each criminal action tried and finally dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed of before him.</p>
<p>Article 1076. The county judge shall present to the commissioners court of his county, at a regular term thereof, an account in writing, specifying each criminal action in which he claims the fee allowed by the preceding article, which account shall be certified to be correct by such judge, and the same shall be filed with the clerk of the county court. The commissioners&#8217; court shall approve such account for such amount as they may find to be correct, and order a draft to be issued upon the county treasurer in favor of such judge for the amount so approved.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the end of the session, and the fact that there is no provision in the law providing fees for county judges, creates an imperative public necessity and emergency that the rules requiring this bill to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is hereby suspended, and that this act take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to prescribe what character of buildings shall be erected and what articles shall be manufactured at the East Texas Penitentiary at Rusk.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the &#8220;East Texas penitentiary board&#8221; in contracting for the build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of workshops and other improvements necessary and proper to put<pb n="73" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the East Texas penitentiary into operation, shall cause such improvements to be made and buildings to be erected as will, in its judgment, furnish employment for the largest number of convicts practicable, with ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chinery and tools which can be purchased and had without an extrava<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gant outlay of money, and need not provide for the manufacture of iron exclusively, but shall provide for smelting and casting iron, and may pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vide for more extensive iron works, if, after experiment, it shall be found advisable.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the obscurity of the law relating to this subject creates an imperative public necessity that the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is suspended, and that this act take effect from its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend article 1057, 1058, and 1059 of the Code of Criminal Procedure of the State of Texas, adopted at the regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lar session of the Sixteenth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That articles 1057, 1058 and 1059 respectively of the Code of Criminal Procedure of the State of Texas, passed and adopted at the regular session of the Sixteenth Legislature, be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 1057. Before the close of each term of the district court, the district or county attorney, sheriff and clerk of said court shall each make out a bill or account of the costs claimed to be due them by the state respectively in the felony cases tried at that term; the bill or account shall show&#8212;</p>
<p>&#8220;1. The style and number of the case in which the costs are claimed to have accrued.</p>
<p>&#8220;2. The offense charged against the defendant.</p>
<p>&#8220;3. The term of the court at which the case was disposed of.</p>
<p>&#8220;4. The disposition of the case and that the case was finally disposed of and no appeal taken.</p>
<p>&#8220;5. The name and number of defendants, and if more than one whether they were tried jointly or separately.</p>
<p>&#8220;6. Where each defendant was arrested, or witness served, stating the county in which the service was made, giving distance and direction from county seat of county in which the process is served, and mileage shall be charged for distance by the most direct and practicable route from the court whence such process issued to the place of service.</p>
<p>&#8220;7. In allowing mileage the judge shall ascertain whether the process was served on one or more of the parties named therein on the same tour, and shall allow mileage only for the number of miles actually traveled, and then only for the journey made at the time the service was perfected.</p>
<p>&#8220;8. The court shall inquire whether there have been several prosecu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions for an offense or transaction that is but one offense in law, and if there is more than one prosecution for the same transaction or a portion thereof that could have been combined in one indictment against the same defendant, the judge shall allow fees to sheriffs, clerks and district and county attorneys in but one prosecution.</p>
<pb n="74" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>&#8220;9. Where the defendants in a case have severed on the trial, the judge shall not allow the charges for service of process and mileage to be duplicated in each case as tried, but, only such additional fees shall be allowed as are caused by the severance.</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 1058. It shall be the duty of the district judge when any such bill is presented to him to examine the same carefully and to inquire into the correctness thereof, and approve the same in whole or part, or to disapprove the entire bill as the facts and law may require; and such bill, with the action of the judge thereon, shall be entered on the minutes of said court; and immediately on the rising of said court it shall be the duty of the clerk thereof to make a certified copy from the minutes of said court of said bill and the action of the judge thereon, and transmit the same by mail in registered letter to the comptroller of public accounts.</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 1059. It shall be the duty of the comptroller upon the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceipt of such claim and said certified copy of the minutes of said court, to closely and carefully examine the same, and if correct to draw his war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant on the state treasurer for the amount due in favor of the officer en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to the same; provided, that if the appropriation for paying such accounts is exhausted, the comptroller shall file the same away, if correct, and issue a certificate in the name of the officer entitled to the same, stating therein the amount of the claim and character of the service per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formed. And all such claims or accounts not transmitted to, or placed on file in the office of the comptroller of public accounts within six months from the date of the final disposition of the case in which the services were rendered, shall be forever barred.&#8221;</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act defining the boundary lines of Montague county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That article 860 of the Revised Civil Statutes, adopted by the Sixteenth Legislature, February...., 1879, shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Beginning sis miles west of the northeast corner of Wise county; thence west with the north line of Wise and Jack counties to a point four miles west of the northeast corner of Jack county; thence due north to Red river; thence down said river with its meanders to a point due north of the beginning; thence due south, to the place of beginning.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict with the above entitled act are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The near approach of the close of the session creates a public imperative necessity that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days should be suspended, and it is so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="75" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to prescribe the remedy and regulate the proceedings by quo warranto, and confer the jurisdiction in certain cases upon the district court of Travis county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That, in case any person shall usurp, intrude into, or unlawfully hold or execute, or is now intruded into, or now unlawfully holds or executes any office or franchise, or any office in any corporation created by the authority of this state, or any public officer shall have done or suffered any act which by the provisions of law works a forfeiture of his office, or any association or number of persons shall act within this state as a cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration without being legally incorporated, or any incorporation does or omits any act which amounts to a surrender or a forfeiture of its rights and privileges as a corporation, or exercises powers not conferred by law, or if any railroad company doing business in this state shall charge an extortionate rate for the transportation of any freight or passengers, or refuse to draw or carry the cars of any other railroad company over its line as required by the laws of this state, the attorney general, or district or county attorney, of the proper county or district, either of his own accord or at the instance of any individual relator, may present a peti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to the district court of the proper county, or any judge thereof, in vacation, for leave to file an information in the nature of a quo warranto, in the name of the State of Texas; and if such court or judge shall be satisfied that there is probable ground for the proceeding, the court or judge may grant the petition and order the information to be filed and process to issue.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. When it appears to the court or judge that the several rights of divers parties to the same office or franchise may properly be deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mined on one information, the court or judge may give leave to join all such persons in the same information in order to try their respective rights to such office or franchise.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. When the information is filed, as hereinbefore provided, the clerk shall issuer citation in like form as in civil suits commanding the defendent to appear at the return time of said court to answer the relator in an information in the nature of a quo warranto. If the information is filed in vacation the citation shall be returnable on the first day of the next succeeding term; if in term time it may be made returnable on any day of the same term, not less than five days after the date of the writ, as shall be directed by the court.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Every person or corporation who shall be cited as hereinbefore provided shall be entitled to all the rights in the trial and investigation of the matters alleged against him, as in cases of trial of civil causes in this state; and in case of appeal to the supreme court, to which either party shall be entitled, the said court shall give preference to such case and hear and determine the same at the earliest day practicable; and all such appeals shall be prosecuted to the term of the court in session, at either branch, or the first term to he held, if not in session, after judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment has been rendered in the district court.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. In case any person or corporation against whom any such is filed shall be adjudged guilty, as charged in the information, the court shall give judgment of ouster against such person or corporation from the office or franchise, and may fine such person or corporation for usurp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, intruding into or unlawfully holding and executing such office or<pb n="76" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>franchise, and shall also give judgment in favor of the relator for the costs of the prosecution.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The remedy and mode of procedure hereby prescribed shall be construed to be cumulative of any now existing.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Suits against persons illegally claiming or holding any state office or appointment as contradistinguished to a county or district office, shall be brought in the district court of Travis county.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Whereas, this session of the Legislature must adjourn in less than three days from this date, therefore there exists an imperative pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic necessity for the passage of this act to supply a defect now existing in the laws of this state; it is therefore enacted that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act supplemental to and amendatory of an act entitled &#8220;An act to make an appropriation for the support, of the state government for the years beginning March 1, 1879, and ending Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 28, 1881,&#8221; approved April 23, 1879.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following sums of money, or so much thereof as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary, be and the same are hereby appropriated out of any money not otherwise appropriated for the periods hereinafter stated, viz: For the support of the public free schools for the years ending August 31, 1880 and 1881, one-sixth of all the ad valorem and occupation taxes that may be collected, exclusive of the cost of collection; all the annual poll tax levied for school purposes, exclusive of the cost of collection, and all the interest on the permanent school fund, including bonds and other inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est-bearing indebtedness, now or hereafter belonging to said permanent school fund.</p>
<figure xml:id="fig1">
<graphic url="images/0076_001.jpg"/>
</figure>
<pb n="77" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<figure xml:id="fig2">
<graphic url="images/0077_001.jpg"/>
</figure>
<pb n="78" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<figure xml:id="fig3">
<graphic url="images/0078_001.jpg"/>
</figure>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the close of the present session of the Legislature, and the fact that a portion of the interest provided for in this bill falls due in July, 1879, creates an imperative public necessity and emergency for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days and for the immediate passage of this act, said rule is therefore suspended, and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER L.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to regulate the advertisement of sales of lands for taxes dues thereon, and of lands that have been sold for taxes and purchased by the state, and to repeal so much of article 4752 of the Revised Civil Statutes of Texas, adopted by the Sixteenth Legislature of the State of Texas at the first session thereof, and so much of sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion three of &#8220;An act to provide for the sale of all real estate bid off to the state by collectors of taxes at tax sales, the owners of which have not redeemed the same,&#8221; as are or may be in conflict with the provi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions of this act.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That prior to the sale of any real property for taxes in any county in this state the collector of taxes shall advertise the same by posting a list of the names of the delinquents for thirty days as follows: One copy at the court house door of the county and a copy at two other public places in the county where the lands or lots are situated.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That so much of the above recited acts, sections and articles and all laws and parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act, and all laws requiring collectors of taxes to advertise in newspapers any tax sales, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Whereas, the end of the session is near at hand and the law as it now exists requires impossibilities of collectors of taxes and retards the collection of the state revenues; therefore, an emergency exists, and an imperative public necessity demands that the constitutional rule requiring<pb n="79" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>a bill to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend &#8220;An act to provide for the incorpor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ation of associations that may be organized for the purpose of con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structing railways, maintaining and operating the same, for prescrib<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and defining the duties and limiting the powers of such corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions when so organized,&#8221; approved August 15, 1876.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section thirty-one of &#8220;An act to provide for the incorporation of associations that may be organized for the purpose of constructing rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ways, maintaining and operating the same, for prescribing and defining the duties and limiting the powers of such corporations when so organ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized,&#8221; approved August 15, 1876, be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 31. If any railway corporation; organized under this act, shall not, within two years after its articles of association shall be filed and recorded as provided in the second section of this act, begin the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction of its road and construct, equip aud put in good running order at least ten miles of its proposed road; and if any such railroad corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, after the first two years, shall fail to to construct, equip and put in good running order at least twenty additional miles of its road, each and every succeeding year, until the entire completion of its line, such corpor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ation shall, in either of such cases, forfeit its corporate existence, and its powers shall cease as far as relates to that portion of said road then un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />finished, and shall be incapable of resumption by any subsequent act of incorporation; provided, that any railroad company heretofore organized under the act to which this is an amendment, which shall, previous to the taking effect of this amendment, have graded as much as ten miles of its road-bed, shall have an additional time of twelve months from, the day of the passage of this amended act to construct, equip and put in good running order at least ten miles of its proposed road, as re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired in the section herein amended; and any such company may then and thereafter proceed to construct twenty miles of its proposed road each and every succeeding year after the lapse of the additional period of twelve months hereby given, and shall not, in such case, forfeit its cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate existence or any of the powers or privileges conferred by said act or any other law of this state.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That article 4278 of chapter thirteen of the Revised Statute&#8217;s be and the same is hereby repealed, in so far as it conflicts with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The tact that the present extra session of the Sixteenth Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature is limited to thirty days, and a good portion of the same having been exhausted, and the great interests involved in the provisions of this act, create an emergency and necessity for the immediate taking effect of the same; and it is therefore enacted that it be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 14, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="80" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to provide for the sale of a portion of the un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />appropriated public lands of the State of Texas, and the investment of the proceeds of such sale.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the vacant and unappropriated land situated in the following named counties, viz: Noland, Mitchell, Howard, Martin, Andrews, Gaines, Davidson [Dawson?], Borden, Scurry, Fisher, Stonewall, Kent, Garza, Lynn, Terry, Yoakum, Cockran, Hockley, Lubbock, Crosby, Dickens, King, Cottle, Motley, Floyd, Hale, Lamb, Bailey, Parmer, Castro, Swish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />er, Briscoe, Hall, Childress, Collingsworth, Donley, Armstrong, Randall, Deaf Smith, Oldham, Potter, Cordova, Gray, Wheeler, Hemphill, Roberts, Hutchins, Moore, Hartley, Davidson [Dawson?], Sherman, Hansford, Ochiltree and Lipscomb be and the same is hereby appropriated and set apart for sale, together with all the unappropriated lands situated and being within and included in the Pacific reservation, and together with such separate tracts of unappropriated public lands, situated in organized counties of this state, as contain not more than six hundred and forty acres; provided, that the three million and fifty thousand acres, hereto<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore appropriated for the building of a state capitol, shall have a prefer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence right of location in the counties heretofore reserved for that pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose. The provisions of this act shall not be so construed as to prohibit the right of pre-empting within the bounds of the reservation here made; but any party shall have the same right of acquiring a homestead, within this reservation, under the pre-emption laws of this state, as he may have had prior to the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any person, firm or corporation, desiring to purchase any of the unappropriated lands herein set apart and reserved for sale, may do so by causing the tract or tracts which such person, firm or cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration desire to purchase to be surveyed by the authorized public sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyor of the county or district in which said land is situated.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. It shall be the duty of the surveyor, to Thom, application is made by responsible parties, to survey the lands designated in said ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plication within three months from the date thereof, and within sixty days after said survey, to certify to, record and map the field-notes of said survey; and he shall also, within the said sixty days, return to and file the same in the general land office, as required by law in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Surveyors shall be entitled to receive from applicants for the purchase of lands under the authority of this act all legal surveyor&#8217;s fees for work done by them.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Within sixty days after the return to and filing in the general land office of the surveyor&#8217;s certificate, map and field notes of the land desired to be purchased, it shall be the right of the person, firm or cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration who has had the same surveyed to pay or cause to be paid into the treasury of the state the purchase money therefor at the rate of fifty cents per acre, and upon the presentation to the commissioner of the general land office of the receipt of the state treasurer for such purchase money, said commissioner shall issue to said person, firm or corporation a patent for the tract or tracts of land so surveyed and paid for.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. No tract of land shall be sold under the provisions of this act that contains more than six hundred and forty acres, and no tract shall have a greater frontage on any running stream, or permanent water, than one vara per acre for each survey of three hundred and twenty acres, or less, and three-fourth of one vara per acre for all other surveys.</p>
<pb n="81" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="49" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 7. It shall be the duty of the commissioner of the general land office to give such general and specific instructions to surveyors in relation to the surveying of the public lands, under the provisions of this act, as may best subserve the interests of the state, and carry into force and effect the intent and purposes of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. After the survey of any of the public domain authorized by this act, it shall not be lawful for any person to file or locate upon the land so surveyed, and such file or location shall be utterly null and void.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. Should any applicant for the purchase of public land fail, refuse or neglect to pay for the same, at the rate of fifty cents per acre within the time prescribed in section 5 of this act, he shall forfeit all right thereto, and shall not thereafter be allowed to purchase the same, but the land so surveyed may be sold by the commissioner of the general land office to any other person, firm or corporation, who shall pay into the treasury the purchase money therefor.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. One-half of the net proceeds of sales under the provisions of this act, shall be and are hereby set apart for the benefit of the public free schools of this state, and the comptroller of public accounts shall, under and by direction of the governor, invest the same in interest-bear<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing bonds of the State of Texas, or if said bonds are not to be obtained, then in interest-bearing bonds of the United States, the interest there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />from to be paid into the treasury as part of the available school fund. The balance of the net proceeds of sales under the provisions of this act shall be applied by the proper authorities to the payment and extinguishment of the bonded debt of the State of Texas as the same becomes due and payable. No surveys shall be made in any of the counties set aside for the state capitol, and in which said lands may be selected, until after the surveys of the three million and fifty thousand acres set aside for the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction of a new state capitol have been surveyed.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Whereas, the close of the present session of the Legislature is near at hand, an imperative public necessity exists that the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days be sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended, and it is therefore so enacted; and whereas, the unappropriated lands of the state are being rapidly taken up, a public emergency exists that this act take effect from and after its passage, it is therefore so en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />acted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 14, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend article 3785, chapter three, title seventy-eight of the Revised Civil Statutes, passed at the regular ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of the Sixteenth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That article 3785 of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, as mentioned in the caption of this act, be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Article 3785. If at an election held for that purpose, at which none hut property taxpayers, as shown by the last assessment rolls, who are qualified voters of such city or town, shall vote, two-thirds of those voting shall vote in favor thereof, such an amount shall be raised by taxation not to exceed one-half of one per cent. in addition to the pro rata of the available school fund received from the state, as may be necessary to conduct the schools for ten months in the year."</p>
<pb n="82" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="50" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas, the present session of the Legislature is near its close, and as some cities desire to immediately hold an election as con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />templated in this act, an emergency and imperative public nece sity exists that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>NOTE.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the governor of Texas for his approval on the ninth day of July, 1879, and was neither approved by him nor returned to the House in which it originated with his objec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions thereto, within the time prescribed by the constitution, and there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />upon became a law without his signature, July 17, 1879.</p>
<closer>
<signed>(Signed) JOHN D. TEMPLETON, Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAW.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend the charter of the city of Dallas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section three of the charter of the city of Dallas be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 3. The municipal government of the city of Dallas shall consist of a city council composed of the mayor and of two aldermen from each ward. A majority of the aldermen elect shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, except at called meetings, or meetings for the imposition of taxes, when two-thirds of a full board shall be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired. The other officers of the corporation shall be a secretary, a treasurer, an assessor and collector, a city attorney, a city engineer and city marshal, and such other officers and agents as the city council may from time to time direct. The aldermen, mayor, city marshal, and the assessor and collector shall be elected by the qualified electors of the city of Dallas, as now provided for by the city charter. A city secretary, city attorney, treasurer and city engineer shall be elected by the city council at its first regular meeting in May, 1880, and every two years thereafter.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That section fifty-eight of same charter be amended by the addition of the following words: &#8220;Whenever the city council, as pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided by charter, shall fix the compensation to be paid any officer, whether elected by the people or the council, they shall make the same a salary payable monthly out of the city treasury, and no officer shall be allowed any fees or perquisites of office, but all costs and penalties shall go into the general fund, No officer&#8217;s salary shall be fixed at a sum to exceed one hundred dollars per month, except the salary of assessor and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lector, which shall not exceed three thousand dollars per annum.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That section ninety-nine (99) of the charter of said city shall be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 99. All persons or corporations owning or holding personal property or real estate on the first day of any calendar year, shall be<pb n="83" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="51" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>liable for all municipal taxes levied thereon for the fiscal year beginning the April next following said January.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That section one hundred (100) of the charter of said city be amended by the addition at its close of the following words:</p>
<p>&#8220;Whenever any person or corporation fails to render his or its prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty for taxation, or whenever any property is not rendered by the owner, his agent or attorney, the assessor and collector shall assess the same at its cash value, and if the owner is not known then it shall be assessed to unknown owners.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That section 119 of said charter be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 119. The taxes on all personal property and all poll taxes shall be due and payable on demand, as soon as the levy of taxes is made by the city council, and it shall be and is hereby made the duty of the assessor and collector, by virtue of his rolls, to seize upon and sell per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal property sufficient to pay such taxes if the same is not paid on demand.</p>
<p>&#8220;When the assessor and collector distrains and seizes upon such prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty, he shall keep the same at the expense of the owner until sale is made, and shall give notice of the time and place of sale of the same by posting a written notice at the court house door in the city of Dallas and one other public place; the notice to be given at least ten days before the day of sale. He shall sell the same to the highest bidder for cash for all taxes, interest and costs, and expenses in caring for said property, and shall make an entry in the book of sales of the amount realized.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That sections one hundred and thirty-five and one hundred and thirty-six of said charter be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Whenever any real property is hid off to the city for delinquent taxes, or to any individual, the owner, his agent or attorney, may redeem the same at any time within two years from date of sale by paying the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing amounts: All taxes paid or due, ten per cent. interest per annum on said amount of taxes from the time they became delinquent, and two and one-half dollars ($2 50) as costs on each piece of property sold, and, as a further penalty, a sum equal to twenty-five per cent. of the amount of the delinquent tax if redeemed in three months; fifty per cent. penalty if redeemed in six months; seventy-five per cent. penalty if redeemed in one year; and one hundred per cent. penalty if redeemed thereafter with in two years; the said penalty to go to the purchaser at tax sale, whether said purchaser be the city or an individual. The assessor and collector shall in no case be entitled to any fees or costs because of delinquent taxes, but all charges and penalties shall go into the city treasury. When<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever any property is hid in at the tax sale by the city or an individual an entry shall be made in the book of sales; provided further, that all property heretofore sold for delinquent taxes and purchased by the city, may be redeemed by the owner, his agent or attorney, on or before the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />piration of two years from the time of sale of said property, and not thereafter, but in no case shall any forfeiture of said property be had be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore January 1, 1880.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That section one hundred and sixty-five of the said charter of said city be amended by the addition of the following clause: &#8220;The city council may at any time advance money out of the general fund to procure right of way for opening a street, said money to be returned to the general fund out of the special tax fund whenever collected.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The near approach of the end of the present session creates an<pb n="84" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="52" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>imperative public necessity that the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days to be suspended, and the same is hereby suspended; and the fact that the time is near at hand for the collection of the city taxes of said city, and the further fact that the present bill reduces greatly the expenses incidental to the collection thereof, and changes the pay of certain officers of said city, creates an emergency that this act go into effect immediately; therefore, this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<p>No. 1.&#8212;Joint Resolution authorizing the state librarian to turn over to the Agricultural and Mechanical College of Texas specimens of min<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral and other geological specimens in the geological department in said library in certain cases, and copies of all public documents of the state, published for distribution, and all apparatus belonging to the old geological survey.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the state librarian be and he is hereby authorized and required to turn over to the Agricultural and Mechanical College of Texas the dupli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate specimens in the hands of the agent of the International railroad company of all minerals and other geological specimens in the geological department in said library, and copies of all public documents of the state published for distribution, and apparatus belonging to the old geological survey, for the use and benefit ofsaid college.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said librarian be required to take an inventory or all specimens thus turned over to said college by him, and file the same in his office.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The near approach of the close of this session of the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture, and the pressing need of geological specimens at said college for the better instruction of its pupils, create an imperative public necessity for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring this resolution to be read on three several days; therefore, be it further resolved, that the constitutional rule be suspended and this resolution take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 9, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
<p>THE STATE OF TEXAS, <lb/>D<smcap>EPARTMENT OF</smcap> S<smcap>TATE</smcap>.</p>
<p>I, John D. Templeton, secretary of state of the State of Texas, do hereby certify that the laws contained in this volume are true and cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rect copies of the enrolled bills now on file in this department. I further certify that the special session of the Sixteenth Legislature, convened at the city of Austin on the tenth day of June, A. D. 1879, and adjourned on the ninth day of July, A. D. 1879.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I hereto sign my name and affix the seal of the State of Texas, at Austin, on this the twenty-fifth <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L. S.]</p></body></floatingText>day of July, A. D. 1879.</p>
<closer>
<signed>JOHN D. TEMPLETON, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="85" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="53" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO GENERAL LAWS.</head>
<p>Accounts&#8212;for which there are no appropriations, to be presented to comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller, when..... 32</p>
<p>Advertisement&#8212; of sales of land for taxes, regulated..... 46</p>
<p>Agricultural and Mechanical College&#8212;to receive from state librarian cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain geological and mineral specimens..... 53</p>
<p>Agents&#8212;who are for insurance companies..... 32-3</p>
<p>Alternate Sections of Land&#8212;to be sold and funds invested, how..... 23</p>
<p>Appropriations&#8212;for mileage and per diem of extra session Sixteenth Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature..... 1</p>
<p>for contingent expenses of extra session of the Sixteenth Legislature.. 1</p>
<p>to pay interest on the public debt and to pay the sinking fund..... 3</p>
<p>to pay salaries of commissioners of appeals..... 31</p>
<p>for quarantine purposes..... 34</p>
<p>supplemental, for support of state government from March I, 1879, to February 28, 1881..... 44</p>
<p>for purchasing additional land for penitentiaries..... 38</p>
<p>Arbitration, Commissioners of&#8212;act creating office of..... 30</p>
<p>powers and duties of..... 30</p>
<p>where sessions are to be held..... 31</p>
<p>to appoint a clerk..... 31</p>
<p>shall have a seal..... 31</p>
<p>salaries..... 31</p>
<p>Armstrong County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Archer County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 28</p>
<p>Atascosa County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 19</p>
<p>Attorney General&#8212;duty of, in reference to judgments in favor of the state.. 10</p>
<p>Bexar County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 19</p>
<p>Board&#8212;to dispose of useless property, who compose..... 36</p>
<p>to purchase land for penitentiaries, who compose..... 37</p>
<p>of veterans, pay of..... 46</p>
<p>to dispose of judgments in favor of state, who compose..... 10</p>
<p>Bonds&#8212;coupon, in state treasury to credit of certain funds to be changed into manuscript registered bonds..... 16</p>
<p>certain, to be burned..... 16</p>
<p>Bowie County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 3</p>
<p>jurisdiction of county court of diminished..... 21</p>
<p>Briscoe County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 21</p>
<p>Callahan County&#8212;jurisdiction of county court of, diminished..... 21</p>
<p>Camp County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 3</p>
<p>Cars&#8212;sleeping, dining, etc., tax on..... 39</p>
<p>Carson County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Castro County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Cass County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 3 jurisdiction of county court of, diminished..... 21</p>
<p>Childress County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Cities and Towns&#8212;authorities or, to co-operate with commissioners&#8217; courts in reference to sanitary measures..... 9</p>
<p>justices and mayors or recorders to have concurrent jurisdiction in... 17</p>
<p>ordinances of, may not provide less penalty for offenses than is pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by statute..... 17</p>
<p>may vote tax for free schools..... 49</p>
<p>Clay County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 28</p>
<pb n="86" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="54" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Clerks&#8212;bill of costs, how made out..... 41</p>
<p>Code, Civil&#8212;article 1136, chapter 1, title 28, amended..... 12</p>
<p>act to provide for printing, etc., amended..... 17</p>
<p>article 4652, chapter 5, title 93, amended..... 19</p>
<p>article 3888, chapter 5, title 79, amended..... 20</p>
<p>article 3962, chapter 10, title 79, amended..... 23</p>
<p>article 4759, amended..... 36</p>
<p>articles 4759a, 4759b and 4759c, added..... 36</p>
<p>article 1333, amended..... 38</p>
<p>article 4752, repealed..... 46</p>
<p>article 4278 of chapter 13, repealed..... 47</p>
<p>article 3785, chapter 3, title 78, amended..... 49</p>
<p>Code, Penal&#8212;act to provide for printing, etc., amended..... 17</p>
<p>Code of Criminal Procedure&#8212;article 896, chapter 1, title 11, amended..... 17</p>
<p>act to provide for printing, amended..... 17</p>
<p>chapter 3, title 15 amended by adding articles 1075 and 1076...... 40</p>
<p>articles 1057, 1058 and 1059, amended..... 41</p>
<p>Collingsworth County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zation purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Comal County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 19</p>
<p>Commissioners&#8217; Courts&#8212;to co-operate with city authorities in reference to sanitary measures..... 9</p>
<p>to sell certain judgments in favor of counties..... 10</p>
<p>to examine delinquent list of taxes furnished by comptroller..... 10</p>
<p>duty of, with reference to sale of alternate sections of school land..... 23</p>
<p>Commissioner of Insurance&#8212;member of board, to sell useless state property.. 36</p>
<p>Commissioners of appeals&#8212;act creating office of..... 30</p>
<p>powers and duties of..... 31</p>
<p>when and where sessions are to be held..... 31</p>
<p>to appoint a clerk..... 31</p>
<p>seal..... 31</p>
<p>salaries..... 31</p>
<p>rules of practice in..... 31</p>
<p>judgments and decrees of, how enforced..... 31</p>
<p>appropriation for..... 31</p>
<p>Community property&#8212;act providing for record to distinguish, repealed.... 30</p>
<p>Comptroller&#8212;duty of, in reference to judgment in favor of state..... 10</p>
<p>to furnish to commissioners courts abstract of delinquent list of taxes.. 12</p>
<p>to countersign and register certain manuscript registered bonds..... 16</p>
<p>accounts, for which there are no appropriations, to be presented to, when 32</p>
<p>member of board to sell useless state property..... 36</p>
<p>Comanche County&#8212;jurisdiction of county court of, diminished..... 21</p>
<p>Convicts&#8212;act providing for contract for conveying, to penitentiary, amended. 27</p>
<p>County Judges&#8212;of certain counties may practice law..... 12</p>
<p>pay of, for each criminal action tried..... 40</p>
<p>County Courts&#8212;judgments rendered in certain, to be transferred to district courts..... 10</p>
<p>jurisdiction of, in certain counties diminished..... 21</p>
<p>to appoint health officer where there are no town or city authorities.... 34</p>
<p>Costs&#8212;of sheriffs, clerks and attorneys, what bill shall show..... 41</p>
<p>Cooke County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 28</p>
<p>Dallas County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 5</p>
<p>Dallas City&#8212;charter amended..... 51</p>
<p>Dallam County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Debt, (State bonded)&#8212;one-half of proceeds of sale of public land to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plied to extinguishment of..... 48</p>
<p>public, appropriation for interest and sinking fund..... 3-4</p>
<p>Deaf Smith County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organiza<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Denton County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 28</p>
<p>District&#8212;tenth judicial, reorganized..... 28</p>
<p>District Court&#8212;time of holding in fifth judicial district..... 3</p>
<p>time of holding in eleventh judicial district..... 5</p>
<p>time of holding in thirteenth judicial district..... 8</p>
<p>time of holding in twenty-second judicial district..... 18</p>
<p>time of holding in second judicial district..... 21</p>
<p>time of holding in tenth judicial district..... 28</p>
<pb n="87" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="55" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Donley County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Eastland County&#8212;jurisdiction of county court of, diminished..... 21</p>
<p>Ellis County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 5</p>
<p>Erath County&#8212;jurisdiction of county court of, diminished..... 21</p>
<p>Execution&#8212;property sold under, upon judgment in favor of state or county, act in relation to..... 9</p>
<p>Felony&#8212;tax collectors guilty of, for failing to pay over public moneys..... 6</p>
<p>Franchise&#8212;persons illegally holding or executing may be proceeded against by information in the nature of a quo warranto..... 43</p>
<p>Franklin County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 3</p>
<p>Freestone County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 8</p>
<p>Frontier Troops&#8212;pay of, equalized and regulated..... 11</p>
<p>Governor&#8212;to sign certain manuscript registered bonds..... 16</p>
<p>to appoint commissioners of appeals..... 30</p>
<p>to appoint assistant superintendent of the penitentiary..... 35</p>
<p>Gray County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Greer County&#8212;attached to wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Hall County&#8212;attached, to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Hansford County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Hartley County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Harrison-County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 21</p>
<p>Hemphill County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Horse Racing&#8212;over certain distance, exempt from taxation..... 30</p>
<p>Houston Normal School&#8212;act supplementary to act establishing..... 2</p>
<p>Huntsville&#8212;act supplementary to act establishing normal school at..... 2</p>
<p>Hutchison County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Inspector of Hides and Animals&#8212;when may reinspect stock, fees and by whom paid..... 19</p>
<p>Insurance Companies&#8212;act defining who are agents..... 32-3</p>
<p>penalty for persons to act as agents of, without authority..... 33</p>
<p>Jeopardy&#8212;twice in, for same offense..... 17</p>
<p>Judgments&#8212;to facilitate collection of, in favor of the state or any county thereof..... 9</p>
<p>attorney for state or county to buy in property..... 9</p>
<p>sale of, when can not be collected..... 9</p>
<p>by whom sold..... 9</p>
<p>rendered in county courts of certain counties to be transferred to dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict courts..... 10</p>
<p>Judges, County&#8212;of certain counties may practice law..... 12</p>
<p>pay of, for each criminal action tried..... 40</p>
<p>Judges, District&#8212;to examine bill of costs of clerks, sheriffs and county attor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />neys..... 42</p>
<p>Jurisdiction&#8212;justices and mayors, or recorders, to concurrent jurisdiction in cities and towns..... 17</p>
<p>of county courts of certain counties, diminished..... 21</p>
<p>of suits against persons illegally claiming or holding state office con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred on district court of Travis county..... 44</p>
<p>Justices of the Peace&#8212;to have concurrent jurisdiction with mayors or record<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers in cities and towns..... 17</p>
<p>Lands&#8212;reserved from location or patent, titles to, validated..... 20</p>
<p>patents to, may issue from land office without regard to order of filing.. 23</p>
<p>sold at tax sales to individuals, bow redeemed by owners..... 29</p>
<p>act relating to, in a manner to distinguish community property, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pealed...... 30</p>
<p>additional, for use of penitentiaries, may be purchased..... 37</p>
<p>regulating advertisement of sales of, for taxes..... 46</p>
<p>Lands, Public&#8212;portion of, to be sold where situated, and proceeds of sale, how applied..... 48</p>
<pb n="88" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="56" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Lands, Public Free School&#8212;act to provide for sale of alternate sections in or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganized counties..... 23</p>
<p>county surveyor to view and appraise..... 23</p>
<p>pay of surveyor..... 23</p>
<p>persons having improvements on, to have preference in purchase..... 23</p>
<p>quantity which one person may purchase...... 23</p>
<p>amount to be paid in cash..... 23</p>
<p>Land Office (Commissioner of)&#8212;may give copies of certificates in certain cases..... 20</p>
<p>may issue patents without regard to order of filing, when..... 23</p>
<p>duty of, with reference to sale of alternate sections of school land..... 23</p>
<p>to give instructions to surveyors in relation to surveying public lands.... 49</p>
<p>Land Certificates&#8212;when in conflict, commissioner of land office may give copy 20</p>
<p>Librarian, State&#8212;authorized to turn over to Agricultural and Mechanical College mineral and geological specimens..... 53</p>
<p>Limestone County&#8212;tune of holding court in..... 9</p>
<p>Lipscomb County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Marion County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 3</p>
<p>Mayors&#8212;and justices of the peace to have concurrent jurisdiction in cities and towns..... 17</p>
<p>Military Companies&#8212;pay of, equalized and regulated..... 11</p>
<p>Moore County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Montague County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 28</p>
<p>boundary lines of, defined..... 42</p>
<p>Morris County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 3</p>
<p>Navarro County&#8212;civil jurisdiction of county court of, diminished..... 7</p>
<p>time of holding court in..... 8</p>
<p>Normal Schools&#8212;act providing for, supplemented..... 3</p>
<p>Ochiltree County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Office&#8212;persons illegally holding may be proceeded against by quo warranto.. 43</p>
<p>&#8220;O K&#8221; Accounts&#8212;issuance of, prohibited..... 32</p>
<p>Oldham County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Palo Pinto County&#8212;jurisdiction of county court of, diminished..... 21</p>
<p>Panola County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 21</p>
<p>jurisdiction of county court of, diminished..... 21</p>
<p>Parmer County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Patents&#8212;certain, validated..... 20-1</p>
<p>issued in what order..... 23</p>
<p>Penitentiary&#8212;act providing for contract for conveying convicts to, amended. 27</p>
<p>act to provide for organization, amended..... 35</p>
<p>additional land for..... 37</p>
<p>what buildings may be erected, what goods manufactured at Rusk..... 40</p>
<p>Potter County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Property&#8212;sold under execution upon judgment in favor of state or county.. 9</p>
<p>useless property belonging to the state to be sold..... 36</p>
<p>Public Money&#8212;an act to provide for prompt payment of..... 5</p>
<p>Quarantine&#8212;laws amended..... 34</p>
<p>duty of county courts in violation to..... 34</p>
<p>quarantine officers and guards, pay of..... 34</p>
<p>accounts for quarantine service, how paid..... 34</p>
<p>Quo Warranto&#8212;proceedings by, regulated..... 43</p>
<p>Railways&#8212;act providing for incorporation of, amended..... 47</p>
<p>Railroads&#8212;tax on certain cars assigned upon..... 39</p>
<p>may be proceeded against for extortionate charges..... 43</p>
<p>time of certain, extended..... 47</p>
<p>Randall County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Red River County&#8212;jurisdiction of county court of, diminished..... 21</p>
<p>Reservations&#8212;patents to lands invalidated..... 20-1</p>
<p>Roberts County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Rusk County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 21</p>
<pb n="89" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="57" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Sanitary Regulations&#8212;improvements to promote..... 9</p>
<p>School, State formal&#8212;act supplementary to act establishing..... 3</p>
<p>School, Public Free&#8212;available rand of, defined..... 4</p>
<p>sale of alternate sections of land set apart for..... 23</p>
<p>one-half net proceeds of public land appropriated to..... 49</p>
<p>cities may vote tax for..... 49</p>
<p>Shelby County&#8212;time of holding court in 21</p>
<p>Sherman County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Sheriffs&#8212;bill of costs, how made out..... 41</p>
<p>shall present claims against the state to comptroller, when..... 32</p>
<p>Statutes, Revised Civil&#8212;article 1136, chapter 1, title 28, amended..... 12</p>
<p>article 4652, chapter 5, title 93, amended..... 19</p>
<p>article 3888, chapter 5, title 79, amended..... 20</p>
<p>article 3962, chapter 10, title 79, amended..... 23</p>
<p>article 4759, amended..... 36</p>
<p>articles 4759a, 4759b and 4759c added..... 36</p>
<p>article 1333, amended..... 38</p>
<p>article 4752, repealed..... 46</p>
<p>article 4273, chapter 13, repealed..... 47</p>
<p>article 3785, chapter 3, title 78, amended..... 49</p>
<p>act to provide for printing, amended..... 17</p>
<p>Stephens County&#8212;jurisdiction of county court of, diminished..... 21</p>
<p>Stock&#8212;when subject to reinspection..... 19</p>
<p>fees for inspecting, by whom paid..... 19</p>
<p>Swisher County&#8212;attached to Wheeler county for judicial and organization purposes..... 29</p>
<p>Surveyors, County&#8212;to appraise alternate sections of school lands and report to commissioners&#8217; court..... 23</p>
<p>Taxes&#8212;time for forced, collection of, in certain counties postponed..... 6</p>
<p>delinquent, act to enforce collection of..... 12</p>
<p>land sold for, to individuals, how redeemed by owner..... 29</p>
<p>on sleeping cars, etc...... 39</p>
<p>Taxation&#8212;horse racing over certain distance exempt from..... 30</p>
<p>Tax Collectors&#8212;act providing for prompt accounting for and payment of public moneys by..... 5</p>
<p>time in which money must be paid..... 5</p>
<p>notification to, how made guilty of felony for failure to comply with law..... 5</p>
<p>prosecutions of, to be conducted in Travis county..... 6</p>
<p>to post delinquent tax list at court house door..... 13</p>
<p>to sell property for delinquent taxes..... 13</p>
<p>duty of, when land sold for taxes has been redeemed..... 29</p>
<p>to bid in for the state real estate when he fails to sell for want of a pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chaser..... 36</p>
<p>Taylor County&#8212;jurisdiction of county court of, diminished..... 21</p>
<p>Throckmorton County&#8212;jurisdiction of county court of, diminished..... 21</p>
<p>Titles&#8212;to land reserved from location or patent, validated..... 20</p>
<p>Titus County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 3</p>
<p>Travis County&#8212;prosecutions against tax collectors to be conducted in..... 6</p>
<p>suits to be brought in, against persons illegally holding office..... 44</p>
<p>Treasurer, State&#8212;duty of, in reference to judgments in favor of state..... 10</p>
<p>to change certain coupon bonds into manuscript registered bonds..... 16</p>
<p>member of board to sell useless state property..... 36</p>
<p>Verdict&#8212;general or special, what it shall comprehend..... 38</p>
<p>Wise County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 28</p>
<p>Wichita County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 28</p>
<p>Wheeler County&#8212;time of holding court in..... 28</p>
<p>certain counties attached to..... 29</p>
<pb n="90" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="58" />
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
