<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="I" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>PASSED AT THE <lb/>REGULAR SESSION OF THE SIXTEENTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>CONVENED <lb/>AT THE CITY OF AUSTIN</head>
<byline>JANUARY 14<smcap>TH</smcap>, 1879, AND ADJOURNED APRIL 24<smcap>TH</smcap>, 1879.</byline>
<byline>BY AUTHORITY.</byline>
<byline>GALVESTON 1879</byline>
<pb n="2" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="II" />
<pb n="3" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<head type="sub">SPECIAL LAWS OF TEXAS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to legalize the sale of real estate which belonged to Stephens county, in and near the town of Breckenridge, Stephens county, Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Judge E. L. Walker, who was appointed by the proper au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority as commissioner to sell the real estate which belonged to Ste<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />phens county, located in and around the town of Breckenridge, did sell a portion of said lots and lands at private sale; and whereas, the general law of the state requires that all such sales be made at public auction; and whereas, it is deemed proper and expedient that every doubt as to the legality of the sale be removed; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all sales, transfers and conveyances of all lots, tracts or parcels of land in and near Breckenridge, in said county of Stephens, made by the said E. L. Walker, as commissioner for the sale of said real estate, be and the same are hereby legalized and declared to be as legal and valid as if they had been made in strict conformity to law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the county clerk of Stephens county be and he is hereby authorized to record a certified copy of this act in the books kept in his office for the record of deeds.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The great importance to the citizens of Breckenridge and vi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cinity that the titles to all of said real estate be at once settled, and the clouds on the titles of purchasers from the commissioner be removed, creates an imperative public necessity and emergency that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 24, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend section seventeen of &#8220;an act to incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate the Unit, Colorado and Santa Fe railway company, and to grant land in aid of the construction of the same," passed March 28, 1873.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section seventeen of the above recited act shall be amended so as to here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 17. That the organization of this company shall be perfected within six months from date of the passage of this act, and eighty miles<pb n="4" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of their said railroad shall be completed by the first day of March, 1880, and fifty miles each year thereafter or this charter shall be forfeited as to that portion not built.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March. 8, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize the county of Galveston to sell the shares of the capital stock of the Gulf, Colorado and Santa Fe railway company owned by said county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioners&#8217; court of Galveston county be and the same is hereby authorized and empowered to sell the shares of the capital stock of the Gulf, Colorado and Santa Fe railway company now owned by Galveston county, at public sale, at such times and places, in such manner as the said commissioners&#8217; court may deem for the best interest of said county and the inhabitants thereof; provided, that all sales of said stock shall be made at the door of the courthouse of Galveston county, in parcels of not more than five shares, to the highest bidder for cash; provided further, that the commissioners&#8217; court of Galveston county may sell said stock at private sale to such citizens of Galveston county and upon such terms as they may deem best for the interest of the county; but in case of private sale said commissioners&#8217; court shall require the purchaser or purchasers thereof to enter into a bond, payable to the county of Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston, in any sum not less than two hundred thousand dollars, condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned that such purchaser or purchasers shall construct, equip and put in running order a railroad from the present terminus (at Richmond) of the Gulf, Colorado and Santa Fe railway to Belton, Bell county, within the time required by the provisions of the charter of said railway company.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All money received from the sale of said stock shall be used in the purchase and redemption of the Galveston county Gulf, Colorado and Santa Fe railway stock bonds.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the commissioners&#8217; court of Galveston county shall have power to pass all orders necessary to carry out and give effect to the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Whereas, the Gulf, Colorado and Santa Fe railway company owes a large debt which is secured by a deed of trust under which all the property and franchises of said railway company is liable to be sold, and its stock thereby rendered valueless to said county, and an emergency exists that this act take effect from its passage; therefore, this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 8, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize the mayor and board of aldermen of the town of Waxahachie to transfer its stock in the Waxahachie Tap railroad.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the mayor and board of aldermen of the town of Waxahachie, in the state aforesaid, at a regular meeting of said board, be and are hereby<pb n="5" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>authorized and empowered to sell and transfer upon such terms and in such mode as to them may seem best for the interest of said town and the citizens thereof, all interest owned by said town as stock or right thereto, as well as all interest or right in or to shares of stock in the capital stock of the Waxahachie Tap railroad company.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas, a necessity exists for the immediate sale and transfer of the stock mentioned in the preceding section to advance the interests of said town, it is hereby declared to be a case of emergency, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 11, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to repeal an act entitled &#8220;an act to authorize and require all forced sales of real estate and sales of negroes made by executors and administrators in the county of Travis, to be made on Congress avenue, at the southeast corner of Block No. 70,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved November 28, 1857.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the above recited act be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 13, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to incorporate the Grand Lodge of Ancient Free and Accepted Masons, in and for the State of Texas, under and by the name and style of the Grand Lodge of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Ancient, Free and Accepted Masons in and for the State of Texas, now or hereafter acting under the jurisdiction of the Grand Lodge of Texas, be and are hereby incorporated under and by the name and style of &#8220;The Grand Lodge of Texas,&#8221; and by that name shall have and exer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cise corporate powers, and by that name shall have perpetual succession of officers and members; shall have a common seal, which may be changed at the pleasure of the Grand Lodge; shall have full power to take and ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire, hold and enjoy real and personal property; to sue for and recover all sum or sums of money or property of any description, and shall have the right to sell, alien and convey its property of all kinds, at its will and pleasure, and to incumber by mortgage with usual clauses, or such clauses as it pleases, any or all of its property in such manner as may be deemed expedient by the Grand Lodge, and shall in like manner have the right to borrow money and to execute its obligations therefor in such form as may be prescribed by the Grand Lodge, or that may be approved by said Grand Lodge when obligations have already issued by the said Grand Lodge.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all subordinate lodges heretofore chartered by the Grand Lodge of Texas, and now existing, and all lodges which may hereafter be chartered by said Grand Lodge, shall constitute and form parts and parcels of the Grand Lodge incorporated by this act, under the name or<pb n="6" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>names by which such subordinate lodges were or may be chartered; and such subordinate lodges shall have the right to sue and be sued by their corporate name, and shall have the right to acquire and hold real or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal property, and to sell or mortgage the same, but the power to sell or mortgage shall be subject to such conditions or prerequisites as may be from time to time established by said Grand Lodge, and no sale or mortgage shall be made except by the previously obtained consent of the Grand Lodge. Such subordinate lodges shall at all times be subject to the jurisdiction and control of said Grand Lodge, and subject, as hereto<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore, to have their charters revoked by said Grand Lodge. Upon the demise of any subordinate lodge, all property and rights existing in such lodge shall pass to and vest in the Grand Lodge, subject in its hands to the payment of all debts due by such subordinate lodge, but the Grand Lodge shall never be liable for any sum greater than the actual cash value of the effects of such subordinate lodge actually received by it or its authority.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act is declared to be a public general statute and shall as such be taken notice of by all courts and in all places.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The charter under which the Grand Lodge of Texas is now acting being defective, creates an imperative public necessity and emer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gency which requires that this act should be immediately passed, and to to take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 19, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend section two of the charter of the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration of Victoria, and to provide for certain changes caused thereby.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section two of the present charter of the corporation of Victoria be, and is hereby so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 2. That the bounds and limits of said town, and within which said corporation shall exercise lawful jurisdiction, shall include and comprehend the territory embraced within the metes and bounds now laid out and designated as the town proper of said town, and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinued within one mile square so known and designated as the town proper of the town of Victoria; provided, that all streets, alleys, roads or highways, as heretofore laid out or established within the territory relieved from the jurisdiction of the said corporation under this act, are declared to be so set apart for public use, and shall remain forever as so established; and provided further, that all lots or parcels of lots of land or subdivisions of the same which at the time of the passage of this act did belong to the said corporation of the town of Victoria, situated in said territory cut off under this act from the jurisdiction of the aforesaid corporation, shall remain the property of the said corporation of Vic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />toria; and provided further, that all taxes due prior to January 1, 1879, to said corporation from any person or property within the territory cut off from the jurisdiction as aforesaid, shall exist as claims against said per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons or property, and due to said corporation, and subject to collection as provided by the laws regulating the assessment and collection of taxes.&#8221;</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 19, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="7" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act authorizing and requiring the commissioner of the general land office to issue patents to certain lands granted to the Bayland Orphans&#8217; Home, situated on Galveston bay, Harris county, Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office be authorized and required to issue patents to the Bayland Orphans&#8217; Home, situated on Galveston bay, Harris county, Texas, to the amount of forty-eight thousand six hundred and thirty-five acres donated to said Bayland Orphans&#8217; Home by the act of the Legislature of 1873, in accordance with the field notes and plats of the subdivisions of such lands now on file in the general land office.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That so much of the act of the Legislature of 1873 as requires the patenting of said lands to said Bayland Orphans&#8217; Home in tracts of three hundred and twenty acres each be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Whereas, it is indispensable that this act take effect imme<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diately to prevent the dissolution of the Bayland Orphans&#8217; Home, an emergency exists, this act shall go into effect immediately after its pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age; owing to the fact that this session of the Legislature is near its close, there is an imperative public necessity requiring the reading of this bill for three several days be dispensed with.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 20, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Mrs. M. A. C. Wilson, widow of William F. Wilson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That headright land certificate number one thousand and forty-six, second class, for six hundred and forty acres, granted and issued to William F. Wilson, December 6, 1838, be and the same is hereby approved as a valid and subsisting claim against the state, and that the commissioner of the general land office do issue a patent thereupon when the same shall have been located, as for an unconditional certificate.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That bounty land warrant number five thousand and thirty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />one, for six hundred and forty acres of land, issued September 6, 1838, be and is hereby approved as a valid and subsisting claim against the state, and that the commissioner of the general land office do issue a pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent thereupon whenever the same shall have been located.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 22, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the heirs of Alexander S. Green, deceased, late of Brazoria county, State of Texas; and Matthew Dock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ery, now a citizen of Lavaca county, State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Alexander S. Green immigrated to the State of Texas in the year 1835, and served in the army of Texas nine months, from the first day of October, 1836, to the thirtieth day of June, 1837, for which he received a bounty land warrant, which is on file in the general land office,<pb n="8" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and did thereafter remain a good and law-abiding citizen of the Republic of Texas up to the time of his death, and did never receive the headright to which he was entitled by the laws of the Republic of Texas; now therefore.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office is hereby authorized and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to issue to the heirs of Alexander S. Green, deceased, a headright certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, to which he was enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled by the laws of the Republic of Texas;</p>
<p>And, whereas, Matthew Dockery, now a citizen of Lavaca county, State of Texas, immigrated to the State of Texas about the month of February, in the year 1837, and has continued to reside in the State of Texas ever since; that at the time of his immigration he was a single man, over the age of twenty-one years; that he married in the State of Texas, on the fourteenth day of June, 1838; that, under the laws of Texas in force at the time of his immigration, he was entitled as a single man to six hundred and forty acres of land, and also under the laws in force at the date of his marriage, he was entitled to six hundred and forty acres of land as a married man, making in all twelve hundred and eighty acres; that he has never received any land from the State of Texas, either as a headright or any other way, or any certificate therefor, or authorized any other person to receive any land or land certificate for him; there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office is hereby authorized and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to issue to the said Matthew Dockery his headright certificate for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land, to which he was entitled by the laws of the Republic of Texas; said certificate to be located upon any of the unappropriated public domain of the State of Texas, subject to all the laws now in force in reference to the location of such certificate.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 22, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the Aransas Road company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, It appears that the Aransas Road company has operated under its charter in good faith, with large outlay and with great misfor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tunes and without any remuneration, and that it still proposes to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress in important portions of its work, especially in making roads and improving navigable channels through the southern part of Aransas bay, within Aransas county; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That said company shall continue to have its rights obtained by sections one, two and three of &#8220;an act supplemental to an act to incorporate the Aran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sas Road company,&#8221; dated September 1, 1856, for accomplishing works heretofore authorized by said company&#8217;s charter on specified terms, to the extent of the following provisions:</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said company may improve the navigability of the ship chan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nel on Aransas bar, and between this bar and the Corpus Christi mud flats, by deepening the present channel, or by making a new one, in any part, of greater depth; and may connect said ship channel with the main<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />land at any places on the western shore of Aransas bay, by one road or<pb n="9" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>more; and may by such and other means reclaim from overflow any lands subject thereto that may be connected with any such road.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. For such improvements the company shall have rights as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows: 1st&#8212;Of way and of stations, within the bay on public lands, whether covered by water or not. 2d&#8212;Of property in any flats, shal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows, reefs and islands connected with or near to any such road, between the mainland and the main gulf, exclusive of the large islands bordering the latter, and of a small island called the &#8220;Shell Bank;&#8221; and for such a road other than a railroad substantially made from proper elevation on the mainland, through the bay, with a wharf so as to afford eligible fa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cility for transportation between the mainland and shipping, the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany may perfect its title to such lands by location, survey and patent, on any valid land claim in the usual mode, within the distance of one mile from such road; and in case such road shall be a good and substan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tial railroad, with suitable iron or steel railing, made from proper eleva<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions on the mainland through the bay, with a wharf so as to afford elegible facility for transportation between the mainland and shipping, the company may perfect its title to such lands, by survey and patent without any other claim, within the distance of two miles from such railroad.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. For the improvement of said ship channel the company may close Cedar Bayou, which is not navigable, so as to prevent the flow of water through it; and so may close all the unnavigable channels between Aransas and Corpus Christi bays.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The company may demand and receive reasonable rates of compensation for the use of any such road or wharf; but the rates shall be subject to regulations by the Legislature at any time.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Within two years from the date when this act shall become effective, the work to be done under it shall be commenced in a practical way, and then so prosecuted that one road and one wharf shall be in good condition for ordinary use as above provided for, within five years from said date.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The company shall continue to have its rights heretofore granted and remaining unrepealed, so far as necessary and proper for using the rights above specified; provided, that its capital stock shall be limited to its original amount of one million of dollars; and that the company&#8217;s acceptance of this act by a statement of its president, filed in the office of the secretary of state, or by proceeding under it, shall be a disclaimer of all provisions of its charter not properly applicable to the rights above specified.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The great importance of early progress in the improvements contemplated by the company under this act in connection with, and in a way to assure the largest benefits from proposed improvements by the United States government in the navigation of Aransas bay, creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity that the company shall have such guaranty as will justify the immediate prosecution of its enter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prise; therefore this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 26, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="10" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to declare valid and binding on the county of Wilson certain sales of lots and blocks of the town of Floresville, in said county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all sales of lots and blocks belonging to the county of Wilson, situated in and a part of the town of Floresville in said county, made at private sale by any commissioner or agent heretofore appointed by the proper authorities of said county, for which said lots or blocks the said county has received payment, be and are hereby made and declared valid and binding on said county.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 26, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act authorizing the commissioner of the general</salute>
</opener>
<opener>
<salute>land office to approve the bounty land certificate issued to the heirs of William Fishbaugh, deceased, who fell at the Alamo.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office be and he is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to approve the bounty land certificate for nineteen hundred and twenty acres, issued to the heirs of William Fishbaugh, deceased, who fell at the Alamo.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 3, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of the heirs of Captain Silas Dinsmore, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Silas Dinsmore, late a citizen of Matagorda county, was ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed and commissioned as captain in the navy of the Republic of Texas on the thirtieth day of March, 1836, by David G. Burnet, presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent of said republic; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, the said Dinsmore was not employed or engaged in the navy service of the said republic, because there were no ships belonging to said republic; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, the said Silas Dinsmore took an active and zealous part in the struggle for Texas independence, and served continuously as a soldier in the land service of Texas during the whole of the war, in 1835 and 1836, and that by his exposure as a soldier under orders, in defense of Galveston island, in 1836, he contracted a disease of his lungs which re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sulted in his death; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, the said Silas Dinsmore was rightfully entitled to a bounty warrant for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land for the above men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned services by virtue of the act of the congress of the republic, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved &#8220;December 4, 1837: and.</p>
<p>Whereas, no such certificate or warrant has ever been granted to him or his heirs; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office is hereby authorized and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to issue to the heirs of Silas Dinsmore, deceased, a bounty land<pb n="11" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>certificate for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land for his services as a soldier in the years 1835 and 1836, to be located upon any of the unap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated public domain of the State of Texas, subject to all the laws now in force in reference to the location of such certificates.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 7, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to grant to Jackson Doyle a headright of six hundred and forty acres of land.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Jackson Doyle be and is hereby granted a certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, as an emigrant to Texas before the first day of January, A. D. 1840.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the commissioner of the general land office be and is hereby required to issue to Jackson Doyle a certificate for six hundred and forty acres of land, which may be located upon any unappropriated domain of the state.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The fact that the session is drawing to a close and accumula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of business creates an imperative public necessity that the rule should be suspended requiring this bill to be read on three several days, and it is so ordered.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 14, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act granting further time to the Corpus Christi, San Diego and Rio Grande Narrow Gauge railroad company.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, The port of Corpus Christi was closed during the summer of 1878, by quarantine and the subsequent shoaling of water on Aransas bar has made navigation impossible since that time; and</p>
<p>Whereas, the Corpus Christi, San Diego and Rio Grande Narrow Gauge railroad company have thereby been delayed in the receipt of material for the completion of the last ten miles of the fifty of their road required by law to be constructed by March 13, 1879.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the time in which said company is now required by law to construct their railroad, or any section thereof, is hereby extended and enlarged for an additional two years.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That as a matter of vital general interest an imperative public necessity exists for the passage of this act, it shall therefore take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 14, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTEP XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act for the relief of Joseph Fenner.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the commissioner of the general land office be and he is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized and required to issue to Joseph Fenner a bounty warrant for<pb n="12" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>twelve hundred and eighty acres, and a donation warrant for six hundred and forty acres of land, being the quantity to which the said Fenner is entitled as a soldier of the Texas army in 1836, under Col. J. W. Fannin, at Goliad, which may be located, surveyed and patented in the same manner as other certificates.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 17, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to amend &#8220;an act to incorporate the city of San Antonio, and grant a new charter to said city,&#8221; and to repeal &#8220;an act to incorporate the city of San Antonio,&#8221; approved July 17, 1856, and &#8220;an act to amend the act to incorporate the city of San Antonio,&#8221; approved February 11, 1860, approved August 13, 1870.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That sections five, twenty-four, forty-three and forty-five of &#8220;an act to incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porate the city of San Antonio, and grant a new charter to said city,&#8221; and to repeal an act entitled &#8220;an act to incorporate the city of San An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tonio,&#8221; approved July 17, 1856, and an act entitled &#8220;an act to amend the act to incorporate the city of San Antonio,&#8221; approved February 11, 1860, approved August 13, 1870, be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Sec. 5. That on the second Monday in January of each alternate year, beginning with the year 1881, a mayor, recorder, city councilmen, a city collector, and street commissioner shall be voted for, and the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turns for such election for mayor and other officers shall be made in the same manner as hereinafter provided.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sec. 24. At the first meeting of the city council after the promulga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the result of the election for mayor and other offices, the city council shall, upon the nomination by the mayor, proceed to elect one treasurer, one engineer, one city attorney, one city physician, one city clerk, one assessor, one or more market-masters, one or more water com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners; a marshal and one or more assistant marshals, and such police and other officers as they may deem necessary for the proper administra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the city government, and for the interest of the city. They may provide by ordinance for the suspension or removal of officers elected by the people or appointed by the council for malfeasance or incompetency in office or other cause, and shall fill vacancies as they may occur; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, such vacancies occur less than nine months before the expiration of the respective terms of office of parties vacating.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sec. 43. To incur debts and to borrow money on the credit of the city and issue bonds therefor to an amount not to exceed ten thousand dollars during any one year. To make a loan or incur an indebtedness exceeding ten thousand dollars in any one year, the question must be submitted to the legal voters of the city, and if sustained by a vote of two-thirds of the vote polled, such indebtedness or loan shall be lawful. All bonds shall specify for what purpose they were issued, and they shall not be invalid if sold for less than their par value, and when any bonds are issued by the city, a fund shall be provided to pay the interest and two per cent. per annum on the principal as a sinking fund to redeem<pb n="13" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the bonds, which fund shall not be diverted or drawn for any other pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose, and the city treasurer shall honor no draft drawn on said fund ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cept to pay interest or to redeem the bonds for which it was provided, and for the payment of each loan, to levy a special tax over and above the general tax allowed by this act; provided, the rate of tax shall not exceed one-half of one per cent, and the rate of interest paid shall not exceed ten per cent.; provided, also, no loan shall be made or indebted<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness incurred for any other purpose or purposes than those connected with the corporation of the city of San Antonio, and no loan shall be made or indebtedness incurred to aid any private enterprise, railroad or undertaking not under the management and control of the city council. The sinking fund for the redemption of any bonds or the payment of any loan or debt, shall be invested as fast as the same accumulates in United States interest bearing bonds, bonds of the State of Texas, or bonds of the city of San Antonio, and such bonds, and the interest of such bonds, shall be invested in like securities and shall be sold when necessary to pay the debts or loans or to redeem the bonds for which the sinking fund was accumulated.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sec. 45. To appropriate money and to provide for the payment of debts and expenses of the city. But the bonded or other indebtedness of the city shall not be increased more than ten thousand dollars in any one year unless authorized by a vote of the people of said city as hereinbefore provided.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the end of the session, and the want of a proper law upon this subject, creates an imperative public necessity and emergency that the rules be suspended and that this act take effect from its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 18, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act granting to Mrs. Florence Whitis, executrix, the right to make a change in Laurel street, in the city of Austin.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, The estate of C. W. Whitis owns lots numbers 11, 12 and 13, and all land out of out lot 15, division D, on the south side of Laurel street, city of Austin, therefore, upon the petition of the said Mrs. F. Whitis, executrix, and of proof made that the same has been advertised as required by law;</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Mrs. Florence Whitis, executrix of the will of C. W. Whitis, deceased, be authorized to change the course of Laurel street as shown by the gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment survey and plot of the city of Austin, lying between out lots numbers 11, 12 and 13 on the north, and out lot number 15, on the south of said street, all in division D, city of Austin, as follows: Beginning the change at the west of said Laurel street where it leaves the northwest cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner of out lot number 15, division D, and running thence nearly east at right angles to the street running across the west end of said Laurel street to the west line of out lot number 10 in division D; thence nearly south with said west line of said out lot number 10, till it falls into the street now running nearly north between out lots numbers 15 and 17, division D, on the west of said street, and out lots numbers 7, 8 and 9, division D, on the east of said street.</p>
<pb n="14" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. The right of the state to the land embraced in the limits of said discontinued street as herein set forth is hereby granted to the estate of the said C. W. Whitis, and made a part of out lot 15, division D; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that the said Mrs. Florence Whitis, executrix aforesaid, shall have the proposed new street laid off at least sixty feet wide, and shall cause within sixty days after the passage of this act, a correct plot of the changes herein authorized to be made, and deposit the same with the clerk of the county court of Travis county for record; and provided further, that said Mrs. Whitis, executrix aforesaid, shall, within the same time, exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cute a deed to the land embraced in the limits of the new street as herein designated, to the city of Austin, for public purposes and uses forever, and file the same with the county clerk of Travis county for record; and provided further, that this act shall in no way impair the vested rights of other persons.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The late period in the session at which this bill receives ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and the convenience of the public and owners of adjacent property, which will be subserved by the passage of this act, creates a public neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity for the suspension of the rule which requires this act to be read on three several days.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 18, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize the Austin Canal, Irrigation and Manufacturing company to construct a dam across the Colorado river.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Austin Canal, Irrigation and Manufacturing company, incorporated under a general law of the state, and their associates, successors and as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signs be and they are hereby authorized to construct and keep up a dam across the Colorado river at any point above the city of Austin on said river and within ten miles of said city, selected by said company, and to divert so much of the water of said river as may be required by said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany for their purposes into a canal to be constructed by them; provided, that said company and their successors, should said river become naviga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble from the city of Austin and above said dam, by vessels propelled by steam, shall construct and keep for use a lock in said dam for the pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sage of such vessels; and provided further, that there shall be constructed and kept in good order by said company a fish-ladder or other ways suf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficient to enable fish to pass from below and above said dam; provided, that should said company fail to construct said dam within two years from the passage of this act, then the privilege herein granted shall cease; and provided further, that no acquisition of the right of way herein granted shall avail unless said company shall commence said canal in two years from this date and finish the same in three years thereafter, nor shall this act prevent any person or company from building a man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ufactory or manufactories, or using the waters of said river at any time.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said company shall be authorized and empowered to acquire the right of way and the land necessary therefor in the same manner and under the same regulations as provided by law for the acquisition of the right of way by railroad companies in this state.</p>
<pb n="15" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. Said company shall provide the means of returning all the water diverted into their canal from the Colorado river and not con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sumed or absorbed in use for irrigating purposes, to the natural channel of said river, at a point not further than one mile below the mouth of Shoal creek, at the city of Austin.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Whereas, the present session of [the] Legislature is near ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />journment, with a large number of bills of a public nature pending, there is an imperative public necessity for the suspension of the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days; and it is there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore enacted that said rule is hereby suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 19, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act amendatory of and supplemental to an act en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled an act to consolidate in one act and amend the several acts in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corporating the city of Houston, in Harris county," approved January 23, 1874, and the several acts amendatory thereof.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the inhabitants of the city of Houston shall be a body corporate, by the name of the mayor, aldermen and inhabitants of the city of Houston, and by that name they shall be known in law and shall be capable of su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and being sued, and defending in all courts, and in all matters what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever; may have a common seal, and may alter and change the same at pleasure; may hold and convey any estate, real or personal, for the use of said corporation, within the city limits; provided, that said corpor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ation may hold real estate outside of the limits of said city, for cemetery, powder house, pest house and work house purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the bounds and limits of said corporation shall be three miles square, to be run with the cardinal points of the compass, of which the centre of the court house square in the city of Houston shall be the centre.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the city council may divide the city into a convenient number of wards, not exceeding eight, and define and establish the boundaries thereof, and may change the same from time to time as may be deemed expedient, having regard for the number of inhabitants, so that each ward shall contain, as near as may be, the same number of qualified electors for city elections.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the administration of the business affairs of said corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration shall be conducted by a mayor and board of aldermen, who shall compose the city council.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. All qualified electors of the state, who shall have resided for six months immediately preceding the election within the limits of said city, shall have the right to vote for mayor, and all other elective officers of said city; but in all elections to determine the expenditure of money or assumption of debt, only those shall be qualified to vote who pay taxes on property in said city.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the mayor shall be elected by the qualified voters of the city, and shall hold his office for the term of two years, and until his successor is elected and qualified. No person shall be mayor unless he is a qualified elector of the city. He shall be a con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />servator of the peace throughout the city. He shall have power<pb n="16" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>by and with the consent of the city council to appoint any number of policemen on any special occasion that he may deem necessary to preserve the peace of the city, and to discharge the same at pleasure. He shall have power, in case of necessity, to call out the militia, or any military company in the city, to aid in the suppression of any riot or public dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turbance. He shall be active and vigilant in enforcing all laws and ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nances for the government of the city; and he shall cause all the sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ordinate officers to be dealt with promptly for any neglect or violation of duty. He shall preside at all meetings of the council, when present; and, in case of a tie vote in the board of aldermen, he shall give the cast<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing vote. He shall have power to veto any resolution, by-law, ordinance, motion or order passed by the council in the following manner: He shall give notice of his veto at the same meeting in which said action was had, which shall be entered upon the minutes; at the next regular meeting he shall furnish to the council his reasons in writing, and unless the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil shall pass such law, ordinance, etc., over his veto by a vote of two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds of the aldermen present, taken by &#8220;yeas and nays,&#8221; and entered upon the journal of the council, the same shall be inoperative. He shall have and exercise such powers and authority as may be conferred by the city council not inconsistent with the general purposes and provisions of this charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That each ward in the city shall be represented in the council by two aldermen, elected by the qualified voters of each ward, who shall vote only in their respective wards. No person shall be an alderman unless he is a qualified elector of the city, and a bona fide resident of the ward for which he is elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That regular meetings of the city council shall be held in the council chamber, at least twice in each month, at such times as may be fixed by resolution of the board, and the mayor of his own motion may call special meetings for the transaction of special business, by written notices served personally upon each member of the board, or left at his usual place of abode. Any three members of the board may in like man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner call special meetings of the council; but no special meeting shall be called except in cases of urgent necessity, and the written notices served upon the members of the board shall state the object and purpose for which the meeting is called. General business shall only be transacted at the regular meetings. The city council may adjourn from day to day until the business properly coming before it is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That a majority of the whole number of aldermen elected and qualified shall be required to constitute a quorum, but any four aldermen may convene and compel the attendance of absent members on any day of regular meetings, requiring the city marshal or other police officer to arrest and bring in the absent members.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That the city council shall adopt rules and regulations for the government of the council in its proceedings, and the order for the transaction of business before it. It shall be the judge of the qualifica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions and election of the members of the council, including the mayor. It may punish members or other persons during the sittings of the council for disorderly conduct, to the extent that it may fine and imprison by its by-laws and ordinances, and with the affirmative vote of two-thirds of the whole number of aldermen elected and qualified. The council may remove any officer of the city for any conduct or offense, which, in the opinion of the council, expressed by the two-thirds vote, as aforesaid, shall render him unfit to hold his office, but no officer shall be removed<pb n="17" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>until he shall have had the opportunity of being heard by himself or counsel, or both.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That the meetings of the council shall be held with open doors, except when, by a vote of two-thirds of the members present, it may be deemed expedient upon a special question to deliberate with closed doors.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That whenever it shall be necessary so to do, the board of aldermen shall by ballot elect a member of their own body to act for a designated period as mayor pro tempore, who, for the time, shall have and exercise all the powers and authority of the mayor.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That in case of a vacancy occurring in any office elective by the qualified voters of the city, the council shall order an election to fill the vacancy upon giving ten days&#8217; notice thereof, which election shall be held and conducted in the same manner, and under the same rules and regulations prescribed for the holding of the general elections in the city.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That there shall be a secretary and treasurer, city marshal and assessor and collector of taxes who shall hold their respective offices for two years, and until their successors are duly qualified. The secretary and treasurer shall be nominated by the mayor and confirmed by a majority of all the aldermen elected and qualified, taken by ballot. The city marshal and assessor and collector of taxes shall be elected by the qualified voters of the city.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That the office of city recorder is hereby abolished, and the duties of the same are devolved upon the mayor, who shall have juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction within the limits of the corporation, with power to hear and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />termine all cases of violation of the ordinances of the city council, which shall be prosecuted in the name, and in behalf of the mayor, aldermen and inhabitants of the city of Houston; and for the proper exercise of such jurisdiction the mayor shall have power and authority to issue pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cess; to preserve order and punish for contempt committed in the pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence of his court; to administer oaths and affirmations, to summon wit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nesses, either in the city or from any part of Harris county, and compel their attendance, but process beyond the city limits shall be directed to and executed by the sheriff or some constable for the county; to summon jurors and compel their attendance. The mayor&#8217;s court shall be opened daily, and the accused shall have a speedy trial. The law of the state reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ulating practice and procedure in courts of justice of the peace shall be the rule of practice and procedure in the mayor&#8217;s court. In the absence, sickness, or inability of the mayor to act and hold his court, the mayor&#8217;s court may be held by the mayor pro tempore, [who] shall have the same jurisdiction, power and authority of the mayor. The salary and fees of the mayor&#8217;s court may be determined by the city council. He shall make report to the council from time to time as required, and shall do and perform such duties properly appertaining to the office, as may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by the city council.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That the secretary and treasurer shall attend the city coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil at its meetings. He shall have the custody of all the laws and ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nances of the city. He shall have the custody of the common seal of the corporation, and shall only affix the same to the obligations of the city, by order of the city council. He shall keep a regular and cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rect journal of the proceedings of the council, in well bound record books. He shall be the treasurer and have the custody of all moneys and valuable papers, records and archives of the city. He shall receive all moneys and revenues coming into the city treasury, and pay the same out by order of the council. He shall keep the money and funds of the<pb n="18" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>city on deposit in some bank in the city of Houston. He shall keep the accounts of the city in well bound books, and the books and records of his office shall be opened to the inspection of any citizen upon request, at any reasonable and proper time. He shall prepare and publish in one or more newspapers, printed in the city of Houston, an accurate and detailed statement and account of the receipts and disbursements of the revenues of the city; the outstanding obligations and liabilities of the city, and the condition of the city treasury, which statement shall be prepared and made up to the first Monday of December of each year, and published on or before the fifteenth day of December; and it shall be the duty of the city council to require this statement so to be made and published; and should the said statement not be made in the manner and at the time provided, the secretary and treasurer shall be liable to a fine of one thousand dollars, to be recovered in the district court of Har<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ris county at the suit of the city attorney for and in behalf of the mayor, aldermen and inhabitants of the city of Houston; and the securities of the city secretary and treasurer on his official bond shall be liable for the amount of such fine; and judgment nisi shall be entered against them at the same time with the principal, to be made final upon a return of a writ of scire facias; and the city council may prescribe such other duties to be performed by the secretary and treasurer, concerning the administration of his office as may be deemed advisable.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That the city marshal shall be the chief police officer of the city under the mayor. He shall attend all regular and special meetings of the council. He shall attend upon the mayor&#8217;s court, and shall prompt<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly execute and return all process issued from said court. He shall be act<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ive in quelling riots, disorders and disturbances of the peace within the limits of said city, and shall take in custody all persons so offending against the peace of the community. He shall arrest all offenders against the ordinances of the city for offenses committed in his presence, and shall have authority to take bail for their appearance before the mayor; and, in default of giving which, he shall commit them to the city prison for safe keeping until they can be brought before the mayor for trial. He shall have authority to appoint one deputy, for whose acts and conduct he shall be responsible; and such deputy shall have all the power and authority of the marshal. He shall perform such other duties, and shall be invested with such other power, rights and authority as the city council may by ordinance confer, not inconsistent with the constitution and laws of the state.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That the assessor and collector shall assess and collect all licenses and taxes levied and imposed by the city council, and shall pay the same over to the secretary and treasurer weekly on the Saturday of each week, taking duplicate receipts therefor, one of which he shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain, and the other he shall return to the council (or the proper commit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tee appointed by the council to receive the same) with his report in detail showing the several amounts received and by whom paid, which report shall be made to the first meeting of the council in each month. He shall be governed by the rules and regulations hereinafter prescribed in rela<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to the assessment and collection of licenses and taxes imposed by the city council, and shall do and perform such other acts and duties concern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the administration of his office as may be prescribed by the city council.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. That the officers named in this charter shall perform the duties prescribed by this act, and such other duties as may be prescribed<pb n="19" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>by ordinance; and there shall be such other officers, servants and agents of the corporation as may be provided by ordinance, to be appointed by the mayor with the approval of a majority of all the aldermen elected and qualified, who shall perform such duties and receive such compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion as may be prescribed by ordinance. The council may require any officer or agent of said city as it may deem proper to give good and suffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient bond with approved security for the faithful performance of his duties in such sum as it may prescribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. That bonds shall be required of the city assessor and collector and of the city secretary and treasurer in an amount not less than double the amount of the funds which may probably be in their hands at any one time, to be determined by the council, which bond shall be upon such con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ditions as may be determined by the city council, and with good securities to be approved by the city council, and the city shall in like manner re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire bonds of any officer or agent of the city, through Whose hands the money of the city may pass.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. That the by-laws and ordinances of the city shall be enforced by fine not exceeding one hundred dollars, or by imprisonment not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding thirty days; and the council may provide by ordinances that fines may be commuted by labor in a work house or in the public works; and execution may issue against the goods and chattels, lands and tenements of the offender.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. That the salaries and fees of officers of said city shall be determined by the city council at least one month previous to their elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, which salaries and fees, when so determined, shall not be raised for lowered during the period for which said officers were elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. That the city council shall have power and authority to determine the dimensions, and provide for grading, paving, repairing or otherwise improving the streets or sidewalks, or any parts or portions thereof within the limits of the city, and to make provisions for the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the cost and expense thereof, in whole or in part, by the levy, assessment and collection of a tax upon the lot or lots fronting thereon, which assessment shall be a charge against the owner of said lot or lots, as well as a charge upon the property itself, which may be collected and enforced in any court of competent jurisdiction; provided, that the powers herein conferred shall be exercised only upon the: petition of the owner or owners, or their legal representatives, of seventy-five per cent. of the property of the block or blocks fronting on each side of the street or streets proposed to be paved, and to maintain the cleanliness of the city; to secure the safety and convenience of passing in the streets, side<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />walks and other places in the city; to fix the squaring and to prevent encroachments and obstructions on the streets, sidewalks, squares, ways, levees and public roads and places to fix the place for anchoring all water crafts on Buffalo bayou; to establish an active system of inspection over the conduct of persons and premises; to prevent cattle, horses, swine, goats, geese and animals from running at large in the streets; to estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish and maintain city police, prescribe the duties of policemen and regulate their conduct; to provide for lighting the streets, and for this purpose may establish gas works for the manufacture of gas for the use of the city, and the inhabitants thereof at cost price; to determine in what part of the city slaughter houses, bone boilers, soap makers, or other establishments for any business, which is or may be injurious to the value of adjacent property, or unwholesome or disagreable to the occupant of adjacent property, shall not be allowed to be erected; to<pb n="20" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>determine in what part of the city wooden buildings shall not be erected &#8212;within, the limits prescribed no person shall be permitted to erect such buildings; to prevent gunpowder, or other explosive material, kerosine oil, or other inflammable oils, being stored within the city limits, in such quantity as to endanger the safety of the adjacent property; to provide means for the protection and extinguishment of conflagrations, and for the regulation, maintenance and support of a fire department; in permit or forbid theatres, balls, or other public amusements, and to suppress the same whenever the preservation of order, tranquility or public safety may require; to close dram shops, drinking saloons, and other places where intoxicating liquors are sold whenever necessary or expedient; to define what shall be deemed nuisances in said city, and to abate them by summary proceedings; to provide a work house for vagabonds and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />orderly persons who are unable to pay fines, and make regulations con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cerning the same; to regulate weights and measures, in the city, affix penalties for violation, fix standards, etc.; also that the city council may provide, own and maintain water works for the use of the city and its inhabitants; to provide and keep a city prison; to make all needful and proper regulations concerning bakers, butchers, keepers of taverns, grog shops and other public houses, draymen, horse drivers, water carriers, omnibus drivers, hack drivers, and drivers of baggage wagons, and especially to preserve order and prevent noise and confusion in and about the several depots on the arrival and departure of railway trains; to prevent extortion by carriers of passengers or baggage, hacks, drays and all public conveyances, by establishing maximum rate of charges; to direct, and control the laying and construction of railroad tracks, turn<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />outs and switches, and to require that the[y] be constructed and laid so as to interfere as little as possible with the ordinary travel and use of streets; to require railroad companies to keep the streets, through which they run in repair, and to light the same whenever deemed necessary; to construct and keep in repair bridges and crossings at the intersection of streets and avenues, and over all ditches, sewers and culverts on the line of the railway; to regulate the speed of engines and locomotives within said city; to control and regulate everything concerning street railways, and generally to make and establish all rules, regulations, by-laws and ordinances which may contribute to and promote the better administra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the affairs of said city, as well as for the maintenance of the peace, tranquility and safety of said city, and for the protection of persons and property of its inhabitants, the city council of the city of Houston are hereby empowered and authorized to take and condemn land and real estate in said city to the public use, viz: for streets, alleys and public highways for extending, straightening and widening those streets now in use; for public wharves and landing places; for steamers add other water crafts, and for public squares, parks and pleasure grounds. For the condemnation of any land or real estate, the following proceedings shall be had: The city attorney, or attorneys employed by said city for that purpose, shall file a petition in the district court of Harris county against the owner of the land or real estate, sought to be condemned for any of the purposes aforesaid, setting forth: first, the name or names and residence of the owner or owners, if known, and if unknown, the same shall be stated; second, the description by metes and bounds of any actual survey, had for that purpose, of the land or real estate sought to be condemned; third, the purposes for which the same is proposed to be taken and applied; fourth, the supposed value of the property to be<pb n="21" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>condemed; fifth, the prayer that the same be condemned to the public use for the purposes stated, and upon the filing of such petition, like proceedings shall be had thereon as in other civil suits, and when personal service cannot be had by reason of the defendant being a non-resident or unknown, service by publication shall be made as provided in other cases in the district court and upon trial the court shall proceed to render judgment, condemning the land to public use, upon the payment of the value thereof as assessed by the jury, and upon any suit being brought thereafter against the said corporation for such property so condemned, a copy of the judgment and an actual tender of the money in court shall be sufficient answer in bar of a recovery in any such suit. All costs of proceedings for the condemnation of land and real estate under this act shall be taxed against the plaintiff, including reasonable fees of the attor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ney which the court shall appoint to represent the defendant when cited by publication.</p>
<p>Sec. 24. That the council shall have power and authority to establish one or more markets and market places, and within reasonable hours, not later than ten o&#8217;clock daily, to prevent the sale of fresh meats, game, fresh fish, poultry, eggs, vegetables and such country produce as is usually sold in markets at any place in said city other than said markets and market places so established and to collect market licenses and privileges; to rent and lease for such length of time as the city council may deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mine, not exceeding one year, stalls or stands in said market for the sale of the before-mentioned articles, and to regulate and fix the prices at which the said stands or stalls shall be rented, and to provide for prompt collection of rent of the same and to pay all expenses of collection there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of, and for properly earing for and keeping in repair the market build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and for pavement of streets fronting on and adjacent thereto, and for insurance of the same and its contents, and such care, paving, insurance and general keeping of said market houses shall be paid for out of the revenues collected out of said market house.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. That the market and market privileges of said city may be let and farmed out annually to the highest bidder at public outcry at the market house, after ten days notice of the time, place and terms shall have been published in one of the city papers, and two copies posted in conspic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uous places in said market house. The city council shall, before the day of letting fix upon the minimum sum at which the market amid market privileges may be leased for the ensuing year and publish the same in the public notices required to be given as herein prescribed, and all bids below the amount named shall be rejected. At least five days before the day advertised for the letting, the mayor shall cause to be prepared the contract required to be signed by the lessees, and the same shall not in any manner be changed or modified within the five days previous to the letting, and said contract so prepared shall be open at the mayor&#8217;s office to the inspection of all parties who may desire to see it. A good bond and securities to be approved by the city council shall be required of the lessees, and new and additional securities may be required at any time under penalty of forfeiture of contract.</p>
<p>Sec. 26. That the city council may appropriate to such use and pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses as may be deemed advisable, such halls and rooms in the upper story of the market house as may not be necessary for the public use and to lease and rent the same, from time to time, in the discretion of the council.</p>
<p>Sec. 27. That the city council shall have power to construct wharves<pb n="22" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>on the banks of Buffalo bayou within the limits of the corporation, and make such other improvements as may be necessary for the better navi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gation of said bayou and for the convenience of landing vessels and their cargoes, and to levy contributions upon all vessels and their cargoes as may land at said wharves, and to demand and collect the same, to defray the expenses of such improvements and repairs.</p>
<p>Sec. 28. That whenever any steamboat or other craft shall sink in the Buffalo bayou above Harrisburg and the navigation be obstructed thereby, it shall be the duty of the mayor of the city of Houston to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point three good and discreet commissioners to inspect and examine the same and its condition and immediately to report in writing their opin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ion, stating whether in their opinion the boat or craft sunk can be or is likely to be raised or removed within the space of ten days after their ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />amination; and should they be of opinion that such boat or craft is not likely to be raised so as to open the navigation within twenty days from the time of their examination, then and in that case the mayor and aider<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men of the city of Houston may order the removal of such boat or craft so sunk in any manner they shall deem proper, without incurring any penalty for the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 29. That said corporation of the city of Houston is hereby given full power and authority to take such steps to preserve and improve the navigation of the said Buffalo bayou above the town of Harrisburg as they may think proper; and for that purpose they are authorized to levy and collect a tax on all steamboats and other crafts running in said bayou to the city of Houston for the purpose of, improving navigation thereof; provided, that the power in this section shall not be construed to give said corporation any jurisdiction or control over said Buffalo bayou or the banks thereof in any manner beyond or without the corporate limits of said city, except for the purpose of protecting or improving the navigation of said bayou, and shall not give said corporation jurisdiction or control to prevent or interfere with the construction of any railroad or other bridges by any company or person across said bayou in such man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner as not to interfere with the navigation of said bayou.</p>
<p>Sec. 30. That the city council, by a vote of the majority of the whole number of aldermen taken by &#8220;yeas and nays,&#8221; and entered upon their journal, shall have power to assess, license and tax hawkers, peddlers, auctioneers, theatrical and other exhibitions, shows and amusements, billiard tables, nine and ten pin alleys, alleys with any number of pins, public drays, wagons, omnibuses and carriages, grog shops, tippling houses and dram shops, beer saloons (whether for the sale of domestic beers or otherwise), and such other trades or occupations not especially mentioned herein, as may be taxed by the laws of the state; but no assess<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment or license tax levied under this section shall exceed one-half the amount levied by the state for the same period on such profession or occupation, and the same may be regulated, levied and collected in the same manner as said taxes are regulated and collected by the state.</p>
<p>Sec. 31. That the city council shall have power, by ordinance, to annually levy, assess and collect taxes not exceeding two per cent. ad valorem upon all real and personal estate and property in the city, not exempt from taxation, and to determine when taxes shall be paid by cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porations, and when by individual corporators, and to levy and collect from each male inhabitant of the city, over the age of twenty-one years, an annual poll tax of one dollar. All taxes on real estate shall be a lien<pb n="23" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and charge upon the property, and it may be subjected to the payment of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 32. That the license tax shall be collected by the assessor and collector of taxes, and shall be paid to that officer in current funds of the United States, by each and every person or firm owning such license and before engaging in any trade, profession, business calling, avocation or occupation subject to such tax, taking his receipt therefor, which receipt shall entitle him, her or them, to a corresponding license, to be issued by the mayor, and if any person shall engage in any business, calling, avo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation or occupation, which, by an ordinance of said city, is subject to a license tax, without first having obtained such license, he, she or they shall be liable to arrest and imprisonment and a fine of ten dollars for each and every day such violation of said ordinance may continue; and this section shall apply to all persons owing license and failing to pay the same; and the city council may make such further regulations as it deems necessary to enforce the provisions of this section and punish the viola<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 33. That the city council may and shall have full power to provide by ordinance for the prompt collection of all taxes levied, assessed and due, or becoming due to said city, and to that end may and shall make such rules and regulations and pass such ordinances as it shall deem necessary to the levying, laying, imposing, assessing and collecting of any of said taxes, and to regulate the mode and manner of making out tax-lists and inventories, and the appraisement of property therein; and to prescribe the oath that shall be administered to each person on such rendition of property, and to prescribe how and when property shall thus be rendered, and to fix the duties and define the powers of the assessor and collector of taxes, and adopt such measures as they may deem advisable to secure the assessment of all property in the limits of the city, and collect the taxes thereupon in current money of the United States, or otherwise, as herein provided, and may, by ordinance, provide that any person, firm or corporation having or controlling property in said city, subject to taxation, and failing and refusing to render a list, inventory and appraisement thereof, verified as may be required by any ordinance of said city, shall be liable to fine and imprisonment; that the city council shall appoint annually from its own members, at such time as it may determine, three appraisers, who shall be styled the board of appraisement, and whenever the party rendering the property for assess<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment and the assessor and collector cannot agree in the valuation of such property it shall be referred to said board, and their action in appraising the same shall be final; provided, that at the meeting of said board the owner of the property or party rendering the same shall have an oppor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tunity of being heard. Said board shall also appraise all property as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessed as unknown or unrendered, and shall receive such reasonable compensation for the services as the city council shall allow. The city council may, if it sees proper, adopt, as circumstances will permit, the same mode and manner of assessing and collecting taxes as may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by law for assessing [and] collecting state taxes; and all taxes due the city may be collected by an action of debt in any court having jurisdiction. The assessment rolls shall be taken as prima facie evidence of the statement made therein, and the city shall have the equal right to become the purchaser at all sales of property for taxes due it, made under judgments or otherwise. Nothing but current money of the United States shall be collected or received in payment of taxes and<pb n="24" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>licenses due or hereafter assessed, and scrip which may be issued for pavement of streets and constructing sidewalks, and for city waterworks, which shall express upon its face the purpose for which, it is issued, and coupons and scrip made receivable for taxes on the face thereof shall be receivable for all taxes except the bond tax.</p>
<p>Sec. 34. That the said corporation shall not be liable to any person for damages for injuries caused from streets, ways, crossings, bridges or sidewalks being out of repair from gross negligence of said corporation unless the same shall have remained so for ten days after special notice in writing given to the mayor or street commissioner.</p>
<p>Sec. 35. That it shall not be necessary in any action, suit or proceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing in which the mayor, aldermen [or] inhabitants of the city of Hous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton shall be a party that any bond or security shall be required; but all ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, suits or proceedings shall be conducted as if such bond or security had been given. The property, real and personal, belonging to the city, shall not be liable to be sold under any writ of execution, nor shall the funds belonging to the city in the hands of any person, be liable to gar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nishment, nor shall the city or any of its officers or agents be required to answer to any writ of garnishment.</p>
<p>Sec. 36. That all cemetery lots which have been or may hereafter be laid out by said city or in any private cemetery grounds, together with all monuments or railings upon the same, shall with all their appurten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ances forever be exempt from taxes, executions, attachments or forced sale, and the property of all churches, masons, odd fellows, or other chari<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />itable associations, used by them for places of meeting, both real and per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonal, bonds of the United States and bonds of the city of Houston, shall not be subject to tax under this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 37. That no person shall be an incompetent judge, justice, wit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness or juror by reason of his being an inhabitant or freeholder in the city of Houston, in any action or proceeding in which said city may be a party interested, and all officers of said city shall be exempt from jury<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />service while holding office.</p>
<p>Sec. 38. That the city council shall annually appoint, by ballot, one person from each ward of the city who, together with the mayor as pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ident thereof, shall constitute a board of health of the city. The city council may appoint a health physician and as many health inspectors as they may deem necessary, and shall prescribe by ordinance the powers and duties of the board and its members; and the secretary of the city council shall be clerk of the board of health and shall keep a record of their proceedings.</p>
<p>Sec. 39. That the city council shall have power to take such measures as they deem effectual, to prevent the entrance of any pestilential, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tagious or infectious diseases into the city, to stop, detain and examine for that purpose any person coming from any place infected or believed to be infected with such diseases; to establish, maintain and regulate pest houses or hospitals within the city, or not exceeding five miles from its bounds; to cause any person who shall be suspected of being infected with any disease to be sent to such pest house or hospital; to remove from the city or destroy any furniture, wearing apparel or property of any kind which shall be suspected of being tainted or infected with pes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tilence; to prevent persons from infected places coming into the city of Houston, and to adopt any sanitary measures whereby the health of the city may be protected and improved; but said corporation shall not have<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />power or authority to prevent railroad trains and passengers therein<pb n="25" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>from passing through said city, but may regulate the speed of such trains passing through and prevent their stopping.</p>
<p>Sec. 40. That all works of improvement and all public works for said city, exceeding the sum of five hundred dollars ($500) in cash, shall be let out to the lowest or, best bidder in the discretion of the council, by sealed proposals; and no contract shall be made or entered into until after the plans and specifications shall have been prepared and submitted to the council and approved by it, and afterwards published in at least four issues of some daily paper published in the city, inviting bids there for, and stating the time when such sealed proposals will [be] opened. City printing, and all repairing of bridges or other similar work, of which it is manifestly impracticable to make specifications, are not in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cluded in this requirement. No bid shall be considered unless made in accordance with the plans and specifications so published, and no allow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance for extra work shall ever be made or paid for. The sealed proposals shall be addressed to the city secretary and treasurer, and shall only be opened in the presence of the city council, at a regular meeting, and the bidders shall have the right to be present. Bond and security to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the city council shall be required of all contractors. The taking of any contract or any interest therein, openly or secretly, directly or indirectly, by any officer of the city, shall ipso facto work a forfeiture of the contract and the consideration thereof, and shall vacate the office held by the party taking the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 41. The city council shall have power and authority to borrow money on the credit of the city, and issue bonds therefor to an amount not to exceed one hundred thousand dollars, during any one year; to create a debt during any one year exceeding one hundred thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars, the question must be submitted to the taxpaying voters of the city, and if two-thirds of the votes polled shall be in favor of creating such debt, it shall be lawful for the city council to authorize the issuance of the bonds for the amount named in the resolution or ordinance submit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ting the question to the voters. No bonds shall be issued drawing a greater rate of interest than ten per cent. per annum, but shall not be invalid if sold for less than their par value. All bonds shall express upon their face for what purpose they were issued. When any bonds are au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to be issued in the same ordinance, a fund shall be provided to pay the interest and two per centum per annum on the principal as a sinking fund to redeem the bonds; and the two per cent, sinking fund shall be invested in the bonds of the city, or in United States bonds. The appropriation made for the interest and sinking fund shall under no circumstances be diverted to any other purpose. The city council &#8220;may make an appropriation from the general revenues in aid of public schools within the limits of the city by a vote of the majority of the whole num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of aldermen elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 42. That the city council shall make all necessary regulations concerning elections and provide for officers to conduct the same, and for the examination and counting of the returns of elections.</p>
<p>Sec. 43. That the general election of the officers of the city shall take place on the first Monday in April, 1880, and every two years thereafter; and the present incumbents shall hold over until their successors, elected at the first election, shall qualify. No election of city officers shall be held on the day of state or county election.</p>
<p>Sec. 44. That an act entitled &#8220;An act to consolidate in one act and amend the several acts incorporating the city of Houston, in Harris<pb n="26" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>county, passed August 2, 1870,&#8221; and all other acts relative to the incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration of the city of Houston, in conflict with this act, be and the same are hereby repealed; but all property, actions, rights of action, claims and demands of every nature and kind whatever vested in said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion under and by virtue of the said laws hereby repealed, shall vest in, and remain, and enure to the said corporation under this act as fully and completely, in all respects, as if the said laws had not been repealed; and all by-laws and resolutions and ordinances made and passed under or in pursuance of said laws hereby repealed, shall continue and remain in full force and effect until repealed by the proper authorities of said corporation.</p>
<p>Sec. 45. That this act shall be deemed a public act and judicial notice shall be taken thereof in all courts.</p>
<p>Sec. 46. Whereas, the end of the session is approaching, and the inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est of the people of the city of Houston demand that this act should be passed at the present session of the Legislature, therefore an emergency exists, and an imperative public necessity demand that the constitutional rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days be suspended and this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage; provided, however, that the present officers of the city of Houston shall continue in their present offices until the first Monday in April. A. D. 1880.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 21, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to validate the sale of certain town lots and county lands in the county of McCulloch.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sale of town lots and county lands situated in and adjoining the town of Brady, in the county of McCulloch, and State of Texas, heretofore made at private sale, by the agent, or agents, commissioner or commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners, be, and the same are hereby made as legal and valid as if made in strict conformity with law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas, an irregularity exists in the sale of said lands and lots, liable to cause confusion in years to come; and, whereas, the notice required by the constitution has been given of an application for the passage of this act; and, whereas, this session of the Legislature is fast drawing to a close, which necessitates the suspension of the rule requiring bills, to be read on three several days, and as an imperative public neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity, and emergency exists for the immediate passage of this act, it shall, therefore, take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 21. A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize Messrs. Cunningham &#38; Ellis, lessees of the State Penitentiary, to sue the state.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Messrs. Cunningham &#38; Ellis, lessees of the state penitenti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary, claim that the State of Texas is indebted unto them in the sum of seven thousand seven hundred and eighty dollars for which they claim<pb n="27" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>to be entitled to a credit, but which, on the part of the state, is denied; therefore that justice be done in the premises,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That said Cunningham &#38; Ellis be, and they are hereby authorized to sue the State of Texas, in the district court of Travis county, on said claim, and upon a recovery of judgment by them, the comptroller of public accounts shall allow them the amount of their recovery by way of credit on any settlement thereafter made with said lessees.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The session of this Legislature being now near its close makes it an imperative public necessity that the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days be suspended and that this act take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 22, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize the construction of a ship chan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nel from Corpus Christi across Mustang Island, and to donate land for the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, The citizens of Nueces county, on February 5, 1879, in con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention assembled, for the purpose of making arrangements for increasing the harbor facilities of Corpus Christi, by removing the Bulkhead and opening a free channel to the Gulf by way of Corpus Christi pass, se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected as a special committee M. Kenedy, George F. Evans, J. B. Mitchell, C. C. Heath and Wm. Headen, with full power to proceed with the work at their discretion in the best and most practicable way, and to expedite and promote the completion of said public work: therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That so soon as the aforesaid M. Kenedy, Geo. F. Evans, J. B. Mitchell, C. C. Heath, Wm. Headen and their associates, have completed a chan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nel across the Bulkhead at Corpus Christi pass, to the depth of eight feet, and one hundred feet wide, so that there shall be a continuous depth of eight feet at average tide, from the wharf at Corpus Christi to the bar at Corpus Christi pass, they shall notify the governor of such fact, when he shall appoint some competent person to examine and measure such channel; and if the same shall be found to have been constructed in con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formity with this act, then shall the commissioner of the general land office, upon presentation of the certificate of the governor, issue to M. Kenedy, Geo. F. Evans, J. B. Mitchell, C. C. Heath, Wm. Headen and their associates, three hundred and twenty land certificates, of sections of six hundred and forty acres each, which said certificates shall be located and surveyed in alternate sections on any of the unappropriated public domain not previously titled or surveyed, and the state shall not be responsible for any want of domain to locate said certificates upon, the field notes and maps returned to the general land office, and the odd sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions patented to said M. Kenedy, Geo. F. Evans, J. B. Mitchell, C. C. Heath, Wm. Headen and their associates, and the even sections reserved to the state for the school fund; provided, said M. Kenedy, J. B. Mitchell, Geo. F. Evans, Wm. Headen, C. C. Heath and associates, shall keep open and maintain said channel free of all toll ortax upon com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="28" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>merce for ten (10) years, and the work of opening said channel shall be completed within five years from the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That inasmuch as the closing of the bar at Aransas pass has interrupted and almost paralyzed the transportation of merchandise to Corpus Christy from which point a large extent of country is supplied, and that an immense quantity of wool and other articles cannot for that reason be forwarded to a market, a public necessity and emergency exist justifying the suspension of the rule and the immediate passage of this act, and that the same take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 22, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to authorize the survivors of Terry&#8217;s Texas Rangers to erect a monument to the dead of that command in the burying grounds belonging to the state at Austin.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the survivors of Terry&#8217;s Texas Bangers be permitted to erect a monument within the limits of the burying grounds belonging to the state at Austin, at such spot as may be designated by the governor.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the late hour of the session at which this act is proposed creates an imperative public necessity that the rule should be suspended which requires a bill to be read on three several days, and it is so sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 23, A. D. 1879</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
<closer>
<signed>THE STATE OF TEXAS, <lb/>D<smcap>EPARTMENT OF</smcap> S<smcap>TATE</smcap>.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>I, John D. Templeton, secretary of state of the State of Texas, do hereby certify that the laws contained in this volume are true and cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rect copies of the enrolled bills now on file in this department. I further certify that the regular session of the Sixteenth Legislature convened at the city of Austin, on the fourteenth day of January, A. D. 1879, and adjourned on the twenty-fourth day of April, A. D. 1879.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I hereto sign my name and affix the <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L. S.]</p></body></floatingText>seal of the State of Texas, at Austin, on this the seventeenth day of June, A. D. 1879.</p>
<closer>
<signed>JOHN D. TEMPLETON, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="29" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<p>Aransas Road. Company&#8212;act for relief of..... 6</p>
<p>Austin City&#8212;act authorizing forced sales in Travis county to be made at cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain place in, repealed..... 3</p>
<p>Mrs. Florence Whitis authorized to change Laurel street in..... 11</p>
<p>Austin Canal, Irrigation and Manufacturing Company&#8212;authorized to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struct a dam across the Colorado river, near Austin.... 12</p>
<p>Bayland Orphans&#8217; Home&#8212;lands granted to, to be patented..... 5</p>
<p>Brady City&#8212;sale of town lots in, validated..... 24</p>
<p>Breckinridge&#8212;sale of lands in, legalized..... 1</p>
<p>Colorado River&#8212;dam across, near Austin, legalized..... 12</p>
<p>Corpus Christi&#8212;ship channel from across Mustang Island authorized..... 25</p>
<p>Corpus Christi, San Diego and Rio Grande Narrow Gauge R. R. Co.--further time granted to..... 9</p>
<p>Cunningham &#38; Ellis&#8212;authorized to sue the State..... 24</p>
<p>Dam&#8212;Austin Canal, Irrigation and Manufacturing Company authorized to construct across Colorado river..... 12</p>
<p>Dinsmore, Silas&#8212;act for relief of heirs of..... 8</p>
<p>Doyle, Jackson&#8212;act for relief of..... 9</p>
<p>Dockery, Matthew&#8212;act for relief of..... 5</p>
<p>Fenner, Joseph&#8212;act for relief of..... 9</p>
<p>Fishbaugh, William&#8212;commissioner of land office authorized to approve bounty land certificate..... 8</p>
<p>Floresville&#8212;sale of lots and blocks in, valid and binding on Wilson county.. 8</p>
<p>Galveston County&#8212;authorized to sell her stock in Gulf, Colorado and Santa Fe railroad..... 2</p>
<p>Gulf, Colorado and Santa Fe Railway Company&#8212;act incorporating amended 1</p>
<p>Galveston county authorized to sell her stock in..... 2</p>
<p>Grand Lodge&#8212;of Masons, incorporated..... 3</p>
<p>Green, Alexander S.&#8212;act for relief of heirs of..... 5</p>
<p>Houston City&#8212;charter amended..... 13</p>
<p>Incorporations&#8212;Gulf, Colorado and Santa Fe railway company, act incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porating amended..... 1</p>
<p>Grand Lodge of Masons incorporated..... 3</p>
<p>Victoria, act incorporating amended..... 4</p>
<p>San Antonio, act incorporating amended..... 10</p>
<p>Houston, act incorporating amended..... 13</p>
<p>Corpus Christi, San Diego and Rio Grande Narrow Gauge railroad com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, further time granted to..... 9</p>
<p>Lands&#8212;granted to Bayland Orphans<sup>&#8217;</sup> Home to be patented..... 5</p>
<p>Masons&#8212;Grand Lodge of, incorporated..... 3</p>
<p>McCulloch County&#8212;sale of lots in town of Brady, validated..... 24</p>
<p>Penitentiary&#8212;lessees of, authorized to sue the state..... 24</p>
<p>Railroads&#8212;act incorporating Gulf Colorado and Santa Fe railroad company amended..... 1</p>
<p>Corpus Christi, San Diego and Rio Grande Narrow Gauge railroad com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, further time granted to..... 9</p>
<p>Relief&#8212;granted to Mrs. M. A. C. Wilson..... 5</p>
<p>granted to heirs of Alexander S. Green..... 5</p>
<p>granted to Aransas Road company..... 6</p>
<p>granted to William Fishbaugh..... 8</p>
<p>granted, to heirs of Silas Dinsmore..... 8</p>
<p>granted to Jackson Doyle..... 9</p>
<p>granted to Joseph Fenner..... 9</p>
<p>granted to Matthew Dockery..... 5</p>
<p>San Antonio&#8212;charter amended..... 10</p>
<pb n="30" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Stephens County&#8212;act legalizing sale of land belonging to, in and near Breck<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />inridge..... 1</p>
<p>Travis County&#8212;act authorizing forced sales in, to be made at certain place repealed..... 3</p>
<p>Terry Rangers&#8212;authorized to erect a monument to their dead in state cemetery, at Austin..... 26</p>
<p>Victoria&#8212;charter amended..... 4</p>
<p>Waxahachie Town&#8212;authorized to transfer its stock in Waxahachie Tap rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road..... 2</p>
<p>Waxahachie Tap Railroad&#8212;town of Waxahachie authorized to transfer its stock in..... 2</p>
<p>Wilson, Mrs. M. A. C.&#8212;act for relief of..... 5</p>
<p>Wilson County&#8212;sales of certain lots and blocks in Floresville, binding on.... 8</p>
<p>Whitis, Mrs. Florence&#8212;authorized to make change in Laurel street, in the city of Austin..... 11</p>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>