<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="485" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="I" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>PASSED AT THE <lb/>REGULAR SESSION OF THE EIGHTEENTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>CONVENED <lb/>AT THE CITY OF AUSTIN</head>
<byline>JANUARY 9, 1883, AND ADJOURNED APRIL 13, 1883</byline>
<byline>BY AUTHORITY OF THE STATE OF TEXAS</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN, TEXAS 1883</byline>
<pb n="486" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="II" />
<pb n="487" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<head type="sub">SPECIAL LAWS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 1.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Sections three (3), four (4), five (5), six (6), eleven (11), fourteen (14), fifteen (15), sixteen (16), eighteen (18), twenty (20), twenty one (21), twenty two (22), twenty three (23), twenty six (26), twenty eight (28), twenty nine (29), thirty (30), fifty one (51), fifty two (52), eighty two (82), ninety (90), ninety one (91), one hundred and seventeen (117), one hundred and twenty seven (127), one hundred and twenty eight (128), one hundred and thirty five (135), one hundred and forty (140), one hundred and forty two (142), one hundred and forty seven (147), one hundred and forty eight (148), one hundred and fifty one (151), one hundred and fifty seven (157), one hundred and fifty eight (158), one hundred and fifty nine (159), one hundred and sixty one (161), one hundred and seventy (170), and one hundred and seventy one (171), of an act. to incorporate the city of Galveston and to grant a new charter; approved August 2nd, 1876, and amended by act of Legislature approved April 5th 1881.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That section three (3) of said act be, and the same is hereby amended, so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit;</p>
<p>Section 3. The municipal government of the city shall consist of a city council, composed of the mayor, and one alderman from each ward. A majority of the aldermen elected shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, except at called meetings, or meetings for the imposition of taxes, when three fourths of the aldermen elected shall be required unless herein otherwise specified.</p>
<p>The other officers of the corporation shall be a recorder, a treasurer, an assessor, a collector, a clerk, a chief of police, an engineer (who shall also be superintendent of streets), an attorney, an auditor, a health, physician and such other officers and agents as the city council may from time to time direct: All of whom except the mayor, aldermen, clerk, and chief of police shall be elected by ballot by the aldermen at a meeting to be held on the third Monday in March in each year, upon the nomination of the mayor: or in case no person shall then be nominated by him, or if the person so nominated shall not be elected, then as soon thereafter as pos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sible, upon the nomination of the mayor. The clerk and chief of police shall be appointed by the mayor on the third Monday in March in each year or as soon thereafter as possible. All of said officers so nominated, and elected shall hold their offices until the third Monday in March there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after and until the nomination, and election and qualification of their suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors: and in such election a majority of all the aldermen elected shall be necessary to a choice. The officers appointed by the mayor as afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said, shall hold their offices until the third Monday in March thereafter, unless earlier removed by the mayor, or by the city council under the au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="488" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>thority vested in it by section one hundred and fifty five (155) hereof; and until the appointment by the mayor, and qualification of their successors.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That Section four (4), of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit;</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Elections for mayor and aldermen shall be held biennially, on the first Monday in March, at such place and places as the city council may direct, and of which thirty days previous notice shall be given by publication in one or more newspapers of said city. Said election shall be ordered by the city council or mayor. For the purpose of holding such elections, and others ordered, the city council shall appoint biennially, in April or earlier, in each ward some competent and suitable person, who shall be the presiding officer at all elections held in his ward. The presiding officer in each ward shall elect two judges and two clerks, who with the presiding officer shall be managers of the election. The presid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing officers and judges must be qualified voters in the city. The city coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil shall provide for their compensation, and by ordinance, regulate and define their powers and duties, and determine the hours of opening and closing the polls. The mayor, whenever an election is ordered, shall give the required notice and issue to the presiding officer a writ of election; and every published notice of election shall state the officer, or officers to be elected, the place where the election will be held and the name of the presiding officer thereat. In case the officer so appointed is un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able, fails, refuses or neglects to act, or the city council have failed to appoint, the mayor shall appoint; and in case no appointed presiding officer appears to open the polls, the attending qualified electors at the place for holding such election may appoint such officer, who shall per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form the same duties and shall have like power and authority to act as a first appointee; but in such case the managers in their return&#8217;s or other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise, shall certify that the presiding officer failed to attend, or neglected to act and that the person acting as such was duly chosen by the electors present; provided, that if from any cause an election cannot be, or is not held on the day aforesaid, such election shall be held as soon there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after as the order can be made and the necessary notice given. And the city council shall have full authority to designate the day for such elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion; and provided further, that the presiding officer, for the first, elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion under this act, may be appointed at any time prior to such election.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That section five (5) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Sec. 5. At the first biennial election there shall be elected, by the qualified voters of said city, voting by ballot, a mayor, who shall hold his office for two years from the date of said election, and until his suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessor shall be elected and qualified; at the same time there shall be elected one alderman from each ward of the city by the qualified voters of such ward, who shall hold his office for two years, from the date of said election, and until his successor shall be elected and qualified. The person receiving the highest number of votes in the whole city for mayor shall be declared elected; and the person receiving the highest number of votes cast for alderman in their respective wards, shall be declared elected. In case the person elected mayor shall refuse to accept the office, the city council, mayor or acting mayor shall order another election; and in case of a vacancy in the office of mayor by death, resignation, removal or otherwise, it shall be filled for the remainder of the term by a new election, to be ordered by the city council, or acting mayor. And<pb n="489" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>in case of vacancy in the office of alderman by a refusal to accept or qualify, or by death, resignation, removal or otherwise, the city council, mayor or acting mayor shall order a new election to fill the residue of the unexpired term; and all special elections shall be conducted in the same manner as is herein provided for the biennial election; provided, that in special elections, five days notice thereof shall be deemed sufficient.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That Section six (6) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereinafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Sec. 6. The manner of conducting and voting at elections to be held under this act, and contesting the same, the keeping of the poll list, can<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vassing of the votes, and certifying the returns, shall be the same as nearly as may be, as is now, or may hereafter be provided by-law at gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral State elections; provided, the city council shall have full power and authority to regulate elections and pass all ordinances in relation thereto, not inconsistent with the general laws of the State which they may deem proper and necessary, and to prescribe what action shall be had in the event of there being no biennial election, or a failure to elect the officers, or any of them, for which any election was ordered; and to prescribe the manner and mode of determining contested elections. The voting shall be by ballot, and the managers shall take the same oath and shall have the same power and authority as the managers of general State elections. After closing the polls the ballots shall be counted in the manner re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired by law; and the returns, including the ballots, shall be returned to the city clerk within three days after the election; and within five days from the election, the city council shall meet and canvass the same and declare the result of the election; or, failing to meet at the specified time, shall proceed to- canvass said returns at the next subsequent meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing. It shall be the duty of the city clerk to notify all persons elected or appointed to office of their election or appointment and unless said per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons shall respectively qualify within five days thereafter the office shall become vacant, except in case of sickness or unavoidable accident. The city council shall meet at the usual place of meeting at 4 o&#8217;clock p. m., on the second Wednesday after the first Monday of March, or as soon thereafter as possible and the newly elected members shall be installed under the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That Section (11) eleven of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Sec. 11. Every person elected by the voters of said city, or by the city council on the nomination of the mayor, or appointed by the mayor to fill any office under this act shall before he enters on the duties of his office, take and subscribe the official oath prescribed in the Constitution of this State; and the city council may by ordinance require such addi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional oath as they may deem best calculated to secure faithfulness in the performance of their duties by such officers.</p>
<p>Section 6. That Section fourteen (14) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 14. The mayor shall preside over the meetings of the city council, but shall have no vote unless there is a tie, in which case he shall give the easting vote. Tie shall have like power with a justice of the peace, to administer oaths of office, and also all oaths and affirma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions and to give, certificates thereof. He shall possess and execute in the city, in criminal cases, all the powers and duties of a justice of the peace. He shall be compensated for his services by a salary of three<pb n="490" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>thousand dollars per annum payable at stated periods, and shall receive such fees as may be allowed by law, which fees shall be paid into the city treasury. He shall have power to remove any officer holding office under the appointment of the mayor and any member of the police force, and to suspend any officer (except alderman) holding an office created by this charter, or any ordinance of the city, under any authority other than that of appointment by the mayor. He may fill by appointment any va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cancy occasioned by the exercise of his said power of removal. He may fill by appointment any vacancy occasioned by the exercise of his said power of suspension/until the cause of such suspension can be acted on by the city council, and may fill by appointment any vacancy so occa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioned. He shall have authority in case of a riot, or any unlawful assem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />blage, or with a view to preserve peace and good order in said city, to or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der and enforce the closing of any theatre, ball room, grog shop, tippling shop, bar room, or other place of resort, or public room or building and may order the arrest of any person violating in his presence the laws of the State, or any ordinance of the city; and he shall perform such other duties, and possess and exercise such other power and authority as may be prescribed and conferred by the city council.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That Section fifteen (15) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 15. In case of a vacancy in the office of mayor, or of his be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing unable to perform the duties of his office by reason of temporary or continued absence or sickness, the aldermen shall appoint by ballot, by a majority of all the aldermen present, one of their number to act in his stead, whose official designation shall be acting mayor: and the alderman so appointed shall be be invested with all the powers and shall perform all the duties of mayor of the city, and shall receive the salary of mayor during such vacancy; provided, it shall continue for ten days or longer; and during that time the mayor shall receive no salary. And during such temporary exercise of the functions of mayor, it shall be the duty of the acting mayor to daily report, his presence at the city clerk&#8217;s office, and he shall continue to exercise such functions until such time as the mayor shall report in person at the city clerk&#8217;s office and duly record his presence in writing, or until the acting mayor shall be removed by the aldermen, as provided by this charter; but he shall not vote as an aider<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man while acting; as mayor.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That Section sixteen (16) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 16. All ordinances and resolutions adopted by the city coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil, and all acts of the council authorizing or making any contract, grant or concession, whether such act be had or passed in response to petition or proposition, or in any other manner whatsoever, and irrespective of the form of such acts, shall be subject to veto by the mayor. Such ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nances, resolutions and acts of the council, together with such papers as may pertain thereto, shall be placed in the office of the city clerk, and if the mayor approve thereof he shall endorse the same, &#8220;approved,&#8221; and sign his name to such endorsement, and thereupon such ordinances, res<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />olutions and acts shall go into effect. If the mayor shall fail to approve any such ordinance, resolution or act for a longer period than five days after it shall be placed in the clerk&#8217;s office, it shall go into effect, un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />less he shall have within said period, signified his disapproval thereof, by returning it to the clerk&#8217;s office, together with his written objections thereto, for the consideration of the city council. The vote by which<pb n="491" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>any ordinance, resolution or act so disapproved by the mayor was passed, shall be reconsidered by the city council either at the next regular meet<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing thereof held after such disapproval is filed in the clerk&#8217;s office, or at a special meeting called earlier for that purpose, and if after such recon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sideration, two-thirds of the aldermen elected agree to pass such ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance, resolution or act, it shall be in force, but not otherwise. No ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance, resolution or act appropriating money, or authorizing or making any contract, grant or concession involving an appropriation of money, or a relinquishment of any property, right, interest, or franchise shall be passed or had by the city council except by a vote of two-thirds of the aldermen elected east therefor.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That Section eighteen (18) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 18. The chief of police shall, either in person or by deputy attend upon the recorder&#8217;s court while said court is in session, and shall promptly and faithfully execute all writs and process issued from said court. He shall be the chief police officer of the city under the mayor. He shall have like power with the sheriff of the county to execute the writ of search warrant. He shall be active in quelling riots, disorders, and disturbances of the peace within the limits of said city, and shall take into custody all persons so offending against the peace of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />try and he shall have authority to take suitable and sufficient bail for the appearance before the recorder&#8217;s court, of any person charged with an offence against the ordinances and laws of the city. It shall be his duty to arrest all violators of the public peace, and all persons who shall obstruct or interfere with, him in the execution of the duties of his office, or who shall be guilty of disorderly conduct or disturbances whatsoever. To prevent a breach of the peace, or preserve quiet and good order, he shall have authority to close any theatre, bar room, ball room, drinking house or any other place or building of public resort; and in the preven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and suppression of crime and arrest of offender, he shall have, pos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sess and execute like power, authority and jurisdiction as a sheriff of a county under the laws of the State. He shall receive a salary of two thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars per annum. The chief of police shall give such bond for the faithful performance of his duties as the city council may require and he shall perform such other duties and possess such other powers, rights and authority as the city council may, by ordinance require and confer, not inconsistent with the Constitution and laws of this State, or the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That Section (20) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 20. That it shall be the duty of the city clerk to attend every meeting of the city council and keep accurate minutes of the proceedings thereof in a hook to be provided for that purpose; to engross and enroll all laws, resolutions and ordinances of the city council: to keep the corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rate seal; to take charge of, preserve and keep in order all hooks, records, papers, documents and files of said council: to countersign all commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions issued to the city officers, and licenses issued by the mayor; and to keep a record or register thereof, and to make out all notices required under any regulation or ordinance of the city. He shall draw all war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rants on the treasurer, to be signed by the mayor, and by the auditor, and countersign the same, and keep an accurate account thereof in a hook to be provided for the purpose. He shall also be clerk of the recorder&#8217;s court, and shall have custody of all books and papers belonging to said<pb n="492" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>court. He shall make out all process and writs, and enter upon a docket all complaints for violation or infraction of city ordinances before the recorder, and his judgment and sentence therein. He shall have power and authority to administer all oaths and affirmations. The city clerk shall be the general accountant of the corporation, and shall keep in books regular accounts of the real, personal and mixed property of the city, of all receipts and disbursements of the city and separately, under proper heads each cause of receipt and disbursement. And also accounts with each person, including officers who have money transactions with the city, crediting amounts allowed by proper authority and specifying the particular transaction to which such entries apply. He shall also keep a register of bonds and bills issued by the city, and all evidence of debt due and payable to it, noting the particulars thereof, and of all facts connected therewith as they occur. He shall carefully keep all contracts made by the city, and he shall do and perform all such other duties as may be required of him by any law, ordinance, resolution or order of the city council. He shall receive for his services a salary of eighteen hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars per annum; and for the faithful discharge of his duties he shall give bond, with good security to the city, for such sum as may be required by the city council, not less than two thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That Section twenty-one (21) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 21. The treasurer of said city shall give bond in favor of the city of Galveston, in such amount and in such form as may be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired by the city council, not less than fifty thousand dollars, and with sufficient sureties, conditioned for the faithful discharge of his duties. He shall receive and securely keep all moneys belonging to the city, and make all payments for the same, upon the order of the mayor, attested by the clerk, and auditor and the seal of the corporation. He shall render a full and correct statement of his receipts and payments to the city coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil at their regular meeting in every quarter and whensoever at other times he may be required by them to do so; and at the end of every half year he shall cause to be published, at the expense of the city, a statement showing the amount of receipts and expenditures for the six months next preceding, and the general condition of the treasury; and he shall do and perform such other acts as the city council may require; and for his services he shall receive such salary as shall be fixed by the city coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil, not, to exceed twelve hundred dollars per annum.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That Section twenty-two (22) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 22. That the assessor of the city shall make up all the as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessments of all property taxed by the city, including license and occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pation taxes and make rolls thereof, and on completion of the rolls, and when accepted by the city council, after twenty days public notice, shall deliver such assessment rolls to the collector, and the inventory lists to the auditor; provided, also, that supplemental rolls may be handed in from time to time, as may be prescribed by ordinance. The collector shall collect all taxes due the city, and in the event of non-payment of any taxes or licenses, shall proceed to sell property to raise the amount of taxes so due, and shall in the performance of his duties observe the provisions of this act and the ordinance of the city relating thereto. He shall give bonds in such amount and in such form as the city council may provide, not less than twenty five thousand dollars, with good and sufficient sure<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="493" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ties; and the city council may require a new bond whenever in their opinion the existing bonds is insufficient; and whenever such bond is re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired he shall perform no official act until said bond shall be given and approved. He shall, at the expiration of every week, pay to the treasurer all money by him collected, and shall report to the city council at the first meeting of that body in every month, all moneys so collected and paid, and he shall perform all such other duties, and in such manner and according to such rules and regulations as the city council may pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe. The assessor shall receive for his services an annual salary or com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission not to exceed two thousand dollars; and shall give security to the city for the faithful discharge of his duties in an amount not less than ten thousand dollars. The collector shall receive for his services an annual salary or commission not to exceed twenty four hundred dollars, and shall give bond, with good security, to the city for such sum as may be required by the city council, not less than twenty five thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars. The assessor is authorized to require the owners of all property subject to taxation to render a correct account of the same under oath, to be administered by him.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That section twenty three (23) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that it shall hereafter be as follows, to wit;</p>
<p>Section 23. It shall be the duty of the auditor to examine in detail all bills, accounts and claims against the city, and if found correct, sign his name in approval; but if found incorrect, he shall return them to the appropriate committee, or the city council with his objections thereto. It shall also be his dirty to examine the books of all the officers, of the city, and if they should be found incorrect, to make a report of the same to the city council. It shall also be his duty to act as assistant to the city clerk, and he shall render such other services from time to time as the city council may direct, and shall receive for his services such com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation as the city council may determine, not to exceed eighteen hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars per annum, and shall give bond for the faithful performance of his duties in the sum of ten thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That Section twenty six (26) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows to wit:</p>
<p>Section 26. The city council shall hold stated meetings, and the mayor may of his own motion, or on the application of three aldermen, call special meetings by notice to each of the members of said council, served personally or left at their usual place of abode; provided, that in case of emergency, such as the inability of the mayor, because of serious sickness, or absence from the city, or in the event of the death of the mayor, the city clerk shall, on the application of three aldermen, call a meeting of the council. Petition and remonstrances may be presented to the council in writing only; and the council shall determine the rules of its own proceedings, and be the judge of the election and qualifications of its own members, and punish them for disorderly conduct; and with the concurrence of two thirds of the aldermen elected may expel a member.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That Section twenty eight (28) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 28. That the city council shall not borrow for general or special purposes more than fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) in any one year; provided, that this restriction shall not be construed as a limitation upon the power of the council to create and maintain an indebtedness on the part of said city, for all purposes, general and special, not exceeding<pb n="494" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>in the aggregate the amount of indebtedness authorized by section 132 of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That Section twenty nine (29) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 29. The city council shall have power to appropriate money to provide for the payment of debts and expenses of the city. In the month of November of each year it shall make a careful estimate of all the probable revenues of the city for the ensuing year, and shall provide for the disbursement and expenditure of the same, as follows:</p>
<p>First&#8212;It shall set, apart and appropriate to the payment of the interest upon outstanding bonds such amounts as shall have been prescribed by ordinances for that purpose; and shall also set apart and appropriate to the creation and maintenance of sinking funds, for the redemption of said bonds, such amounts as shall have been prescribed by ordinances for that purpose; which said sinking funds shall be invested in bonds of said city in bonds of the State of Texas, or in bonds of the United States as said council may from time to time determine.</p>
<p>Second&#8212;It shall reserve a fund of twenty five thousand dollars, to- he used only in cases of extraordinary emergency, which could not have been foreseen before their occurrence; but in no event to be used for the ordinary expenses of the city; and whenever there shall remain unex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended any portion of such reserve fund, the same shall constitute a part of such reserve fund for the next ensuing year.</p>
<p>Third&#8212;It shall apportion the remainder of the estimated revenue to the several departments of the city government for its general expenses. Any member of the city council who shall knowingly vote for, or in any manner aid or promote the passage or adoption of any ordinance, resolu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion or other act of the city council, increasing the appropriations for the expenses of the city beyond the estimate aforesaid, unless the actual revenues shall have exceeded such estimate, and in such event beyond such actual revenues, shall thereby vacate his office and shall be deemed guilty of malfeasance in office and upon conviction thereof, shall be pun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ished in the manner and to the extent provided in section thirty one (31) of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That Section thirty (30) of said act be and the same is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 30. If the mayor or acting mayor shall sign any warrant, draft, or order for money upon the city treasurer when there are no funds in the treasury to pay the same, the officer so signing such war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant, draft, or order shall be liable to removal from office.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That Section fifty-one (51) of this act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 51. To establish, standard weights and measures to be used within the city, in all cases not otherwise provided for by law. To re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire all traders and dealers in merchandise, or property of any descrip<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, which is sold by weight or measure, to cause their weights and measures to be tested and subjected to inspection in such manner as may be by ordinance prescribed.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. That Section fifty-two (52) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 52. To regulate the inspection of beef, pork, flour, meal, san and other provisions; whisky and other liquors to be sold in barrels, hogsheads, and other vessels, and packages, and of gas metres; to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point weighers, gaugers and inspectors; and prescribe their duties and<pb n="495" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>regulate their fees; provided, that such officers shall be entitled to no fees, unless required to exercise the duties of their office, by and at the request of the parties purchasing, selling, or owning such articles; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that public weighers appointed by the Governor under authority of the Legislature for the city of Galveston, shall in no way be inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fered with, and the produce which they were appointed to weigh, shall not be weighed by the city weighers.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. That Section eighty-two (82) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 82. The city council shall have power to provide by ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance for the assessing and collection of taxes aforesaid,, and to determine when taxes shall be paid by corporations, and when by the individual corporators; provided, no tax shall be levied unless by consent of two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds of the aldermen elected. The license and occupation taxes shall be assessed by the assessor and collected by the collector, and shall be paid to that officer by each and every person and firm owing such license, and before engaging in any trade, profession, business, calling, vocation, or occupation, subject to said tax: that if any person shall engage in any business, calling, vocation, or occupation, which by an ordinance of said city is subject to a license tax, without first having obtained said license, he, she or they shall be liable to imprisonment, and a fine of ten dollars for each day such violation of said ordinance may continue; and this section shall apply to all persons owing any license and failing to pay the same. Said tax levied as herein provided shall not be construed to be a tax on property within the meaning of Section 79 of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. That Section ninety (90) of said act be and the same is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 90. Every person, partnership, and corporation, owning prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty within the limits of the corporation shall, within two months after published notice, hand into the assessor of the city a full and complete inventory of the property possessed or controlled by him, her or them, within said limits, not exempt from taxation, on the first day of January, of the current year, verified as required by ordinance; and any person failing or refusing to comply with the provisions of this section, shall be liable to fine and imprisonment, and the city council shall, by ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance, clearly define the duties of tax payers herein, and make all neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary rules and regulations to secure the rendition of property and the collection of taxes due thereon.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. That Section ninety one (91) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 91. That it shall be the duty of the city council annually, at such time as they may determine, to appoint three commissioners, each being a qualified voter and the owner of real estate in said city to the value of three thousand dollars, who shall be styled the Board of Ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />praisement, and whenever the party rendering property for assessment and the assessor cannot agree on the valuation of such property, it shall be referred to said board, and their action in appraising the same shall be final; provided, that at the meeting of said board the owner of the prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty shall be heard, and due notice of the meeting and session of said board shall be given by publication for ten days. Said board shall also appraise all property assessed as unknown or undrendered, and such ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />praisement shall be final. The city council shall allow said board such compensation for their services as they may think just and reasonable.<pb n="496" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>No person connected with the city government shall be appointed on said board, and any vacancy shall be filled by the council.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. That Section one hundred and seventeen (117) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter, it shall be as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 117. There shall be created a Board of Health which shall consist of six citizens, one from each two contiguous wards, extending from bay to gulf, and three practicing physicians from the city at large, all of whom shall be taxable inhabitants of the city. Five members of the board shall constitute a quorum. They shall be appointed by the mayor with the approval of a majority of the city council, at their first annual meeting, or as soon thereafter as practicable, at a regular meeting. One physician and two citizens shall be appointed for three years, one physi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cian and two citizens for two years, and one physician and two citizens for one year; and annually thereafter the mayor, with like approval, shall appoint one physician and two citizens to be members of the said board for the term of three years, and all vacancies shall be filled in like manner, for unexpired terms. And they shall be subject to suspension or removal as in cases of other officers of the city.</p>
<p>Sec. 24. That Section one hundred and twenty-seven (127) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 127. The city council shall be invested with full power and authority to grade, shell, repair, pave, or otherwise improve any avenue, street or alley, or any portion thereof, within the limits of said city, whenever by a vote of two-thirds of the aldermen elected they may deem such improvement for the public interest; provided, the city council pay one-third and the owners of the property two-thirds thereof; ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cept the intersection of the streets from lot to lot across the streets, either way, shall be paid by the city alone. Said two-thirds of said costs to be paid by the owners of the property fronting on said thoroughfares, shall be assessed on, or against said property and collected by the city whenever such improvement is completed and accepted by the city coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil: provided, further, that not more than twenty thousand (20000) superficial yards of such thoroughfares shall be filled, graded and shelled, or filled graded and paved, in any one year.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. That Section one hundred and twenty-eight (128) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 128. That the city council before beginning any such im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provements, shall, for the purpose of acquiring the most reliable infor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mation practicable, of the probable cost thereof, cause an estimate to be made of said probable cost by the city engineer, or by some other officer of the city, or by a committee of aldermen; and such officer, or commit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tee, shall also report a full list of all fronting lots or fractional lots with number and size of same, and number of block in which situated, and the names of the owners thereof, and such other information as may be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired by the city council; and if there be any lot or fractional lot, the owner whereof is not known, the same shall be entered on said list as unknown; and said officer or committee shall enter in said list, opposite each lot or fractional lot, lying and being on each side of the street, ave<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nue, or alley the improvement whereof is contemplated, one-third of the estimated expense of such work or improvement on such avenue, street or alley, fronting, adjoining, or opposite such lot or fractional lot: upon<pb n="497" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>consideration of said report of said officer or committee, the council shall determine whether or not the said work or improvement shall be made, and shall proceed accordingly; when said work or improvement is or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dered by the council, and shall have been completed, the council shall cause an accurate report of the cost thereof to be made by said officer or committee. As part of said report, said officer or committee shall present a list of the lots or fractional lots lying and being on each side of the street, avenue, or alley so improved, and upon such list of lots or frac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional lots shall be entered opposite each lot or fractional lot, one-third of the actual cost and expense of such work or improvement on said avenue, street or alley, fronting, adjoining, or opposite such lot or fractional lot; and upon the acceptance and approval of said report and List by the city council, said amounts shall be imposed, levied and assessed by the city council on said lots or fractional lots respectively, and collected by the collector, and shall be a lien upon the property until paid.</p>
<p>Sec. 26. That. Section one hundred and thirty-five (135) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 135. The territory contained within the boundary of the city of Galveston shall be divided into twelve wards, as follows: The first ward shall contain all the territory lying north of Avenue G, and east of Thirteenth street. The second ward shall contain all the territory lying north of Avenue G, between Thirteenth and Seventeenth streets. The third ward shall contain all the territory lying north of Broadway, between Seventeenth and Twenty-first streets. The fourth ward shall contain all the territory lying north of Broadway, between Twenty-first and Twenty-fifth streets. The fifth ward shall contain all the territory lying north of Broadway, between Twenty-fifth and Twenty-ninth streets. The sixth ward shall contain all the territory lying north of Broadway, between Twenty-ninth street and the western boundary of the city. The seventh ward shall contain all the territory lying south of Broadway, between Twenty-ninth street and the western boundary of the city. The eighth ward shall contain all the territory lying south of Broadway, between Twenty-fifth and Twenty-ninth streets. The ninth ward shall contain all the territory lying south of Broadway, between Twenty-first and Twenty-fifth streets. The tenth ward shall contain all the territory lying south of Broadway, between Seventeenth and Twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />first streets. The eleventh ward shall contain all the territory lying south of Avenue G, between Thirteenth and Seventeenth streets. The twelfth ward shall contain all the territory lying south of Avenue G, and east of Thirteenth street; provided, that the city council of said city shall have power from time to time to cause a division of said city to be made into as many wards (not less than twelve) as they may deem necessary and for the good of the inhabitants of said city: but no such division shall be made, unless it be done at least three months preceding the city election next ensuing; and said wards so established shall contain, so far as practicable, an equal number of voters; provided, that if any vacancy shall occur in the office of aldermen, while such division is be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing made, said vacancy shall be filled from the ward where said vacancy occurs, as is now provided by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 27. That Section one hundred and forty (140) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to-wit:</p>
<pb n="498" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Section 140. The city council shall during the second week in Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary, in each year, cause to be published in a city newspaper, a correct and full statement of the receipts and expenditures from the date of the last annual report, together with the sources from whence the funds are derived, and showing for what purpose disbursed: the condition of the treasury, together with such information as may be necessary to a full understanding of the financial condition of the city.</p>
<p>Sec. 28. That Section one hundred and forty two (142) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 142. There shall be. a digest of the ordinances of the city, which are of a-general nature, published within six months&#8212;or as soon as practicable thereafter&#8212;from the first Monday in March in 1883, and a like digest within every period of five years thereafter; provided, it shall be the duty of each city council, to cause to be printed in pamphlet form at the end of each municipal year all the ordinances passed for the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceding year.</p>
<p>Sec. 29. That Section one hundred and forty seven (147) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 147. No person other than an elector, resident of the city, shall be appointed or elected to any city office.</p>
<p>Sec. 30. That Section, one hundred and forty eight (148) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 148. Resignation by any officer authorized by this act to be appointed by the mayor, or appointed by the mayor and elected by the city council, shall be made to the mayor in writing, for his action.</p>
<p>Sec. 31. That Section one hundred and fifty one (151) of said act he and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 151. That when charges are so preferred against the mayor, they may be filed with either of the aldermen, whose duty it shall be to call the aldermen together, and when so assembled they shall proceed to elect one of their number to preside during said investigation, and for the purposes of said trial; the presiding officer so elected shall perform the duties of mayor, and the trial shall proceed as provided for in the last preceding section.</p>
<p>Sec. 32. That Section one hundred and fifty-seven (157) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 157. No member of the city council shall hold any other em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployment or office under the city government while he is a member of said council, unless herein otherwise provided; and no member of the city council, or any officer of the corporation shall be directly or indirectly interested in any work, business or contract, the expense, price or con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sideration of which is paid from the city treasury, or by an assessment levied by an ordinance or resolution of the city council, nor be the surety of any person having a contract, work or business with said city, for the performance of which security may be required. Any alderman or officer of the city violating the provisions of this section shall forfeit his seat in the council or office, and shall thereafter be ineligible to any office in or under the city government.</p>
<p>Sec. 33. That Section one hundred and fifty eight (158) of said act<pb n="499" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 158. The members of the city council shall be exempt from jury service during the term of office; each alderman shall be fined seven dollars for every meeting which he fails to attend, unless on account of his own sickness. Any member of the city council remaining absent for three consecutive meetings thereof, whether such meetings be regular, adjourned, special, or called meetings, seven days intervening between such meetings, without first having obtained leave of absence at a regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lar meeting shall be deemed to have vacated his office, and the mayor shall cause the vacancy to be filled in accordance with the charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 34. That Section one hundred and fifty nine (159) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 159. The city council shall have power to prescribe the duties of all officers and persons appointed or elected to any office or place whatsoever under this act. Subject to the provisions of this act, to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />voke any license given under this act; to remit in whole or in part, and on such conditions as shall be deemed proper, by a vote of two thirds of all the aldermen elected, any fine or penalty belonging to the city, which may be imposed, or incurred under this act, or under any ordinance or resolution passed in pursuance thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 35. That section one hundred and sixty one (161) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 161. The city council shall, on or before the first day of Jan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uary, in each and every year, fix the annual salary of all officers appointed or elected under this act, except those whose compensation is fixed by this act, and the compensation or salary so fixed shall not be changed during the year, for which the same are fixed.</p>
<p>Sec. 36. That section one hundred and seventy (170) of said act be and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 170. That no officer of this city shall receive a larger com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation for his services than at the rate of three thousand dollars per annum, and that no officer shall receive fees.</p>
<p>Sec. 37. That section one hundred and seventy one (171) of this act he and the same is hereby amended so that hereafter it shall be as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows, to wit:</p>
<p>Section 171. No salary not fixed or limited in this charter, shall ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed eighteen hundred dollars ($1800) per annum for any office which the city council are authorized to create.</p>
<p>Sec. 38. There shall be elected on the first Monday in March, 1884, one alderman in each of the odd-numbered wards, who shall hold their offices for one year and until their successors are elected and qualified. The first biennial election under this act shall be held on the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day in March 1885.</p>
<p>Sec. 39. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict or inconsistent with the provisions of this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 40. Whereas, an urgent necessity requires it, and a great public emergency exists that the city of Galveston shall have better defined power to improve its streets and secure the better government of said city, it is hereby enacted that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and the near approach of the election in said<pb n="500" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>city, and the early closing of the session of the Legislature, causes an imperative public necessity which justifies a suspension of the rule re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quiring this bill to be read on three several days and it is so suspended</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 7th, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect, from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 2.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of J. W. Chowning, H. Chowning, J. R. Sumner, W. P. Bean, R. F. Jones, J. A. Creager, J. P. Wilson, George W. Darby, C. M. Byars, J. A. Stingley, T. W. Linkhart &#38; Co., T. W. Robinson and Ull Musick, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and is hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to issue to T. W. Robinson as trustee for J. W. Chowning, H. (downing, J. R. Sumner, W. P. Bean, R. F. Jones, J. A. Creager, J. P. Wilson, George W. Darby, C. M. Byars, J. A. Stingley, T. W. Linkhart &#38; Co., T. W. Robinson and the heirs of Ull Musick, patents for all State school section number 18, for 640 acres of land, and the north half of State school section do. 64, for 640 acres of land; both of said sections being in block do. 12 of the Houston and Texas Central Railroad sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veys situated in Wilbarger county, Texas; the same being the land on which the town of Vernon, the county seat of Wilbarger county is now situated; provided, that the said T. W. Robinson, trustee as aforesaid shall within thirty days after the passage of this act, pay to the. Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer of the State the sum of two dollars per acre for said land, and file the Treasurers receipt for the same in the General Land Office and shall pay all fees due the State for the issuance of patents to the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the close of the session creates an im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perative public necessity for suspending the rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days, said rule is therefore suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 13, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 3.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Sections 7, 14, 21, 33, 35, 36, 40, and 45 of an Act incorporating the city of Houston in Harris county approved April 21st A. D. 1879 and Sections 23 and 31 of said Act as amended by an Act of the Legislature of the State of Texas, approved March 9th A. D. 1881 and substituting the following Sections therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Sections 7, 14, 21, 33, 35, 36, 40 and 45 of an Act incorporating the city of Houston approved April 21st A. D. 1879 and Sections 23 and 31 of said Act as amended by an Act of the Legislature of the State of Texas, approved March 9th A. D. 1881, be so amended as to hereafter read as follows.</p>
<p>Section 7. That each ward in the city shall be represented in the city council by two aldermen, who shall hold office for two years and until their successors are elected and qualified: said aldermen shall be elected by the qualified voters of the ward for which they stand, who<pb n="501" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall vote only in their respective wards. No person shall be competent to fill the office of alderman unless he be at the date of his election a qualified voter of the city, a freeholder therein and a bona fide resident of the ward for which he is elected.</p>
<p>Section 14. That there shall be a secretary and treasurer, a city marshal and ail assessor and collector of taxes, who shall be nominated by the mayor and confirmed by a majority vote of all the aldermen elected, to be taken by ballot. Said officers shall hold their respective offices for two years, and until their successors are duly qualified, unless sooner removed by the city council. The assessor and collector shall have authority to appoint one or more deputies, for whose acts and conduct he shall be responsible, and such deputy or deputies shall have power to perform any act which may be performed by the assessor and collector in person.</p>
<p>Section 21. That the by-laws and ordinances of the city shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />forced by fine not to exceed one hundred dollars, or by imprisonment in the city prison not to exceed thirty days, or by both fine and imprison<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment. Provided: that no ordinance or by-law shall provide a less, pen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alty than is prescribed for a like offense by the laws of the State. The city council may provide by ordinance for the commutation of fines im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed, by labor in a work house, on the streets or public works, and for the collection of any fine imposed execution may be issued from the mayor&#8217;s court, in the name of the mayor, aldermen and inhabitants of the city of Houston, against the goods and chattels, lands and tenements of the person offending.</p>
<p>Section 23. That the city council shall have the exclusive control and regulation of all streets, alleys, public grounds and highways within the corporate limits of the city, and shall have power to abate and remove encroachments or obstructions thereon in a summary manner; to open, alter, widen, extend, establish, grade, clean, pave or otherwise improve the same: to put drains and sewers therein, to permit, prevent and regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />late the laying of gas and water mains and pipes therein, to compel any person using the streets or sidewalks for the purpose of laying gas or water mains and pipes, or for building or other purposes, to repair said street or sidewalk so used by them, to prevent any street or sidewalk from being dug up, or excavations to be make therein, unless the same be done with the permission of the city council and under the direction of the city engineer, to prevent the encumbering thereof in any manner, and generally to protect the same from any encroachment or injury: to regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />late, establish and change the grade of all sidewalks, streets and premises, and to require and compel the filling up and raising of the same: to con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struct, regulate and keep in repair all bridges, culverts, sewers and cross<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings: and to control and regulate the use of the same. The city council shall have full power and authority to construct, regulate and keep in re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pair all necessary sidewalks and foot ways, to grade and fill up the same, to regulate the use and abate and remove any encroachments or obstruc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions thereon, and to punish any person by fine and imprisonment who shall encroach upon or obstruct the same, or who shall fail to have such encroachments withdrawn or such obstructions removed after being noti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied by the proper officer to remove or withdraw the same, and each day such encroachments or obstructions are permitted to remain after such notice is served shall constitute a separate offense. The council shall fix and determine the nature and extent of such sidewalk improvements, and decide as to the kind of material to be used, and the cost of the construe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="502" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>tion of all sidewalks and footways, and the cost of the grading, filling and curbing necessary therefor, together with the cost of collection thereof, shall be defrayed by the owner or owners of the lot or block fronting on the sidewalk or footway to be constructed, according to the number of feet frontage so owned by each, which sum shall be a tax and charge against the owner or owners of such lot or blocks, and a lien and encum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />brance upon the property itself, and said tax against the property owner may be collected and the lien upon the property foreclosed in any court having jurisdiction. The city council shall declare by resolution duly passed, upon which street or streets or parts or side of any street or streets such sidewalk improvements are to be constructed, the nature of the improvements to be made, and the kind of material to be used. After the adoption of such resolution it shall be the duty of the mayor to have specifications prepared by the city engineer in accordance with the terms of said resolution, which specifications when so prepared and adopted by the city council, shall be duly advertised, and bids solicited for constructing such improvements. It shall be the duty of the city council after accepting any bid for the construction or improvement of such sidewalks or footways to cause to be prepared by the city engineer a roll showing the number of the lots and blocks fronting on the side<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />walks or footways to be constructed, the names of the owner or owners of each lot, part of lot or block, or if unknown that fact shall be stated, the number of feet frontage owned separately by each person, or jointly with others, the cost per foot frontage of such improvements, and the total proportional cost of such improvement necessary, to be paid by each prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty owner fronting thereon. The correctness of said rolls shall be certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied to by the city engineer and submitted to the city council for its aproval. If said roll is approved and adopted by the city council, the amounts therein stated and asseseed against each property owner, or against one or more owners jointly, shall be a tax against such owner or owners and a lien, charge and encumbrance upon the property so owned and held by them, the amount assessed in said roll against the owner or owners of each lot or lots or blocks shall be divided into two equal parts, one part shall be payable when the improvements contracted to be made on each respective block shall be completed, and the balance shall become due six months thereafter. For such sums of money cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates shall be prepared and issued, signed by the mayor and attested by the secretary and treasurer under his official seal; each certificate shall show upon its face the amount for which it is drawn, the name of the property owner from whom the tax is owing, the number of feet frontage, and the number of the lot or lots and blocks upon which said sum of money is a lien; that said sum of money is a tax against the property owner named, and a lien upon said property described: the date when it will be payable, that it is issued for sidewalk improvements, the date of the resolution authorizing such sidewalks to be improved, and that it is issued by authority of this section of the charter, such certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates when so issued shall be delivered to the contractor or person en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to receive the same, as follows: One certificate for one half the sum assessed against each property owner, when the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective block in which such owners property is situated shall have been completed, and one certificate for the balance upon the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pletion of the contract and the acceptance of the work by by the mayor. Such certificate when so issued shall be evidence that all require<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments and prerequisites of the law have been complied with, and if not<pb n="503" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>paid at maturity may be collected by suit, and the lien therein provided for be foreclosed in any court of competent jurisdiction and such certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate shall bear interest at the rate of eight per cent per annum from the date thereof, which interest shall be expressed on the face of the certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate. The city council shall have full power and authority to grade, shell, pave, repair or otherwise improve any avenue, street, alley, or other highway, or any portion thereof within the limits of the city, when<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever by a vote of two-thirds of the aldermen elected, such improvements shall be declared necessary for the public interest, which grading, shell<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, paving or repairing shall be done at the cost and charge of the owner, or owners of the lot or lots, or block or blocks fronting on such alley, avenue, street or other highway to be improved, and the cost of such improvements, together with the expense of the collection thereof shall be a tax against the owner or owners of such lot or lots, or block or blocks, as well as a lien and encumbrance upon the property itself. The city council shall by resolution duly passed, designate the street or streets or portions thereof to be improved, the nature of the improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment to be made and the material to be used. It shall be the duty of the mayor after the passage of such resolution to have the necessary plans and specifications for such improvements prepared by the city engineer, which plans and specifications, after being approved by the city council shall be advertised together with the resolution aforesaid, and bids shall be solicited for the construction of such improvements. After a bid for the construction of such improvements shall have been accepted by the council, it shall be the duty of the mayor to cause to be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pared by the city engineer a roll showing the numbers of the lots, and blocks fronting on such street, alley or evenue to be improved, the names of the owner or owners of each lot, part lot or block, and if un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />known it shall be stated, the number of feet frontage owned separately by each person or jointly with others, the cost per square foot frontage of such improvements, and the total proportional cost of such improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment necessarry to be paid by each property owner fronting thereon, the correctness of said roll shall be certified to by the city engineer, and the roll submitted to the council for its approval. If said roll is ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the city council the sums of money therein stated and assessed against each property owner, or against one or more property owners jointly, shall be a tax against such owner or owners, and a lien, charge and encumbrance upon the property so held and owned by each. The sum assessed against each property owner on said roll shall be divided into two equal parts, one to be payable when the improvements con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tracted to be made on each respective block shall be completed, and the balance shall be due six months thereafter: for such sums of money certificates shall be prepared and issued, signed by the mayor and attested by the city secretary and treasurer under his of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ical seal, each certificate shall show upon its face the amount for which it is drawn, the name of the property owner from whom the tax is owing, the number of feet frontage, and the numbers of the lot or lots and block upon which said sum of money is a lien: that said sum of money is a tax against the property owner named and a lien upon the prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty described, the date when it will be payable: that, it is issued for street paving, naming the street, the date of the resolution authorizing the street to be paved or improved, and that it is issued by authorithy of this section of the charter. Such certificates when so issued, shall be deliv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ered to the contractor or person authorized by him to receive the same, as<pb n="504" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>follows: One certificate for one-half the sum assessed against each pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perty owner when the respective block in which such owners property is situated, shall have been completed and one certificate for the balance, upon the completion of the contract and the acceptance of the work by the mayor. Such certificate shall bear interest from the date thereof, at the rate of eight per cent per annum, which rate shall be expressed therein, and when issued in accordance with the provisions of this section shall be evidence that all the requirements and prerequisites of the law have been complied with. Should the property owner fail to pay the amount of such certificate when the same becomes due, the owner there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of may institute suit for the enforcement of the tax, and the foreclosure of the lien provided for, in any court having jurisdiction. Provided that the city alone shall pay for the improving of the intersections of the streets from block to block across the street either way: and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided further, that no one shall be made to pay for any improvement done on any street that may be paved or otherwise improved as herein<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />before provided, save for the proportional part of the street that may be in front of his property, and that any railroad or street railway com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall be liable for any grading, paving or other improvement made upon, any portion of said streets used or occupied by such companies. To secure the safety and convenience of passing in the streets, side<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />walks and other places in the city, to fix the squaring, and to prevent encroachments and obstructions on the streets, sidewalks, squares, ways, levees and public roads and places, to fix the place for anchoring all water craft on Buffalo Bayou: to establish an active system of inspec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion over the conduct of persons and premises, to prevent cattle, horses, swine, goats, geese and animals from running at large in the streets or within such prescribed limits as may be established by the city council, to establish and maintain a city police, prescribe the duties of police<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men and regulate their conduct; to provide for lighting the streets, and for this purpose may establish gas works for the manufacture of gas for the use of the city and inhabitants thereof at cost price, to determine<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in what part of the city slaughter houses, bone boilers, soap makers or other establishments for any business which is or may be injurious to the value of adjacent property or unwholesome or disagreeable to the occupants of adjacent property, shall not be allowed to be erected, to determine in what part of the city wooden buildings shall not be erected, within the limits prescribed no person shall be permitted to erect such buildings: to prevent gun powder or other explosive material, kerosene oil or other imflammable oils being stored within the city limits in such quantity as to endanger the safety of adjacent property; to provide means for the protection against an extinguishment of conflagrations and for the regulation, maintenance and support of a fire department: to per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit or forbid theatres, balls or other public amusements and to suppress the same whenever the preservation of order, tranquility, or public safety may require: to close dram shops, drinking saloons and other places where intoxicating liquors are sold, whenever necessary or expedient: to define what shall be nuisances in said city, and to abate them by summary proceedings: to provide a work house for vagabonds and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />orderly persons who are unable to pay fines, and to make regulations concerning the same; to regulate weights and measures in the city, affix penalties for violation, fix standards, &#38;c.; also that the city council may provide, own and maintain water works for the use of the city and its inhabitants; to provide and keep a city prison; to make all needful and<pb n="505" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>proper regulations concerning bakers, butchers, keepers of taverns, grog shops and other public houses, draymen, horse-drivers, water carriers, omnibus drivers, hack drivers and drivers of baggage wagons, and espe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cially to preserve order and prevent noise and confusion in and about the several depots on the arrival and departure of railway trains; to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vent extortion by carriers of passengers or baggage, hacks, drays and all public conveyances, by establishing maximum rates of charges, to direct and control the laying and construction of railroad tracks, turnouts and switches, and to require that they be constructed and laid so as to inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fere as little as possible with the ordinary travel and use of streets: to require railroad companies to keep the streets through which they run in repair, and to light the same whenever deemed necessary; to construct and keep in repair bridges and crossings at the intersection of streets and avenues and over all ditches, sewers and culverts on the line of the railway; to regulate the speed of engines and locomotives within said city; to control and regulate everything concerning street railways, and generally to make and establish all rules, regulations, by-laws and ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nances which may contribute to and promote the better administration of the affairs of said city, as well as for the maintenance of the peace, tranquility and safety of said city, and for the protection of the persons and property of its inhabitants. The city council of the city of Hous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton are hereby empowered and authorized to take and condemn land and real estate in said city to the public use, viz: for streets, alleys and public highways, for extending, straightening and widening those streets now in use, for public wharves and landing places for steamers and other water craft, and for public squares, parks and pleasure grounds. For the condemnation of any land or real estate, the following proceedings shall be had: The city attorney or attorneys employed by the city for that purpose, shall file a petition in the District Court of Harris county against the owner of the land or real estate sought to be condemned for any of the purposes aforesaid, setting forth; first, the name or names and residence of the owner or owners, if known, and if unknown, the same shall be stated; second, the description by metes and bounds of any actual survey had for that purpose, of the land or real estate sought to be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demned; third, the purpose for which the same is proposed to be taken and applied; fourth, the supposed value of the property to be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demned; fifth, the prayer that the same be condemned to the public use for the purpose stated, and upon the filing of such petition, like pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceedings shall be had thereon as in other civil suits, and when personal service cannot be had by reason of the defendant being a non-resident, or unknown, service by publication shall be made as provided in other cases in the district court, and upon trial the court shall proceed to ren<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der judgment, condemning the land to the public use, upon the payment of the value thereof as assessed by the jury, and upon any suit being brought thereafter against the said corporation for such property so con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demned, a copy of the judgment and an actual tender of the money in Court shall be sufficient answer in bar of a recovery in any such suit. All costs of proceedings for the condemnation of land and real estate under this act shall be taxed against the plaintiffs, including reasonable fees of the attorney, which the court shall appoint to represent the defendant when cited by publication. Ho person shall erect any building or fence in the city of Houston without first obtaining a permit in writing from<pb n="506" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the mayor and having the lines of his property established by the city engineer.</p>
<p>Sec. 31. [21] That the city council shall have power by ordinance an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually to levy, assess and collect a tax not exceeding two per cent ad va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lorem, upon all real and personal property in the city of Houston not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />empt from taxation, and to determine when taxes shall be paid by cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porations, or by the individual incorporators, and to levy, assess and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lect from each male citizen of the city, over the age of twenty-one years, an annual poll tax of one dollar. All taxes upon real estate shall be a lien and charge upon the property, which lien may be foreclosed, and the tax collected by suit, in any court having jurisdiction. All taxes not paid within the time prescribed by the ordinances shall bear interest at the rate of ten per cent per annum. All real and personal property held, owned or situated in the city of Houston shall be liable for all taxes due by the owner thereof, including taxes on real estate, personal property and poll tax, and all personal property may be levied upon, seized and sold by the assessor and collector, for any taxes that may be due, without fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ther warrant of authority than the production of his tax roll, which sale when made shall convey a perfect title to the purchaser thereof. It shall be the duty of every person owning, or holding property in the city of Houston to render to the assessor and collector of taxes at his office in said city annually, within the time prescribed by the ordinances of said city, a full and complete inventory of all property so owned or held by him, whether real or personal and to take and subscribe an oath as to the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectness of such inventory, which oath may be administered by the asses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sor and collector in person or by deputy. All taxes shall be payable at the office of the assessor and collector, and no demand by him shall be requi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />site or necessary to enforce the collection thereof by any proceedings herein prescribed. The assessor and collector shall inventory and assess all property which the owners thereof may fail or refuse or may have failed or refused to inventory and assess for any previous year, which inventory and assessment when so made by him shall be as valid and ef<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fective as if made by the owner thereof.</p>
<p>Section 33. That the city council may and shall have full power to provide by ordinance for the prompt collection of all taxes levied, assessed and due or becoming due to said city, and to that end may and shall make such rules and regulations and pass such ordinances as it shall deem necessary to the levying, laying, imposing, assessing and collecting of any of said taxes, and to regulate the mode and manner of making out tax lists and inventories, and the appraisement of property thereon, and to prescribe the oath that shall be administered to each person on such rendition of property, and to prescribe how and when property shall thus be rendered; and to fix the duties and define the powers of the assessor and collector of taxes; and adopt such measures as they may deem ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visable to secure the assessment of all property in the limits of the city, and collect the taxes thereupon in current money of the United States; or otherwise as herein provided, and may by ordinance provide that any person, firm or corporation having or controlling property in said city, subject to taxation, and failing and refusing to render a list, inventory and appraisement thereof, verified as may be required by any ordinance of said city shall be liable to fine and imprisonment; that the city coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil shall appoint annually from its own members, at such times as it may determine, three appraisers, who shall be styled the Board of Appraise<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="507" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ment and whenever the party rendering the property for assessment, and the assessor and collector can not agree in the valuation of such property, it shall be referred to said board and their action in appraising the same shall be final, unless notice of dissatisfaction with said action is given within five days after their decision; and the party giving such notice shall have the right of appeal to the council. It shall be the duty of said board of appraisement to meet at least once during every year, and carefully to examine the values of property rendered to the assessor and collector, and rendered by him for delinquents, and if it shall appear to said board that the values assessed are too low or too high, they shall have full power to raise or lower the same, and from the action of said board there shall be no appeal. Said board shall not raise the value on any property assessed for taxation by the owner thereof without first notifying such property owner of its intention to so raise the same, which notice shall be directed to the person giving in the assessment, and deposited in the post office in the city of Houston, and said notice shall be mailed at least three days before any action is taken by the board. The raising of the value of any property by said board shall be prima facie evidence that all require<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments of the law have been complied with. The city council may if it sees proper adopt, as circumstances will permit, the same mode and man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner of assessing and collecting taxes as may be prescribed by law for as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessing and collecting State taxes, and all taxes due the city may be col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected by an action of debt in any court having jurisdiction. The assess<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment roll shall be taken as prima facie evidence of the statement made therein, and the city shall have the equal right to become the purchaser at all the sales of property for taxes due it, made under judgment or otherwise. Nothing but current money of the United States shall be collected or received in payment of taxes and licenses due or hereafter assessed, and scrip which may be issued for pavement of streets and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structing side walks, and for city water works, which shall express upon its face the purpose for which it is issued, and coupons and script made receivable for taxes on the face thereof shall be receivable for all taxes except the bond tax.</p>
<p>Sec. 35. That it shall not be necessary in any action, suit or proceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing in which the mayor, aldermen and inhabitants of the city of Houston shall be a party, that any bond or security shall be given, but all actions, suits or proceedings shall be conducted as if such bond or security had been given and in all judicial proceedings it shall be sufficient to plead any ordinance of the city by caption without embodying the entire ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance in the pleadings; and all printed ordinances or codes of ordinances shall be admitted in evidence in any suit, and shall have the same force and effect as the original ordinance. The property, real and personal, belonging to the city shall not be liable to be sold or appropriated under any writ of execution, nor shall the funds belonging to the city in the hands of any person be liable to garnishment, nor shall the city or any of its officers or agents be required to answer to any writ of garnishment.</p>
<p>Sec. 36. That the following property shall be exempt from taxation, to wit: All lands used exclusively for graveyards, or grounds for bury<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the dead, except such as are held by any person, company or corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration with a view to profit, or for the purpose of speculation in the sale thereof; all buildings belonging to institutions of purely public charity, together with the lands belonging to and occupied by such institutions,<pb n="508" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>not leased or otherwise used with a view to profit, and all moneys and credits appropriated solely to sustaining such institutions, together with such other property as is exempt from taxation by the laws of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 40. That all works of improvements and public works for said city, the cost of which will exceed the sum of one thousand dollars, shall be let out to the lowest or best bidder in the discretion of the council, by sealed proposals, and no contract shall be made or entered into, until the plans and specifications for such work or improvement shall have been prepared and submitted to the council and adopted by it, and an adver<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tisement published in at least four issues of some daily paper published in the city, inviting bids therefor, and stating the time when such sealed proposals will be opened. Provided: that if no bids be received or those received be rejected by the city council, the city may in its discretion pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed to have such work or improvement done under the direction of a committee from its membership. City printing and all repairing of bridges or other similar work, of which it is manifestly impossible to make speci<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fications, are not embraced in this requirement. No bid shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sidered unless made in accordance with the plans and specifications, and no allowance for extra work shall ever be made or paid for. The sealed proposals shall be addressed to the city secretary and treasurer, and shall only be opened in the presence of the city council, at a regular meeting. Bond and security to be fixed and approved by the city council shall be required of all contractors. The taking of any contract, or any interest therein, openly or secretly, directly or indirectly, by any officer of the city, shall ip[s]o facto work a forfeiture of the contract and the consideration thereof, and shall create a vacancy in the office held by the party taking the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 45. That this act shall be deemed a public act, and judicial no<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice shall be taken thereof in all courts. No general law hereafter passed by the Legislature of the State shall be held to repeal any power herein granted, or which is now vested in the corporation of Houston, unless the act conferring such power be specially referred to in such repealing act. Whereas there are no laws in force, providing for the paving, im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proving and repairing of the streets and sidewalks of the city of Hous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton and for the collection and enforcement of the taxes due to the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration, and said corporation is greatly in need on that account, there exists an imperative public necessity for dispensing with the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional rule requiring this bill to be read on three several days in each house of the Legislature, and an emergency exists which requires this act, to take effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 13, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect after passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 4.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize and grant to E. S. Crosby the right to construct, maintain and use a boom across the Brazos river in McLen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nan county, for the stoppage of floating material.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That E. S. Crosby of McLennan county, his heirs and assigns are hereby<pb n="509" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>authorized, and the right and privilege is hereby granted him for the period of ten years, to construct, and for said period of time to maintain and use a boom across the Brazos river in said county, within one mile of the suspension bridge across said river in the city of Waco; which boom is to be used for arresting the progress of timber, wood, lumber and other material floating on said river; provided, said boom shall be so constructed as to provide at one end thereof, a passage way that may be opened for the passage of boats up and down said river, but such boom shall not be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to be opened when the same is under tension by reason of floating material pressing against it; provided further, that said boom shall only be used when necessary to catch the timber being floated by him the said Crosby, and shall-be constructed so as not to interfere with the right, nor cause delay to any one, nor interfere with any one who may be engaged in a like business.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 20, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 5.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act defining the boundaries of the corporation of the city of Gonzales, for municipal purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the boundaries of the city of Gonzales, for municipal purposes, shall be as hereinafter described, to wit: Beginning at a point on the Guad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alupe river where a street that divides Ranges one (1) and two (2) west of Water street, intersects said river; thence north along the centre of said street or road to the northwest corner of Block No. 4, in Range No. 1, west of Water street; thence, east along the north boundary line of said block No. 4, to the north boundary line of lot No. 7, on North Avenue; thence east along the north boundary lines of lots numbered seven (7) in Ranges Nos. 1, 2, 3 and 4, east of Water street, to the centre of the street dividing Ranges Nos. 4 and 5; thence south with the centre of said street to the east boundary line of Lot No. 6 in tier on No. 2 on East Avenue; thence south with said east boundary of Lot No. 6, across East Avenue and with the east boundary line of Lot No. 6, in Tier No. one (1), south to a point opposite the south east corner of Green Dewitts homestead lot; thence with the south boundary line of said Green Dewitt&#8217;s lot to the Guadalupe river; thence up said Guadalupe river with its meanders, to the point of beginning.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted: That the boundaries of the said city of Gonzales shall not be extended except by the consent or vote of a two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds majority of the legal voters residing upon the territory proposed to be annexed to the said city of Gonzales.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted: That whereas an imperative necessity exists for the immediate passage of this act, and for the suspending of the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, therefore said rule is hereby suspended and this act shall be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 24, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect after passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="510" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 6.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the patenting and disposition of the lands situated in Medina county State of Texas, for which certificates were issued by the State to Henry Castro, in trust for school and church purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the lands heretofore granted to Henry Castro in trust for church and school purposes, lying and being situated in Medina county State of Texas, for the benefit of the people of said Medina county, shall be pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ented to the said Medina county, in trust for the benefit of the public free schools of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Commissioner of the General Land Office of the State of Texas is hereby authorized and directed, as soon after the pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sage of this act as possible, to patent all of said lands granted to the said Henry Castro, in compliance with section first of this act, and deliver said patents to the commissioners court of said Medina county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said lands from and after the issuance of said patents shall be subject to sale, and proceeds of said sale disposed of by the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners&#8217; court of Medina county under the same rules and regulations as are provided in Title LXXXI, Chapter 3, page 581 of the Revised Statutes of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Whereas the said lands are lying unoccupied, unimproved and useless to the people of said Medina county, and that the people of said county need the proceeds from sale of said lands for the benefit of the public free schools of said county, creates a public emergency that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days before their final passage be suspended, that said constitutional rule be, and the same is hereby suspended, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 24, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 7.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amendatory of an act approved August 9th 1876 entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the city of Dallas, and grant a new charter to said city&#8221; and the amendments thereto.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the following numbered Sections of the charter of the city of Dal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />las be amended so as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the bounds and limits of the city of Dallas shall be as follows: Beginning at a point on the north corporation line of the pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent corporate limits of said city, where the track of the Missouri Pacific railroad crosses said line; thence with the line of said railroad to a point where said railroad track crosses the northwest line of the John Grigsby league; thence north 46&#189; east, with said league line the division line be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween both No. 8 and No. 9 of said league; thence with said division line south 54 east through to the southeast line of said league; thence with said southeast league line in a southwesterly direction to the south corner of said league; thence north 42 west with the southwest line of<pb n="511" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the said league, to a point where the said line intersects the south line of the present limits of said city, as established by an act of the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture approved August 9th 1876 entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the city of Dallas and grant a new charter to said city;&#8221; thence westerly with said present south line to the Trinity river; thence up said Trinity river to the northwest corner of said present corporation; thence with the north line of said present corporation to the place of beginning; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided: That the new territory added to the city of Dallas by this act shall not become a part of said corporation until a majority of those liv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing in said new territory who are qualified to vote for members of the Legislature shall have voted to have such territory added to said city: when a majority of such qualified voters shall have so determined, from such date such territory or any part thereof as set out in petition and determined by vote shall for all purposes become a part of said city of Dallas. Whenever as many as forty qualified voters shall petition the county judge of Dallas county, he shall order an election to be held in the territory added by this act, or sought to be added as set out in the petition, and he shall appoint judges to hold such election under the forms of law, and he shall appoint a time and place for said election to be held, and give public notice thereof for twenty days by publication in some daily newspaper published in the city of Dallas. The county judge shall issue an order for the election within ten days after the afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mentioned petition is filed with him, and within ten days after the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion is held shall announce the result to the city council of the city of Dallas, who shall pass such ordinances as are necessary to have surveyed and fully defined the boundaries of the new addition to said city. The county judge shall not order an election for the above purposes unless the petition is first approved by a majority of the board of aldermen of the city of Dallas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That section 21 of the charter of the city of Dallas be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 21. The city council may at any time after the adoption of this act, by ordinance establish the office of recorder of said city and or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der the election of a suitable person to fill the same, and when elected and qualified he shall be the chief judicial magistrate of the city, and shall hold his office until his successor is elected and qualified, the election of whom shall be at the next general election of city officers, and as such shall hold a court within said city by the name of recorder&#8217;s court of the city of Dallas, which said court shall have concurrent jurisdiction and cognizance of all misdemeanors, breaches of the peace, infractions of the ordinances, and all other causes arising under the laws of said city: and said court shall also have concurrent jurisdiction of all misdemeanors arising under the criminal laws of this State within said city limits, in which the punishment is by fine only, or by fine or by imprisonment, or by both: provided, that no fine shall exceed two hundred dollars, or period of imprisonment exceed thirty days in the city jail; and provided further, that said court shall have concurrent jurisdiction of all cases for keeping disorderly houses, or houses of prostitution within the limits of said city. And said court shall be deemed always open for the trial of said causes. Said court shall have full power, authority and concurrent jurisdiction in all cases arising under the ordinances of said city, or the State law as hereinbefore limited; and over any breaches and violations thereof, and of any and all persons thus offending including vagrants, gamblers, prostitutes and keepers of disorderly houses, and to try and<pb n="512" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>determine all suits, accounts and complaints charging a violation of any ordinance or aforesaid laws, and may grant new trials on motion in writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, showing sufficient cause and duly sworn to; and all prosecutions, trials and proceedings had in said court under this act shall be governed by the laws and rules regulating trials and prosecutions and proceedings in justice&#8217;s court, in force at the time, and shall be a bar to prosecutions for the same offence in other courts. Said officer shall be entitled to such compensation for his services as the council may provide: provided, the city shall pay no costs; and to such additional compensation as may be allowed by the laws and ordinances of the corporation. The recorder may require of any person arrested under the provisions of this act, a bond for his or her good behavior, and to keep the peace, or for his or her appearance before said court with two good and sufficient sureties, which bond, as well as all other bonds taken in any proceeding in said court shall be payable to the city of Dallas. He shall have full power and authority to issue subp&#339;nas for witnesses, and to compel their attend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance by process of an attachment. He may punish all contempts by fine or imprisonment, or either; may issue subp&#339;nas, writs of capias, warrants of arrest, search warrants, executions and all process known to law which a justice of the peace of this State may lawfully issue: and all of said writs and process shall run in the name of the city of Dallas, be issued, served and executed in the same manner as the like process would be when issued by a justice of the peace, unless herein otherwise provided. He shall also have full power and authority to administer official oaths, and all oaths and affirmations, and give certificates therefor. The re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corder shall be exofficio justice of the peace, and he shall possess and ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ecute in the city in criminal cases all the powers and duties of such officer, and shall have the same authority and like power with justices of the peace in the prevention and suppression of crime; provided, that in no case shall be entertain jurisdiction in civil suits. The city council may determine what costs, if any, shall be charged for proceedings in, and for all process issued in said court, and shall allow the judge thereof for his services such salary or fees, or either, or both, as they deem necessary; and the recorder shall perform such other duties as may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by any ordinance of said corporation that may properly and law<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fully be required of said officer as the judge of said court, and as are not inconsistent with the laws and Constitution of this State: provided, that all money collected from fines of whatever character imposed by the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corder, shall be paid into the city treasury for the use of the city, and provided further, that until the said office of recorder is established, and a recorder is elected, or when the same shall be discontinued, or a va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cancy occur therein, the mayor of the city shall possess and execute all the powers and duties of recorder, holding a court which shall be known as the mayors court as set forth in this section, and that may be imposed by ordinance of the city, and shall receive for his services such compen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation as the council may provide.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That Section 41 of the charter of the city of Dallas be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 41. The city council shall have power and authority by or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dinance to regulate, control and prohibit the carrying of weapons within the limits of the city of Dallas.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That Section 66 of the charter of the city of Dallas be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 66. The city council shall have power to abate all nuisances<pb n="513" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>which may injure or affect public health, in any manner they may deem expedient within the city limits, or within three thousand (3000) feet of the corporate lines of said city.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That Section 28 of the charter of the city of Dallas be so amended as to read follows:</p>
<p>Section 28. The mayor and aldermen shall constitute the city coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil of the city. The city council shall meet at such times and place as they by resolution shall direct. The mayor when present shall preside at all meetings of the city council, and shall have in all cases a casting vote, but in elections he shall vote as other members of the council. In his absence, and the absence of president pro tem any one of the alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men may be appointed to preside.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That Section 58 of the charter of the city of Dallas be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 58. The city council shall have power to fix the compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of all city officers, and to regulate the fees of all jurors, witnesses and others rendered under the charter and ordinances of said city. Whenever the city council as provided by the charter shall fix the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation to be paid any officer, whether elected by the people or the council, they shall make the same payable monthly out of the city treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ury, and no officer shall be allowed any fees or perquisites of office, but all costs and penalties shall go into the general sinking fund. No officer&#8217;s salary shall be fixed at a sum to exceed fifteen hundred dollars ($1500) per annum, except the salary of assessor and collector, which shall not exceed three thousand dollars ($3000) per annum; provided, that the compensation of no officer of the corporation shall be diminished during his term of office.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That Section 62 of the charter of the city of Dallas as amended by an act of the Legislature approved April 5th 1881 be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 62. The city council shall have the right to enact all neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary ordinances, to restrain and punish vagrants, mendicants, street beg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gars and prostitutes to locate, restrain punish and control all disorderly houses of prostitution or assignation, and the keeper and inmates thereof; to regulate, punish or control all gambling, and the keepers of games and gambling houses, and those who bet on games and gambling devices, where there is an ordinance of the city of Dallas in force punishing this or any other misdemeanor with as great a penalty as the same is punishd by the Statutes of the State. The mayor&#8217;s court of the city of Dallas shall have concurrent jurisdiction of such misdemeanors when committed in the corporate limits of the city of Dallas.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That Section 77 of the charter of the city of Dallas be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 77. The city council shall have the sole authority to grant the right to any person or persons, corporation or company to make and construct street railways in any street in said city and to regulate and control the same and the use thereof; provided, the owners of a majority of front feet on the street along which said railway shall run are willing; the frontage to be calculated, not by blocks, but by the entire length of the proposed line, and on both sides of the street so proposed to be oc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cupied, and provided also, it shall not require the consent of the property owner to the construction of said street railway across any street.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That Section 82 of the charter of the city of Dallas as<pb n="514" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>amended by an act of the Legislature approved April 5th 1881 be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 82. The city council shall have power to pass, publish, amend or repeal all ordinances, rules and police regulations not contrary to the Constitution of the State, and necessary for the order or good government of the city, or the trade, commerce and health thereof or that may be necessary and proper to carry into effect the powers vested in the corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, or any of its officers, by the act of incorporation of date August 9th A. D. 1876, and this and other amendments thereto; to enforce the ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />servance of all such ordinances, rules, and police regulations, and to pun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ish violations thereof by fines and imprisonment, or either, or both, or by work on the streets or other public works as may be provided by ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance, and required by the judgment of the court; provided, that no fine shall exceed two hundred dollars ($200), and no period of imprisonment shall exceed thirty days in the city jail; and for any fine, penalty, and costs imposed by the mayor or recorder, in the trial of any cause or com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plaint before him, executions may issue to collect such fines and costs, to be levied and executed in the same manner that executions are from jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tices of the peace courts. The same shall be issued by the mayor or re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corder to the marshal, who in levying on property and selling shall have like power and authority as the sheriff of the county, in executions issued from the district or county courts, and the laws of the State so far as ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plicable shall apply to and be in full force and effect as to the executions issued from the mayor&#8217;s or recorder&#8217;s court. Any person upon whom any fine or penalty is imposed may be committed until the payment of the same with costs; and on default thereof may be imprisoned in the city prison, or may be required to work on the streets, or other public works of the city for such time, and in such manner as may be provided by ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance; provided, such imprisonment shall not exceed thirty days.</p>
<p>Sec 10. That section 174 of the charter of the city of Dallas be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 174. The city council shall have power by ordinance to cause to be graded, paved, macadamized or graveled or otherwise constructed, improved or repaired all streets, sidewalks, alleys and public highways including cross streets, in the limits of the city of Dallas, at such time, to such extent, and out of such material and under such regulations as the city council may provide by ordinance; provided, that, the owners of prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty bordering on a street or sidewalk so improved, shall pay pro rata ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording to frontage of property thereon, the expense of such improvement so ordered; the city council shall have improved in the same manner as the rest of the streets all the intersections of streets where they cross the streets so improved, and to the middle of the street where another street enters but don&#8217;t cross the street, being so improved. This improvement of intersections and abutments of other streets to be paid for out of the gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral fund. The work shall be done as follows. Whenever the city coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil determine by ordinance that such work shall be done, and the manner and extent of the same, they shall advertise for bids giving the plans, spec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ifications and extent of improvement. The work shall be let to the lowest responsible bidder in the discretion of the city council, and with such bond as the council may determine. The city council shall levy a special tax on the property fronting or abutting on said streets so improved, pro rata according to number of feet of front or abutment, and said tax shall<pb n="515" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>be levied as soon as convenient after contract is let, and the time of pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of same, and when it shall become delinquent shall be specified in ordinance. The tax shall be a lien from time of levy, and its collection shall be enforced as the collection of other taxes, by advertisement and sale of property; provided, it shall not be necessary to sell at same time as for other delinquent ad valorem taxes. If said special tax be not paid in full in ten days from the completion of said work and the levy of said special tax, then the assessor and collector shall proceed at once to ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vertise and sell said property for the special tax due thereon, giving same notice, and executing similar deed as is given when property is sold by city for ad valorem taxes.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That section 177 of the city charter as amended by act of the Legislature of the State approved April 5th 1881 be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 177. It shall be the duty of every person or corporation own<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing property fronting on any street in the city of Dallas to build side<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />walks, construct curbing and guttering and repair the same in front of their property when notified by the proper city authorities and according to ordinance. If the owners of any such property fail after due notice as provided by ordinance, to construct or repair such sidewalks, curbing or guttering as provided by ordinance, the same may be done by the city and taxed against the property according to cost of construction, and the same proceeding shall be had as provided in Section 174 above, in doing said work and collecting said tax. Any one failing or refusing to build or repair the sidewalk, curbing or guttering along their property, ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording to ordinance, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and pun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ished as provided by city ordinance; provided, the fine for any one day&#8217;s neglect shall not exceed fifty dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That Section 180, of the charter of the city of Dallas be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 180. The city council shall have power by ordinance to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vide for and cause a general sewer and drainage system to be established, which shall be divided into three classes, to-wit: Public, district, and private sewers, and drains. Public sewers shall be established along the principal crosses of drainage, at such times, to such extent, and under such regulations as may be provided by ordinance, and there may be ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tension or branches of sewers already constructed, or entirely new throughout, as may be deemed expedient. The city council may, if neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary, levy a tax on all property made taxable for State purposes over the whole city, to pay for the construction and repairs of such public sewers, which shall be called &#8220;Special public sewer tax,&#8221; and shall be of such amount as may be required for the sewer or sewers provided by ordinance to be built, and the fund arising from said tax shall be appropriated solely to the building and repairing of said sewer or sewers, and there shall when necessary be a taking and condemnation of private property for sewers and drains as herein before provided for. No public sewer shall be run diagonally through private property, when it is practicable without injury to said sewer, to construct it parallel with one of the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terior lines of such property; nor shall any public sewer be constructed through private property when it is practicable to construct it oblong or through a street or other public highway.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That Section 181 of the charter of the city of Dallas be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 181. District sewers or drains shall be established within<pb n="516" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the limits of the district to be described by ordinance, connecting with a public sewer or other district sewer, or with the natural course of drain<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age, as each case may be; or in such other manner as the city council may by ordinance provide. Such district may be subdivided, enlarged or changed by ordinance at any time. The city council shall cause sewers or drains to be constructed in each district, to such extent, of such di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mensions, and under such regulations as may be prescribed by ordinance, whenever a majority of the property holders therein shall petition there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />for, or whenever the city council may deem such sewer or drain neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary for sanitary or other purposes, and said sewer or drain shall be of such dimensions as may be prescribed by ordinance; and may be changed, enlarged or extended, and shall have all the necessary laterals, inlets and other appurtenances which may be required. The work shall be done as follows: Whenever the city council shall determine by ordinance, that such work shall be done, and the manner and extent of the same, they shall advertise for bids, giving the plans and specifications and ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tent of improvement. The work shall be let to the lowest responsible bid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der in the discretion of the city council, and with such bond as the said council may provide. As soon as any district sewer or drain shall have been completed, the city engineer or other officer having charge of the work, shall make report thereof to the city council, together with the entire cost of said work, and the city engineer shall at the same time furnish to the assessor and collector, and city council, a list of all prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty in said sewer district, together with the owners thereof. The city council shall then at once proceed to assess said amount against said property, and shall levy a special tax therefor against the lots of ground within such district, exclusive of improvements, in proportion to the area of the whole district, exclusive of public highways; provided, that in the discretion of the council a special committee of three disinterested citizens, not residing in the said sewerage district, may be appointed by the mayor for the purpose of assessing the property in such dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict in proportion to the benefit derived from said sewer for the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of paying said cost of such sewer. And the assessor and collector shall enter said list of said property, and the name of the owner thereof, together with the assessment and levy made against each lot or lots within such district on his tax rolls, in a book kept for that purpose and shall proceed to collect the same as other taxes are collected. Said tax shall be a lien on such property from the time of levy, and its collection shall be enforced as other taxes by advertisement and sale of the property taxed; provided, it shall not be necessary to sell at the same time as for delinquent advalorem taxes. If the said special tax be not paid in full in ten days from the completion of said work, and the levy of said special tax due thereon, giving same notice and executing similar deed as in case of property sold by the city for advalorem taxes. Private sewer or drain connecting with public or district sewer, may be constructed under such restrictions and regulations as may be provided by ordinance, but the city shall be at no expense in the construction of the same, and may by ordinance force the construction and keeping of the same clean, and in proper repair by parties owning or using the same. If the owner of such property shall not proceed within live days after notice given by the city secretary, to construct such private sewer or drain under the superintendence of the city engineer in strict compliance with the ordinance, then the city shall have such work done as pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided above for district sewer, and the city council shall tax such<pb n="517" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>costs against such property, and as soon as said work shall be completed shall levy a special tax on such property to pay for such improvement, and the city tax shall be a lien on such property from time of levy; if said special tax be not paid within the time provided above for payment of special tax for building district sewer, then the assessor and collector shall proceed to advertise and sell the property for the special tax so levied thereon, and execute a deed therefor as provided above in case of district sewer. The time of payment, and the time of becoming delin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quent of such special taxes herein provided for, shall be fixed by ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance, where the same is not fixed in the charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That Section 101 of the charter of the city of Dallas ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved August 9th 1876 be and the same is hereby amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 101. It shall be the duty of the assessor and collector be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween the first day of January, and the fifth day of April of each year to make and return to the city council a full and complete assessment of all property real and personal in said city, on the first day of January, liable to municipal taxation, together with the cash value of all goods, wares and merchandise owned or kept on hand for sale by any merchant on the first day of January of that year, together with the cash value of all property real and personal belonging to any corporation, also a list of all insurance companies doing business in said city and the name of the agent of the same. The city council shall have power in its discre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, at or before its last regular meeting in December of each year, to appoint two resident freeholders of the city of Dallas, qualified voters, to be called assistant assessors, whose duty it shall be when so appointed, to attend with the assessor and collector at the time of making said as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessment for the year following their appointment, and having equal power and authority with the assessor and collector, together with said assessor and collector to make and return to the city council a full and complete assessment of all property, personal and real, as above provided, and they shall attend and assist the assessor and collector in receiving the lists of property and statements of merchants and others by the act re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to be delivered to said assessor and collector, and their compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and further duties and powers, shall be such as the city council may by ordinance provide.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. The city council shall prior to the first day of A. D. 1883, divide the city into convenient wards, not to exceed eleven (11) wards in all, and each ward shall at the next regular election, April 1884, elect two aldermen, one of whom shall serve one year, and the other two years. The terms of service to be determined by lot. Each of said wards shall thereafter elect one alderman annually who shall hold his office for two years, or until his successor has been elected and qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. Whereas the good government of the city of Dallas depends upon the immediate passage of this act, therefore a public necessity and emergency exists for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days. The rule is therefore hereby sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended, and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and that all laws and parts of laws in conflict herewith be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 31, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect after its passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="518" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 8.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Alsey S. Miller, Milburn Harral and Mary A. Woods, widow of Gonzales Woods, deceased, survivors of the &#8220;Dawson massacre," by granting to each one of them a certificate for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required, to issue a certificate for twelve hundred and eighty acres of land each to Alsey S. Miller, Milburn Harral and Mary A. Woods, widow of Gonzales Woods, deceased, survivors of the &#8220;Dawson massacre,&#8221; which may be located as headright certificates upon any of the unappropriated public domain, and patented as in other cases; and the said certificates, and the land located by virtue thereof, shall be ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />empt from forded sales so long as it shall remain the property of the grantee in said certificate; provided, that the Commissioner of the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Land Office shall charge no fees for the issuance of such certificate and patent; provided, that the State shall not be held responsible for any deficiency in the public domain.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the close of the present session of the Legislature, making it doubtful if this bill can pass in the ordinary course of legislation, creates an imperative public necessity for the sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pension of the constitutional rule requiring a bill to be read on three several days: and it is so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 9, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 9.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of General Mosely Baker, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, General Mosely Baker, a soldier of the Revolution of the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas, to whom was granted a headright certificate by said Republic for services rendered therein; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, said head right certificate was located back of and adjoining the town of Anahuac on Galveston bay; and</p>
<p>Whereas, said certificate was located upon lands that had been pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viously located by other parties, by reason of which all benefits of said headright certificate were lost, to the said General Mosely Baker, or his heirs; and</p>
<p>Whereas, Mrs. Fannie A. D. Darden, of Columbus, Texas, is the only surviving heir of the said Genl. Mosely Baker, deceased, therefore</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be and he is hereby authorized and required to issue to Fannie A. D. Darden, sole heir of Genl. Mosely Baker, deceased, a certificate for one league and one labor of land, which may be surveyed and located and patented as other first class head right certificates, she paying the Government fees; provided, that this act shall not be construed to bind the State, should no vacant land be found, which should be stated on the face of the certificate.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The said certificate can only be located upon vacant and un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="519" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>appropriated public domain; and the State is to be in no manner liable in case the certificate is not located on vacant land.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The near approach of the end of the present session of the Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature rendering it improbable that this bill will pass in the regular course of legislation, creates an imperative public necessity for the sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days: and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 10, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 10.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of John W. Thomson, who fell at the storming of the Alamo on the 6th day of March, 1836.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, John W. Thomson, a volunteer in the defence of the Repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic of Texas, under the command of Bowie and Travis, was killed while serving as a volunteer in the armies of Texas, as aforesaid, on the 6th day of March, 1836, at the storming of the Alamo: and,</p>
<p>Whereas, All his comrades perished in said masacre, and many diffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />culties intervened which prevented his heirs from securing the land cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates granted to those who fell in said battle, and were residing in the State of Texas at the time of the Declaration of the Independence of the State of Texas: and,</p>
<p>Whereas, The old &#8220;court of claims&#8221; before which said matters were adjudicated, has been and was, abolished before the claim of the heirs of said Thomson was adjudicated, and while the said claim was therein pending; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, No certificates for land, granted to those who fell in said battle of the Alamo, and were in Texas at the time of the Declaration of the Independence of the State of Texas; and</p>
<p>Whereas, The State of Texas has heretofore granted to the heirs of all Those who fell at the Alamo, in the service of Texas, the following land certificates, to wit: A special head-right certificate of 1476 acres, 1920 bounty, and 640 acres donation, and to those that were citizens of Texas at the Declaration of Independence a certificate of 1476 acres; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, the lapse of time, the death of witnesses, the war between the States, and other obstacles, intervened to prevent the said heirs of the said Thomson from presenting and establishing their claim before the &#8220;Court of Claims&#8221; prior to its abolition; and,</p>
<p>Whereas, said heirs are justly entitled to said certificates, and the same have never been to them issued, therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas; that the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized, empowered and required to issue to the heirs of said John. W. Thomson the following certificates, to wit: One special head-right cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate of 1476 acres, class&#8212;; one 640 donation certificate, class&#8212;: one 1920 acre bounty certificate, class&#8212;, and one 1476 head-right cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate, class<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />, &#8212;said certificates only to be located on unappropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated vacant public domain, and the State to be in no manner liable if there is not vacant land upon which said certificates can be located.</p>
<pb n="520" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted that said Commissioner of the General Land Office shall deliver to said heirs, their legal agent or representative, said certificates, when he shall have been assured by satisfactory proof of such heirship.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 10, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 11.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize Christian Jordan to sue the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Christian Jordan of Galveston county is hereby authorized and empowered to sue the State of Texas in the district court of Travis county for the enforcement and adjustment of any right or claim which he may have against the State of Texas by reason of the transfer and assignment to him, by the State, of a certain judgment recovered by said State on the 31st day of October 1873, against Frank Dirks and his sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eties in cause No. 3399 in the district court of Travis county or by reason of any taxes or moneys collected by the State of Texas, or her officers and agents and which taxes or moneys in law, equity or justice should have been credited on said judgment and paid to the owner thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The suit provided for in the preceding section, shall be filed within one year from the passage of this act, and when filed, a certified copy of plaintiffs petition, and a citation such as usually issue to the de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fendants in suits in the district court, shall be served on the Governor of the State at least ten days before the first day of the term of court, to which said suit is brought.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Said suit shall be tried by said district court like other suits, and either or both parties shall have the right to an appeal from the judgment of said district court to the Supreme Court of the State, in the same manner as appeals are allowed in other cases; provided, that the State shall not be required to give any appeal bond, or be liable for any costs of court whatever.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. If judgment shall be rendered in favor of said Christian Jor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />don by the district court, and no appeal be taken or perfected by the State as required by law, or in case such judgment shall have been af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />firmed on appeal by the Supreme Court, such judgment shall be certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied to the Comptroller of the State by the clerk of the district court, and the Comptroller shall draw his warrant on the Treasurer in favor of said Christian Jordan for the amount of such judgment.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 12, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 12.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to receive the surrender of the corporate rights and franchises of the Jefferson Iron Company, a private corporation of this State, and to amend the charter of the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas,<pb n="521" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>that Horace Ware, as the sole owner of the corporate rights and fran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chises of the Jefferson Iron Company, a private corporation, chartered on the 9th day of March, A. D. 1874, by virtue of the general incorpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion law of the State of Texas, be and he is hereby permitted to surrender all the corporate rights and franchises of said Jefferson Iron Company to the State of Texas; and the charter heretofore issued to said company be and the same is annulled and cancelled, and record of such cancella<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion may be made in the office of the Secretary of State of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The title to all the property real and personal of said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion is hereby divested therefrom and freely vested in the said Horace Ware individually, and to prosecute any and all suits in which said cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration may be a party.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Notice of this act having been published for 30 days as re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired by the Constitution, and the near approach of the close of the 18th Legislature creates an imperative public necessity that the consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days should be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage; and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 14, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 13.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act ceding to the United States government exclusive jur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />isdiction over certain property in the city of Dallas for the purpose of erecting a public building thereon.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas The United States government has made an appropriation for the purpose of erecting a court and post office building in the city of Dal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />las, State of Texas, now therefore</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the State of Texas does hereby cede to the government of the United States exclusive jurisdiction over lots numbers (5, 6, 7 and 8) five, six, seven and eight and (20) twenty feet of west part of lots numbers (4) four and (9) nine in block (96) ninety six according to official map of the city of Dallas; or over any property acquired or to be acquired in the city of Dallas for the purpose above indicated, so long as said government of the United States shall be and remain the owner thereof; provided that the State of Texas does hereby retain jurisdiction over said prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty for the administration of the criminal laws of this State and the service of civil process therein.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas the United States government is now ready to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed with the construction of said building, an imperative necessity and emergency exists for the suspension of the constitutional rule, requiring bills to be read on three several days and that this act take effect from and after its passage and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed....., <date>1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="522" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 14.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amendatory of an Act entitled &#8220;An Act to incorporate the City of Austin,&#8221; approved April 5, 1873.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Article four of the above recited act, shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 4, Section 1.</head>
<p>That an election shall be held on the first Monday in December, 1883, for the election of a city council to consist of a mayor and a board of aldermen, who shall hold their offices for two years, or until their suc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessors are elected and qualified, except that one of the two aldermen elected from each ward shall hold his office for only one year; the long and short terms to be drawn for by the aldermen elected from each ward immediately after their installation; that the board of aldermen shall consist of two members from each ward, to be chosen by the qualified voters of their respective wards; that thereafter there shall be an election held on the first Monday in December of each year, to fill all vacancies occurring, or to occur in the city council from the expiration of terms of office, or otherwise; and no person shall be a member of the city council, unless he be a citizen of the State of Texas, and shall have resided within the city limits for six months preceding his election, and shall have been a bona fide resident of the ward from which he is elected for at least thirty days preceding his election. That if any alderman shall after his election remove from the ward from which he is chosen, his office shall thereby be vacated. The city council shall judge of the election returns and qualifications of its own members and shall determine contested elections of all city officers made elective under this act.</p>
<p>The majority of the city council shall constitute a quorum to do busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness, but a smaller number may adjourn from day to day, and may compel the attendance of absent members in such manner, and under such pen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alties as they may prescribe. The city council may determine the rules of its proceedings, punish its members for a willful violation of its rules, or other disorderly behaviour and with the consent of two-thirds of the members elected, expel an alderman, but not a second time for the same offense. The city council shall keep a journal of its proceedings and whenever practicable, publish the same, or a synopsis thereof in a news<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />paper of the city; and the yeas and nays of the members on any question shall, at the desire of any alderman present be entered on the journal. Aldermen shall serve without pay and no alderman shall during the term of his office hold any other office under the city; nor shall any alderman during his term of office, be interested directly or indirectly, in any con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tract or agreement for work to be done, or service to be performed, for which the city is to pay a consideration, or in the purchase of any prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty by the city for any purpose whatever. All vacancies that shall oc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cur in the board of aldermen shall be filled in such manner as shall be hereafter provided for by ordinance. Each alderman shall before entering upon the duties of his office take the oath prescribed by the Constitution of the State of Texas and that he will faithfully discharge the duties of his office. Whenever there shall be a tie in the election of aldermen, the judges of the election shall certify the same to the mayor, who shall immediately thereon issue his proclamation, stating such facts, and order<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing a new election.</p>
<pb n="523" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. And be it further enacted, That Article five of the above re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cited Act shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 5, Section 1.</head>
<p>The major and the board of aldermen shall constitute the city council of said city. There shall be stated sessions of the city council at least once in each month, and such special meetings as the mayor or any two members of the council may deem necessary. In the absence of the mayor any one of the aldermen may be appointed to preside, in which case, the alderman who presides shall vote only as an alderman. The city council shall have the care, management and control of the city and its property and finances; and shall have power to enact and ordain any and all ordinances not repugnant to the Constitution and laws of this State, and such ordinances to alter, modify, or repeal. Upon the passage of all ordinances appropriating money, imposing taxes, increasing, lessen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing or abolishing licenses, and of ordinances for borrowing money, the yeas and nays shall be entered in the journal, but no ordinance for bor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rowing money shall pass, except by a vote of two-thirds of the whole council. All ordinances shall be read in the council for three separate days, unless two-thirds of the members elected shall dispense therewith. A majority of the members of the whole council shall be necessary to pass an ordinance appropriating for any purpose the sum of five hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars or upwards, or for passing an ordinance in any wise diminishing or increasing the city revenues.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. And be it further enacted, That Article six of the above re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cited Act shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 6, Section 1.</head>
<p>That the mayor and city council shall have power within the city by ordinance:</p>
<p>First. To levy and collect an annual tax, not exceeding one per centum upon all property within the limits of the city, made taxable by law for State and county purposes, the money raised by said tax to be used for the current expenses and for the general improvement of the city.</p>
<p>Second. To raise money on the credit of the city, for a special and definite purpose, by issuing bonds of the city, or otherwise; provided, the bonded debt of the city shall not at any time exceed one hundred and twenty-five thousand dollars, and the interest due on bonds, and in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest bearing warrants issued by the city of Austin with the interest accrued thereon, shall be at all times considered a part of the bonded debt of the city. To extend the bonded debt of the city beyond one hundred and twenty-five thousand dollars shall only be done by a special act of the Legislature, or by the consent of two-thirds of the tax paying citizens voting at an election ordered for the purpose, after thirty days notice by the mayor, by the authority of and in the method that may be prescribed by the city council. All bonds shall specify for what pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose they were issued, and when any bonds are issued by the city, a fund shall be provided to pay the interest, and two per cent. per annum on the principal, as a sinking fund to redeem the bonds, or pay them at matu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rity; and said sinking fund shall not be diverted to or drawn for any other purpose, and the city treasurer shall honor no draft drawn on said sinking fund except to pay the interest, or redeem the bonds for which said fund was provided. The sinking fund for the redemption of any bonds and the payment of the interest thereon shall be invested, as fast as the same accumulates, in interest bearing bonds of the United States, or of the State of Texas, or of the city of Austin, as the city council<pb n="524" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>may deem most advantageous: and such bonds and the interest thereon shall be sold when necessary to pay or redeem the bonds for which the sinking fund was established.</p>
<p>Third. To appropriate money and to provide for the payment of the debts and expenses of the city.</p>
<p>Fourth. To make regulations to prevent the introduction of conta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gious diseases into the city.</p>
<p>Fifth. To establish hospitals and make regulations for the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment thereof, within or without the city limits.</p>
<p>Sixth. To make regulations to secure the general health of the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />habitants, and prevent and remove nuisances.</p>
<p>Seventh. To construct water works, gas works and street railroads, within or beyond the city limits, or both; to provide the city with water and gas, and to erect hydrants, fire-plugs and pumps in the streets; to erect the necessary machinery, lamp posts, &#38;c. for lighting the city, within or beyond the limits of the city, for the convenience of the inhab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />itants of the city and environs.</p>
<p>Eighth. To have the exclusive control and power over the streets, alleys, side-walks, lanes, avenues, public grounds and highways of the city, and to abate and remove all encroachments thereon; to open, alter, widen, straighten, extend, establish, abolish, regulate, grade, re-grade clean, pave, macadamize, or otherwise improve the same; and to regulate the making of side-walks, their grade, material and mode of construc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, when such side-walks are made by private parties.</p>
<p>Ninth. To establish, erect and keep in repair bridges, culverts and sewers and regulate the use of the same; to establish, alter and change the channel of water courses and to wall them up and cover them.</p>
<p>Tenth. To provide for the lighting of the streets and erecting lamps thereon.</p>
<p>Eleventh. To establish, support and regulate night watch and patrols.</p>
<p>Twelfth. To erect market houses, establish markets and market places, provide for the government and regulation thereof, and to license, tax and regulate butchers and the vendors of poultry, fish, vegetables and other provisions.</p>
<p>Thirteenth. To provide for the erection of all needful buildings for the use of the city.</p>
<p>Fourteenth. To provide for the inclosing, improving and regulating all public grounds belonging to the city.</p>
<p>Fifteenth. To license, tax and regulate auctions, grocers, merchants, retailers, hotels and boarding houses, and bakeries; and to license, tax and regulate or suppress ordinaries, hawkers, peddlers, brokers, and pawn brokers and money changers.</p>
<p>Sixteenth. To license, tax and regulate hackney carriages, omnibuses, wagons, carts and drays and fix the rates to be charged for carriage of persons, and for wagonage, cartage and drayage of property.</p>
<p>Seventeenth. To license and regulate porters and fix the rate of porter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age.</p>
<p>Eighteenth. To license, tax, regulate and suppress theatrical and other exhibitions shows and amusements.</p>
<p>Nineteenth. To license tax and regulate billiard tables, pin alleys and ball alleys, restaurants, drinking houses or saloons and all places or establishments where intoxicating or fermented liquors are sold; real estate agents, insurance brokers, insurance agents and all other trades, professions, occupations and callings the taxing of which is not prohib<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="525" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ited by the Constitution of the State, which tax shall not be construed to be a tax on property; to restrain and suppress disorderly houses: to suppress lotteries and all fraudulent devices and practices; to suppress gaming and gambling of all kinds and descriptions, and to prevent the same; to restrain bawdy houses, houses of prostitution or assignation and to punish prostitutes and the keepers of houses of prostitution within the city or within such limits therein as may be defined by ordinance, by fine or imprisonment, or both and to adopt, summary measures for the removal or suppression of all such establishments.</p>
<p>Twentieth. To provide for the prevention and extinguishment of fires and organizing and establishing fire companies; also to regulate and restrain and prohibit the erection of wooden buildings in any part of the city; to regulate and prevent the carrying on of manufactories dan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gerous in causing or producing fires; to appoint fire wardens and prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty guards, with power to remove and keep away from the vicinity of any fire all idle and suspicious persons lurking near the same, and to compel any person or persons present to aid in extinguishing such fire, or in the preservation of property exposed to the danger of the same; and in preventing goods from being purloined thereat; and with such other powers and duties as may be prescribed by ordinance, to compel the owners of houses and other buildings, to have scuttles upon the roof of any such houses and buildings, and stairs and ladders leading to the same.</p>
<p>Twenty first. To regulate and order the cleaning of chimneys, and fix the fees thereof.</p>
<p>Twenty second. To regulate the storage of gunpowder, tar, pitch, Rosin, hemp, cotton and all other combustible materials, and the use of lights and candles in all stables, shops and other places; to remove and prevent the construction of any fireplace, hearth, chimney, stoves, ovens, boilers, kettles or apparatus used in any house, building, manufactory or business which may be dangerous in causing or promoting fires; to direct the safe construction of deposits for ashes, and severally to enter into or appoint one or more officers at reasonable times to examine all dwellings, houses, lots, yards, enclosures, buildings of every description, in order to discover whether any of them are in a dangerous state, and to cause such as may be dangerous to be put in a safe and secure condition.</p>
<p>Twenty third. To regulate and prescribe the manner and order, the building of partition and parapet walls and of partition fences.</p>
<p>Twenty fourth. To establish standard, weights and measures and to regulate the weights and measures to be used in the city in all cases not otherwise provided by law.</p>
<p>Twenty fifth. To provide for the inspection and measuring of lumber and other building materials.</p>
<p>Twenty sixth. To provide for the inspection and weight of hay, the measuring of charcoal, fire-wood and all other fuel to be used in the city.</p>
<p>Twenty seventh. To regulate the inspection of lard, butter and other provisions, to regulate the vending of meat, poultry and vegetables; to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strain and punish the forestalling of poultry, butter, eggs and fruit and to suppress hucksters.</p>
<p>Twenty eighth. To regulate the weight, quality and price of bread to be sold and used in the city.</p>
<p>Twenty ninth. To regulate the size of brick made or sold in the city.</p>
<pb n="526" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Thirtieth. To provide for the taking of an enumeration of the city.</p>
<p>Thirty first. To provide for the removing from office any person holding an office created by this act, or by ordinance, not otherwise pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for.</p>
<p>Thirty second. To provide for the appointment or election of all offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers, servants and agents of the corporation, not otherwise provided for.</p>
<p>Thirty third. To fix the compensation of the city officers not herein provided for, and regulate fees of all jurors, witnesses and others, for services rendered under this act or ordinance.</p>
<p>Thirty fourth. To regulate the police of the city; to impose fines, for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />feitures and penalties for the breach of any ordinance and to provide for the recovery and appropriating such fines and forfeitures, and the en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />forcement of such penalties; provided, that no fine shall exceed one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars and imprisonment not exceeding fifteen days for any one offence.</p>
<p>Thirty fifth. To erect a work-house and house of correction and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vide for the regulation and government thereof.</p>
<p>Thirty sixth. To regulate and license all ferries and toll bridges within the limits of the city.</p>
<p>Thirty seventh. To remove all obstructions from the streets and sidewalks and at the expense of the owners of the ground fronting thereon, to provide for the construction, paving, repairing and cleaning of all sidewalks and gutters.</p>
<p>Thirty eighth. To prevent the assemblage of idle persons at or near store house doors, whereby the trade of such house or persons passing are interrupted; and also to prevent and restrain any riot, rout, disturb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance or disorderly assemblage in any street, house or place in the city.</p>
<p>Thirty ninth. To prevent and remove all encroachments in and upon all streets, lanes, avenues and alleys, established by law or ordinance.</p>
<p>Fortieth. To establish cemeteries within or without the limits of the city and to regulate the same.</p>
<p>Forty first. To exercise complete and perfect control over the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mons and all the property belonging to the city real or personal, whether lying within or beyond the limits of the corporation created by this act, and the same to lease, sell in part, or whole, transfer and dispose of, either absolutely or within limitation, to any person or persons whatsoever; and generally to make such rules, regulations, by laws and ordinance, for the purpose of maintaining the peace, good government and order of the city of Austin, and the trade, commerce and manufactories thereof, as the city council may deem expedient, not repugnant to the laws and constitution of this State; and also to enforce the observance thereof by inflicting penalties upon any inhabitant thereof, or any person or persons, for the violation of any ordinance, not exceeding $100 and imprisonment not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeding fifteen days for any one offence, recoverable with costs, by suit by and in the name of the city of Austin, for the use of the city, before any court having cognizance of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. And be it further enacted that article 7 of the above recited act shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 7, Section 1.</head>
<p>That the city council shall have power, subject to the restrictions in the preceding section, to make all ordinances which shall be necessary and proper for carrying into effect the powers specified in the preceding sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and all other powers vested by this act in the corporation, the city government, or any department, or office thereof. No money shall be<pb n="527" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>expended, nor shall any improvement be ordered involving an expendi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture of money except by ordinance, the provisions of which shall be specified and definite.</p>
<p>Every ordinance which shall have been passed by the city council, shall before it becomes a law, be presented to the mayor for his ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proval; if he approve, he shall sign it; if not, he shall return it, with this objections to the board of aldermen, which objections shall be entered at large on the journal and the ordinance shall be reconsidered. If after such reconsideration, two-thirds of the members of the board shall agree to pass the same, it shall be in force as an ordinance. In all such cases the votes of the city council shall be taken, yeas and nays, and entered on the journal. If any ordinance shall not be returned by the mayor with his objections in writing at the next meeting of the council, the same shall be in force as an ordinance in the same manner as if he had approved and signed it. Every resolution of a general character, or re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lating to any matter in which the public are interested, shall be presented to the mayor and before the same shall take effect, shall be proceeded upon in the same manner as in case of an ordinance. The style of the ordinance of the city shall be: &#8220;Be it ordained by the city council of the city of Austin.&#8221;</p>
<p>Every ordinance imposing any penalty, fine, imprisonment or forfeit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ure, for violation of its provisions shall, after the passage thereof, be published in every issue of a daily paper for ten days.</p>
<p>Ordinances passed by the city council and requiring publication shall be in force from and after the publication thereof, unless it be therein otherwise expressly provided.</p>
<p>Ordinances not requiring publication shall take effect and be in force from and after their passage, unless it shall be therein otherwise expressly provided. All ordinances of the city when printed and published by au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority of the city council, shall be admitted and received in evidence in all courts and places without further proof. All ordinances, regulations and resolutions now in force in the city of Austin and not in conflict with this act shall remain in force under this act until altered, modified or repealed by the city council after this act shall take effect.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further enacted That article 8, of the above recited act shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 8, Section 1.</head>
<p>That the mayor shall be the chief executive officer of the city, who shall be elected as hereinbefore authorized, by the qualified voters of the city and who shall hold his office for the term of two years and until his successor is elected and qualified. The salary of the mayor shall be six hundred dollars per annum with no fees of office, this salary being in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tended not as a compensation for services in the performance of his du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties as mayor, but only as a reimbursement for expenses incident to and growing out of his position. No person shall be mayor who at the time of his election is not possessed of the qualification required for an alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />man or who holds any lucrative office under authority of the United States or any State; he shall before entering upon his duties take the oath prescribed by the Constitution of this State, and to faithfully and impartially perform his duties. When two or more persons shall have an equal number of votes for the office of mayor, a new election shall be ordered, except in case such election is contested, and whenever an elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for mayor shall be contested, the city council shall determine the same by vote. Whenever any vacancy shall happen in the office of<pb n="528" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>mayor, it shall be filled by election in such manner as shall be pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for by ordinance, in which case the mayor so elected shall hold the office for the unexpired term only. The mayor may be removed from office for any misdemeanor in office by a majority of two-thirds of a full board of aldermen, after trial and conviction in accordance with the laws of the State. The mayor shall have power to nominate, and by and with the consent of the board of aldermen, to appoint all city officers not ordered by this act to be otherwise elected; provided, any alderman may also make nominations for any of the city officers herein referred to. The mayor shall sign the commissions or appointments of all persons elected by the city council, and shall cause all subordinate officers to be dealt with promptly for any neglect or violation of duty. He may suspend and by and with the consent of council, remove from office any person holding an office made elective by the city council under this act, or here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after created by ordinance. He shall have power when he deems it neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary, to require any officer of the city to exhibit his account or other papers, and it shall be his duty to make report to the council in writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, regarding any errors or deficiencies he may discover in said ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />counts or papers. The mayor shall preside at all the meetings of the city council, except as herein otherwise provided and shall have a casting vote when the council is equally divided and not otherwise. He shall from time to time communicate to the city council such information and recommend such measures as in his opinion may tend to the improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the finances, health, security, ornament and general prosperity of the city. The mayor or any two councilmen shall have power to call special meetings of the city council, the object of which shall be submit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ted to the council in writing and the call and object thereof shall be entered on the journal by the clerk. The mayor shall take care that the laws of the State and the ordinances of the city are duly enforced, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spected and observed within the city and he is hereby authorized to call on every male inhabitant of the city over eighteen years of age and under the age of fifty years, to aid in enforcing the laws and ordinances of the city, and any person who shall not obey such call shall forfeit to the city a fine not exceeding five hundred dollars. The mayor, by and with the consent of the council shall have power to remit fines and for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />feitures and to grant reprieves and pardons for all offenses arising under the ordinances of the city. He shall have power to solemnize marriages and to administer oaths of office. In case of the temporary absence or illness of the recorder or in case of vacancy in the office of recorder, the mayor shall have like power with the recorder to try all cases of violation of the city ordinances and it shall be his duty to do so, unless such va<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cancy temporary or otherwise shall have been filled as provided in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. And be it further enacted, That article nine of the above re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cited shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 9, Section 1.</head>
<p>At the first meeting of the city council elected under this act and every two years thereafter the city council shall upon nomination by the mayor, or any alderman, proceed to elect an assessor and collector, a recorder, a city marshal, a treasurer, a city physician, a city clerk, a city attorney and a city engineer, who in addition to the duties prescribed by this act shall perform such other duties as have been, or may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by ordinance. They shall hold their offices for two years and until their successors are duly qualified and may at any time be removed<pb n="529" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>from office by a majority of two-thirds of a full board of aldermen. Such other officers, servants and agents of the corporations as the city coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil may deem necessary for the proper administration of the city gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment and for the interest of the city may be provided for by ordinance and elected in the same manner as the officers mentioned in this section and for such terms of office as the city council may determine. After every election of city officers by the council, the council shall imme<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diately proceed to fix the salaries of such officers and the salaries so fixed shall not be lessened during the term of office for which said officers were elected; provided, the salary of the assessor and collector shall not ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed fifteen hundred dollars per annum, inclusive of all commissions that may be allowed by the city council, the salary of the city marshal shall not exceed twelve hundred dollars per annum, the salary of treasurer shall not exceed six hundred dollars per annum, the salary of city physi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cian shall not exceed six hundred dollars per annum, the salary of city clerk shall not exceed twelve hundred dollars per annum, the salary of city engineer shall not exceed twelve hundred dollars per annum, ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clusive of such fees as he may be allowed by the city council to charge private parties for services rendered them, the salary of recorder shall not exceed twelve hundred dollars per annum with no fees, and the salary of city attorney shall not exceed fifteen hundred dollars per annum and such fees as may be allowed by ordinance for attending to cases of appeal before the county and Supreme Courts. The city attorney shall by him<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />self or deputy appear and prosecute all cases in the recorder&#8217;s court aris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing under the provisions of this act and the ordinances of the city. It shall be the duty of the city attorney to prepare and draw up all com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plaints for misdemeanors and to cause all necessary witnesses to be sum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moned on the part of the prosecution and he shall have full power and authority to administer oaths to persons making complaints before the recorder&#8217;s court. The usual attorneys fees, or such as may be prescribed by the city council, shall be charged and collected as other fees and when collected shall be paid to the assessor and collector as a part of the reve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nue of the city. The city attorney shall attend the meetings of the city council to give his advice, and he shall give his opinion upon all legal questions arising under the city government and perform such other du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties in connection with his office as may be required by the city council. He shall be a licensed lawyer and competent to discharge the duties re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired of him by the provisions of this act and the ordinances of the city.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. And be it further enacted, That Article ten of the above re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cited act shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 10, Section 1.</head>
<p>The recorder shall be the chief judicial magistrate of the city and as such shall hold a court within said city by the name of the Recorder&#8217;s Court of the city of Austin which said court shall have jurisdiction and cognizance in all misdemeanors, breaches of the peace, infractions of the ordinances, and all other causes arising under the laws of said city, subject however to an appeal to the county court in the same manner as appeals are taken and granted from justices&#8217; courts to the county court under the general laws of the State; and in all cases of appeal from the recorder&#8217;s court to the county court either party shall have the right to appeal from the judgment of the county court to the Supreme Court under the general laws of the State. The re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />corder may require of any person arrested under the provisions of this<pb n="530" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>act, or of the ordinances of the city, a bond for his or her good behavior and to keep the peace, with two good and sufficient sureties, which bond thority to issue subpoenas for witnesses and to compel their attendance by shall be payable to the city of Austin. He shall have full power and au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />process of attachment. He may issue warrants of arrests, search war<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rants executions and any other process known to the law which a jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice of the peace of this State may lawfully issue, and he may punish all contempts by fines and imprisonment, or either. He shall also have full power and authority to administer official oaths and all other oaths or affirmations, and give certificates thereof. The recorder shall be ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />officio justice of the peace and shall possess and execute within the city limits in criminal cases all the powers and duties of such offices, but in no case shall be entertain jurisdiction in civil suits. He shall charge in all cases the same fees which are allowed to justices of the peace for the same kind of services, which shall be charged and collected as other fees and when collected shall be paid into the city treasury for the use and benefit of the city. The recorder shall be a conservator of the peace, and his court shall be open every day except Sunday, to hear and deter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mine any and all cases cognizable before him, and he shall have power to bring parties before him forthwith for trial. Persons arraigned for violation of city ordinances demanding a trial by jury, shall deposit with the city clerk the sum of three dollars, security for the payment of the costs of such jury, unless they shall make oath that they are unable to pay or secure the same, any person convicted of an offense under the provisions of this act, or the ordinances of the city shall be punished by fine and imprisonment, or either and hard labor as may be regulated by ordinance.</p>
<p>The recorder shall perform such other duties as may be prescribed by any ordinance of the city and shall receive a salary not to exceed the sum of twelve hundred dollars per annum. The recorder shall be a licensed lawyer, and competent to discharge the duties required of him by the charter and the ordinances of the city. The fines imposed in the recorder&#8217;s court for the violation of the city ordinances, shall not be less than five dollars, nor more than one hundred dollars for each and every offense. In case of the illness or temporary absence of the recorder, the mayor may apppoint an acting recorder, who shall take the required oath and receive the same compensation as the recorder during the time of such temporary appointment.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. And be it further enacted that article sixteen of the above recited act shall hereafter read as follows:</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 16, Section 1.</head>
<p>That the revenues received during each fiscal year shall be applied to the payment of the current expenses of the city government, and the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriation made during that year; and no debt shall be incurred during any fiscal year except as otherwise provided in Section 3 of this act, or under authority conferred by the Legislature. The city council is hereby prohibited from incurring any expense or making appropriations beyond the receipts of the treasury, so that at the close of any fiscal year, any ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ligation created during that year shall remain unpaid, except in case of bonds issued as hereinbefore provided, and it is hereby made a misde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />meanor for the mayor to draw a warrant upon the city treasury, except on written information from the treasurer, that there is sufficient money in the treasury not otherwise set apart for the immediate payment of said warrant. Such misdemeanor on the part of the mayor shall be punished<pb n="531" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>by a trial for impeachment by the board of aldermen, and on conviction by a two thirds vote of a full board, by dismissal from office. It is hereby also made a misdemeanor for any alderman to knowingly vote for any appropriation whereby debt shall be created in violation of the provisions of the act. It shall be the duty of the city attorney to report to the grand jury of the county court of Travis county any alderman for such violation of law, the penalty for which after trial and conviction shall be dismissal from office. It shall be the duty of the city treasurer to report to the city council at their first regular meeting in each month the balance of money in the treasury unappropriated. All officers of the city shall take the oath prescribed in this act for the mayor and alder<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men, and the present city council shall exercise all of the powers and functions vested in the council under this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. And be it further enacted that the amendments to the char<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter of the city of Austin adopted and ratified by the voters of said city, at an election held on the first Monday in November 1875 and not in conflict with this act shall remain in full force and effect.</p>
<p>This act is declared to be a public act and may be read in evidence in all courts of law and equity in this State without proof.</p>
<p>All acts and parts of acts in conflict with the provisions of this act are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>The near approach of the end of the session creates an imperative ne<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessity that the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended; therefore said rule is hereby suspended and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 17, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
<p>THE STATE OF TEXAS, D<smcap>EPARTMENT OF </smcap>S<smcap>TATE</smcap>.</p>
<p>I, Joseph W. Baines, Secretary of State, of the State of Texas, do hereby certify that the Laws contained in this volume are true and cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rect copies of the enrolled bills now on file in this department. I further certify that the regular session of the Eighteenth Legislature convened at the city of Austin, on the ninth day of January, A. D. 1883, and ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />journed on the thirteenth day of April, A. D. 1883.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I hereto sign my name, and affix <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L. S.]</p></body></floatingText>the seal of the State of Texas, at Austin, on this, twelfth day of May, A. D. 1883.</p>
<closer>
<signed>JOS. W. BAINES, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="532" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX.</head>
<p>Amendments to City Charters&#8212;Austin............... 36</p>
<p>Dallas............... 24</p>
<p>Galveston............... 1</p>
<p>Houston.... 14</p>
<p>Austin&#8212;Amendments to city charter............... 36</p>
<p>Baker, Mosely, Heirs of&#8212;Relief granted to............... 32</p>
<p>Bean, W. P.&#8212;Relief granted to............... 14</p>
<p>Boom&#8212;E. S. Crosby granted right to construct across Brazos river............... 22</p>
<p>Byars, C. M.&#8212;Belief granted to............... 14</p>
<p>Charters&#8212;Austin city, amendments to............... 36</p>
<p>Dallas city, amendments to............... 24</p>
<p>Galveston city, amendments to............... 1</p>
<p>Houston city, amendments to............... 14</p>
<p>Chowning, H.&#8212;Relief granted to............... 14</p>
<p>Chowning. J. W.&#8212;Relief granted to............... 14</p>
<p>Creager, J. A.&#8212;Relief granted to............... 14</p>
<p>Crosby, E. S.&#8212;Boom, granted right to construct............... 22</p>
<p>Dallas&#8212;Amendments to city charter...............</p>
<p>Darby, Geo. W.&#8212;Relief granted to............... 14</p>
<p>Darden, Fannie A.&#8212;Relief granted to............... 32</p>
<p>Galveston&#8212;Amendments to city charter............... 1</p>
<p>Gonzales&#8212;Corporation boundaries defined............... 23</p>
<p>Harral, Milburn&#8212;Relief granted to............... 32</p>
<p>Houston&#8212;Amendments to city charter............... 14</p>
<p>Jefferson Iron Company&#8212;Authorized to surrender charter............... 34</p>
<p>Jones, R. F.&#8212;Relief granted, to............... 14</p>
<p>Jordan, Christian&#8212;Authorized to sue State............... 34</p>
<p>Linkhart, T. W. &#38; Co.&#8212;Relief granted to............... 14</p>
<p>Medina County&#8212;Certain lands to be patented for benefit of free schools............... 24</p>
<p>Miller, Alsey S.&#8212;Relief granted to............... 32</p>
<p>Musick, Ull&#8212;Relief granted to............... 14</p>
<p>Relief Granted to&#8212;Baker, Mosley, heirs............... 32</p>
<p>Bean, W. P.; Byars, C. M.; Chowning, H.; Chowning J. W.; Creager, J. A.; Darby, Geo. W................ 14</p>
<p>Harral, Milburn............... 32</p>
<p>Linkhart, T. W. &#38; Co.; Jones R. F................ 14</p>
<p>Miller, Alsey S................ 32</p>
<p>Musick, Ull; Stringley, J. A.; Sumner, J. R.; Wilson, J. P................ 14</p>
<p>Stringley, J. A.&#8212;Wilson, J. P.; Sumner, J. R................ 14</p>
<p>Thomson, John W., Heirs&#8212;Relief granted to............... 33</p>
<p>United States Government&#8212;Jurisdiction over certain property in Dallas ceded to............... 35</p>
<p>Woods, Mary A.&#8212;Relief granted to............... 32</p>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
