<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="975" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>PASSED AT THE <lb/>REGULAR SESSION OF THE TWENTIETH LEGISLATURE <lb/>CONVENED <lb/>AT THE CITY OF AUSTIN</head>
<byline>JANUARY 11, 1887, AND ADJOURNED APRIL 4, 1887.</byline>
<figure xml:id="fig1">
<graphic url="images/0975_001.jpg"/>
</figure>
<byline>AUSTIN, TEXAS 1887</byline>
<pb n="976" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX.</head>
<p>Bettijohn, S. W.&#8212;relief of...................................................................... 20</p>
<p>Charters&#8212;Dallas............................................................... 3</p>
<p>Galveston................................................................. 8, 14</p>
<p>Dallas&#8212;Charter amended.............................................................. 3</p>
<p>Early, J. B.&#8212;Relief of............................................................ 8</p>
<p>Farmer, Alexander&#8212;Relief of................................................. 19</p>
<p>Gaines, J. W.&#8212;Relief of................................................................. 20</p>
<p>Galveston&#8212;Charter amended....................................................... 8, 14</p>
<p>Holmes, James L., Heirs of&#8212;Relief of................................................. 22</p>
<p>Hughes, E. J.&#8212;Relief of............................................................ 20</p>
<p>Johnston, Pierce&#8212;Validating purchase of school lands............................... 7</p>
<p>Kuhlman, Wilhelm, Heirs of&#8212;Relief of................................................ 6</p>
<p>Parr, W. W.&#8212;Relief of................................................................... 20</p>
<p>Patton, J. C.&#8212;Relief of........................................................................ 21</p>
<p>Peery, W. T.<sub>;</sub> Heirs of&#8212;Relief of................................................ 19</p>
<p>Randall, S. S.&#8212;Relief of........................................................... 20</p>
<p>Robinson, O. B.&#8212;Relief of.................................................... 20</p>
<p>Starkie, L. O.&#8212;Relief of...................................................... 20</p>
<p>Stevens, John W.&#8212;Relief of................................................ 20</p>
<p>Storkigd, J. S.&#8212;Relief of.................................................. 20</p>
<p>Walker, William&#8212;Relief of........................................................... 20</p>
<p>Wilson, William&#8212;Authority to sue the State........................................ 18</p>
<pb n="977" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">SPECIAL LAWS OF TEXAS. TWENTIETH LEGISLATURE, 1887.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">DALLAS CITY&#8212;AMENDMENTS OF CHARTER.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 1.&#8212;[H. B. No. 280.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Sections 4 and 12 of an act entitled An Act amendatory or and supplementary to the several acts incorporating the city of Dallas, taking effect April 3, 1885, and to add thereto another section to be known as Section 15a, and also to amend Sections 25, 63, 84,91, 94, 113, 126 127, 133, and 179 of an act to incorporate the city Of Dallas, approved August 9, 1876, and all amendments to said sections by the amendatory acts of July 9, 1879, April 3, 1881, and March 31, 1883, and to repeal all laws and parts of laws in conflict herewith.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Section 4 of an act amendaitory of and supplementary to the several acts incorporating the city of Dallas, and talking effect April 3, 1885, be and the same is hereby amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 4. The municipal government of the city of Dallas shall consist of a city council, composed of the mayor and two aldermen from each ward. A majority of the aldermen shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, but a smaller number may adjourn from day to day, and may compel the attendance of absent members in such manner and under such penalties as they may prescribe. At called meetings, or meetings for the imposition of taxes, two-thirds of a full board shall be required. The other officers of the corporation shall be a city secretary, treasurer, an assessor, a collector, a city attorney, a city engineer, a city marshal, a city superintendent of water works, a health officer, a street superintendent, and such other officers and agents as the city council may hereafter create, all of whom shall be elected by the qualified voters of the city of Dallas, as provided for by the city charter, except the city secretary, city treasurer, and city attorney, who shall be elected by the city council at the first regular meeting in May, 1888, and every two years thereafter: Provided, That the assessor and collector mentioned in this section shall not he elected until the regular election of officers in 1888, when they shall be elected in such manner as may be provided for by the city charter.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That Section 12 of said last named act be and the same is hereby amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 12. The city council shall have power to fix the compensation of all city officers, and to regulate the fees of all jurors, witnesses, and others who ren<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der services under the charter and ordinances of said city. Whenever the city coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil shall fix the compensation to be paid any officer, whether elected by the peo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ple or by the council, they shall make the same playable monthly, out of the city treasury.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That there be added to said last named act another section, to be known as Section 15a, which shall read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 15a. In all cases of special assessments for local improvements of any kind, whatever, against any property, persons, or corporations whatsoever, and said assessment has failed to be valid, in whole or in part, because the charter provisions authorizing such assessment did not sufficiently point<pb n="978" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>out the mode and manner of making or enforcing the collection of such assessment, or because said assessment is void, insufficient, or inoperative for want of form or any non-compliance with the charter provisions governing such assessment, the city council shall be and are hereby authorized to reassess said special taxes or as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessments against the property of persons or corporations that may have been bene<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fited by the improvement made, and to enforce the collection of the same, said re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />assessment and collection to be made and enforced in accordance with the charter provisions existing at the time the reassessment is made.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That Section 25 of an act to incorporate the city of Dallas, approved August 9, 1876, and all amendments thereto by the amendatory acts of July 9, 1879, April 3, 1881, and March 31, 1883, be and the same are hereby amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 25. The assessor shall make up all the assessments of all property to he taxed by the city, including license and occupation taxes, and make duplicate rolls thereof; and on completion of said rolls and their approval by the city council, he shall deliver one of them to the city secretary and the other one to the collector, all to be done in such manner and by such time as the city council may prescribe by ordinance. The assessor shall perform such other duties as may be required of him by the city council. He shall receive for his services such salary as the city council may establish by ordinance. He shall give bond in such amount and in such form as the city council may prescribe, with good and sufficient sureties. He shall be and hereby is authorized to require the owners of all property subject to taxation by the city to render a correct account of the same under oath or affirma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, to be by him administered. The collector shall collect all taxes due the city, whether the same be general or special taxes, or special assessments for any purpose whatever. And in the event of the non-payment, of any of said taxes or assess<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments, he shall proceed to sell property to satisfy the amount of said taxes and assessments, together with all costs and penalties, in accordance with the provisions of the charter in such cases made and provided. In the performance of his duties the collector shall observe the charter provisions concerning the collection of taxes heretofore applying to the office of assessor and collector, and shall be governed by the same so far as they may be applicable. He shall give bond in such amount and form as the city council may prescribe, with, good and sufficient sureties. The city council may require a new bond whenever in their opinion the existing bond is insufficient; and whenever such bond is required, the collector shall perform no official act until said bond shall be given and approved. He shall at the expiration of every week pay to the city treasurer all money by him collected and report to the city council, at the first regular meeting in every month, all moneys so collected and paid. The collector shall perform all such other duties, and in such manner, and according to such rules and regulations, as the city council may prescribe. This section is not to be construed to authorize the collector and assessor herein mentioned to enter upon their respective duties herein provided for until after they shall be regularly elected in the year 1888, in such manner as may be pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided in the city charter. All provisions now in the charter regulating the duties of the present assessor and collector, are hereby made to govern the collector pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for in this section, as far as the same may be applicable to the office of col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lector.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That Section 63 of said last named act be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 63. To establish and regulate public pounds, and to regulate,<pb n="979" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>restrain, and prohibit the running at large of horses and mules, cattle, sheep, swine, and goats, and to authorize the detaining, impounding, and sale of the same for the costs of the proceedings and the penalty incurred, whether the owners thereof reside in or out of the city limits, and to order their destruction when they cannot be sold, and to impose penalties on the owners or keepers thereof for violation of such ordinance.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That Section 84 of said last named act be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 84. To appropriate so much of the resources of the city, emanating from whatever source, for the purpose of retiring and discharging the accrued in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />datedness of the city; and for the purpose of improving the public markets and streets, erecting and conducting city hospitals, city halls, water works, etc., as they may from time to time deem expedient; and in furtherance of these objects they shall have power to borrow money upon the credit of the city, and issue coupon bonds of the city thereof, in such sum or sums as they may deem expedient, to bear interest not exceeding six per cent per annum, payable semi-annually at such place as may be fixed by the city ordinance: Provided, That the aggregate amount of bonds issued by the city council shall at no time exceed one million dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That Section 91 of said last named act be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 91. That the city council shall have power to levy and collect taxes anually, known as license or occupation taxes, upon trades, professions, callings, and other business carried on, and upon carriages, hacks, coaches, buggies, drays, carts, wagons, and other vehicles used in said city, when the same are for public use; that each and every person or firm engaging in the following trades, profes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions, callings, and business, among others, shall be liable to pay such license tax; but this enumeration shall not be considered to deprive the city council of the bight and power to levy and collect other license taxes, and from other persons and firms, under the general authority herein granted, whether the same be taxed by the State or not.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That Section 94 of said last named act be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 94. That the city council may provide by ordinance for the exemption from taxation of such property as they may deem just and proper: Provided, Nothing contained herein shall be construed to allow the city council to exempt any persons, corporations, or property whatever from the payment of any special taxes or assessments whatever for local improvements of any kind or purpose whatever.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That Section 113 of said last named act be and the same is hereby amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 113. The city council are herein empowered to pass all ordinances neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary for the levying and proper assessment of all taxes and assessments provided for anywhere in any and all of the various acts incorporating the city of Dallas and in any and all acts amendatory thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That Section 126 of said last named act be and the same is hereby amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 126. On the first Tuesday in November of each year, the collector shall offer at public sale, at the court house door in the city of Dallas, all real estate on which taxes or special assessments shall remain due and unpaid, and such sale shall be made to realize all taxes due on such lands and all interest and costs of sale: Provided, That this section shall not be construed to prevent the sale of real estate for special assessments at such<pb n="980" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>other times as may be provided for elsewhere in the city charter and ordinances in pursuance thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That Section 127 of said last named act be and the same is hereby amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 127. Before such sale, notice of the time and place of sale, together with as near as may be a description of the property, shall be given by posting two notices, one at the court house and the other at the city hall in the city of Dallas, also by publication in some newspaper of the city once a week for at least four weeks before said sale, which notice shall contain a statement of the amount due on each particular piece of ground.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Thai Section 133 of said last named act be and the same is hereby amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 133. If from neglect of the officers, or from any other cause, real prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty is not duly advertised and sold on the first Tuesday in November of each year, then the city collector shall sell the same on the first Tuesday in December, or on the first Tuesday in any month thereafter, giving notice as provided for in Section 127 of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That Section 179 of said last named act be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 179. The city council are hereby empowered to enact all ordinances necessary for the enforcement of all the provisions contained in any and all acts incorporating the city of Dallas, or in any and all amendments thereto, and to levy, assess, and collect any and all taxes and assessments anywhere provided for in any of said acts of incorporation or in amendments thereto.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That all laws and parts of laws in conflict herewith be and the same are hereby repealed; that the completion of the improvements now in course of construction creates an emergency, and an imperative public necessity exists that the constitutional rule be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 80 yeas, 1 nay; and passed the Senate by a vote of 25 yeas, 1 nay.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March. 4, 1887</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">HEIRS OF WILHELM KUHLMAN&#8212;RELIEF OF.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 2.&#8212;[H. B. No. 172.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize and require the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue a patent to the heirs of Wilhelm Kuhlman for 320 acres of land located in Gillespie County on December 1, 1879, by virtue of Scrip No. 5.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas the heirs of Wilhelm Kuhlman have heretofore received from the State of Texas land scrip No. 5 for 320 acres of land, issued by J. Portis, commissioner of Fisher and Miller&#8217;s Colony, this certificate having been located in Gillespie County, on application of F. Winkel, by Julius Schuchard, the lawful county surveyor of said county, on the first day of December, 1879; and whereas said certificate, together with the field notes, properly authenticated, have been lost by mail while on the road to be returned to the General Land Office; and whereas, in consequence of the destruction of said certificate, a patent cannot be issued; and whereas said F. Winkle has given notice, as required by law in such cases, that he will apply to this Legislature for a special law granting the land located in Gillespie County, State of Texas, by virtue of said certificate No. 5, prior to the loss of the same.</p>
<pb n="981" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby authorized and required to issue a patent for the 320 acres of land located in Gillespie County by virtue of said certificate No. 5, to the heirs of Wilhelm Kuhlman: Provided, the issuance of said patent as provided above shall not prejudice the claim or claims of any other claimant to said land.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 15, 1887</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">VALIDATING PURCHASE OF SCHOOL LANDS BY PIERCE, JOHNSTON.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 3.&#8212;[H. B. No. 219.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to validate the purchase by Pierce Johnston from the State of Texas of certain school sections of lands lying in La Salle County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, on the-day of March, 1882, Pierce Johnston, county surveyor of La Salle County, purchased from the State of Texas, under the act of the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature approved April 6, 1881, six and one-half sections of land lying in La Salle County, belonging to the common school fund, viz.:</p>
<p>Survey Certificate No. Original Grantee.</p>
<p>162.......................... 15/3092 ....................... H. &#38; G. N. R. R. Co.</p>
<p>152.......................... 13/2796 ....................... H. &#38; G. N. R. R. Co.</p>
<p>156.......................... 12/2591  ...................... H. &#38; G. N. R. R. Co.</p>
<p>320 acres out of 22.......... 89 ............................ Seale &#38; Morris.</p>
<p>150.......................... 13/2797 ....................... H. &#38; G. N. R. R. Co.</p>
<p>74........................... 1599 .......................... B. S. &#38; F.</p>
<p>76........................... 1600 .......................... B. S. &#38; F.</p>
<p>And whereas the said Pierce Johnston in all things complied with the law in making said purchase and paid into the State Treasury one-twentieth of the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase money for said land; and whereas, in the winter of said year, 1882, the said Pierce Johnston sold and conveyed four and one-half sections or said land to Charles Sullivan, for the sum of three thousand one hundred and fifty dollars, the said Sullivan in addition thereto assuming to pay the State of Texas the balance of the purchase money due on the same; and whereas the said Pierce Johnston sold and conveyed the remaining two sections to Charles F. Shea, for a valuable consideration; and whereas both the said Sullivan and Shea purchased the same in good faith, under the impression that they were receiving a perfect title thereto, and in that belief have annually, as the law requires, paid into the State treasury the accrued interest on the unpaid purchase money assumed to be paid by them severally; and whereas they have improved said lands by a large outlay of money in constructing tanks and inclosing the same: Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the purchase of said six and one-half sections of land by Pierce Johnston, county sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyor of La Salle County, on the &#8212;&#8212;&#8212; day of March, 1882, be and the same is in all things affirmed and validated, and to have the same force and effect as if the said Pierce Johnston had not been county surveyor at the time of said purchase.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proval on the fifteenth day of March, 1887, but was not signed by him or re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turned to the house in which it originated with his objections thereto within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his sig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nature.&#8212;J. M. Moore, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div4>
</div3>
<pb n="982" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">RELIEF OF J. B. EARLY.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 4.&#8212;[H. B. No. 499.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of J. B. Early, and to validate Bounty Land Certificate No. 831 and the survey made by virtue thereof, issued by Ben F. Hill, Adjutant-General of Texas, on the 28th day of May, 1851, for 240 acres of land, to Henry W. Ward, the said J. B. Early being now the owner of said certificates.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas the land certificate issued to Henry W. Ward for 240 acres of land, on the 28th day of May, A. D. 1851, by the Adjutant-General of Texas, was by omission not presented for approval to the Commissioner of Claims, as required by law, said certificate being now in good faith located in Somervell County, formerly Hood County, Texas: Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That said land certificate issued to the said Henry W. Ward as aforesaid be and the same is hereby validated and declared a legal certificate, and the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby required to issue a patent by virtue of any location made by said certificate: Provided, That nothing herein contained shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strued to affect any rights of B. J. Chambers to the land covered by the location hereby validated.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the close of the present session of the Legislature rendering it doubtful as to whether this act can pass in the regular course of legislation, creates an imperative public necessity and emergency requiring the suspension of the constitutional rule which requires bills to be read on three sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral days, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 75 yeas, no nays; and passed the Senate by a vote of 24 yeas, 3 nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 29, 1887</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">GALVESTON CITY&#8212;AMENDMENTS OF CHARTER.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 5.&#8212;[S. H. B. No. 75.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the charter of the city of Galveston, by amending Sections 2, 3, 14, 19, 23, 54, 116, 122, and 127 thereof, and by adding thereto Sections 73a, 96a, 131a, and 132a.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions 2, 3, 14, 19, 23, 54, 116, 122, and 127, of the Charter of the City of Galveston, be and the same are hereby amended so that they shall hereafter read as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 2. That the limits of said city shall embrace so much of the island of Galveston from the point thereof on the east to Fifty-sixth [street], or to include the league and labor of land known as the Menard grant: Provided, That said league and labor shall extend beyond Fifty-sixth street; thence to include Galves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton Bay and Pelican Island, and one mile north thereof; and the waters of the Gulf of Mexico extending south one marine league from the shore, from the chan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nel and anchorage on the eastern end of Galveston Island to the western Boundary of the city, so as to extend the police authority and jurisdiction, inclusive of Peli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />can Island, over all the area and territory aforesaid: Provided, nevertheless, That jurisdiction shall extend from the eastern boundary of said city over all real estate beyond said limits purchased by said city for the use of the corporation: And provided furthermore, That all the municipal regulations of said city shall apply to, extend, and be in full force over the harbor and anchorage of Galves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, and to the bar at the entrance of said harbor, and the corporate authority<pb n="983" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and jurisdiction shall extend from the eastern boundary of said city over the east end of Galveston Island, and over all real estate beyond said limits purchased by said city for the use of the corporation: And provided further, That the said limits may be hereafter extended, including and adding more territory to the same, whenever a majority of the inhabitants of said territory shall indicate a desire to be included within the limits of said city: And provided further, That neither the corporate limits nor the jurisdiction of said city shall extend to any point of the mainland so as to interfere or conflict in any wise with the riparian rights and privileges of the owners of the mainland or any part thereof bordering upon the waters of said bay: And provided further, That the jurisdiction of said city shall not extend over Bolivar Channel except for police and sanitary purposes.</p>
<p>Section 3. The municipal government of said city shall consist of a city coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cil, composed of a mayor, and one alderman from each ward. A majority of the aldermen elected shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, except at a called meeting or meetings for the imposition of taxes, when three-fourths of the aldermen elected shall be required, unless herein otherwise specified. The officers of the corporation shall be a treasurer and asssesor, a collector, a clerk, a chief of police, an engineer (who shall also be superintendent of streets), an attorney, an auditor, a health physician, a Harbor master, and such other officers and agents as the council may direct; all of whom shall be appointed by the mayor on the second Monday after each biennial election, or as soon thereafter as possible, and each of whom shall be confirmed by a majority of the board of aldermen. All of said officers so appointed by the mayor shall hold their offices until the second Monday after the next succeeding biennial election, and until the appointment and qualification of their successors, unless removed by the mayor or by the city council under authority vested in it by this enarter. The duties of the harbor master shall be such as have been or may be prescribed by the city council, and he shall receive for his services such compensation as the city council may determine, not to exceed eighteen hundred dollars per annum, and shall give bond for the faithful performance of his duties in the sum of ten thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Section 14. The mayor shall preside over the meetings of the city council, but shall have no vote unless there is a tie, in which case he shall give the casting vote. He shall also be recorder, and have like power with a justice of the peace to administer oaths of office and also all oaths and affirmations, and to give cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates thereof. He shall possess and execute in the city, in criminal cases, all the powers and duties of a justice of the peace. He shall be compensated for his services by a salary of three thousand dollars per annum, payable at stated periods, and shall receive such fees as may be allowed by law, which fees shall be paid into the city treasury. He shall, by and with the consent of the board of aldermen, have power to remove any officer bolding office under the appointment of the mayor, and shall, by and with the consent of the board of aldermen, fill by appointment any vacancy occasioned by such removal. He shall have authority, in case of a riot or any unlawful assemblage, or with a view to preserve peace and good order in said city, to order and enforce the closing of any theater, ball room, grog shop, tippling house, bar room, or other place of resort, or public room or building, and may order the arrest of any person violating in his presence the laws of the State or any ordinances of the city; and he shall perform such other duties and possess and exercise such other power and authority as may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Scribed and conferred by the city council.</p>
<p>Section 19. It shall be the duty of the city attorney to represent the city<pb n="984" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>in all cases brought for or against it in the courts of the State or United States in the county of Galveston, and in the recorder&#8217;s court when requested by the mayor in writing, or by order of the city council. He shall give legal advice to the mayor, any officer, or the city council, when applied for in writing or referred to him by the city council. He shall prepare all ordinances, and examine, super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vise and prepare all contracts made by the city. He shall receive an annual salary of not to exceed twenty-five hundred dollars, and such fees and commissions as may be provided by the city council. He shall give bond for the faithful per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formance of his duties in the sum of five thousand dollars. The powers, duties, and qualifications of the city engineer, and the salary for his services, shall be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by the city council, not to exceed two thousand dollars, and such fees as may be prescribed by ordinance. As to officers&#8217; fees, thus section shall not be sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject to the provisions of Section 171 of this charter.</p>
<p>Section 23. It shall be the duty of the auditor to examine in detail all bills, accounts, and claims against the city, and if found correct sign his name in ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proval, but if found incorrect he shall return them to the appropriate committee or the city council with his objections thereto. It shall also be his duty to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />amine the books of all officers of the city, and if they should be found incorrect to make a report of the same to the city council. It shall also be his duty to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />amine all warrants and countersign the same when an appropriation has been duly made to pay the same by the city council; and he shall render such other services from time to time as the city council may direct, and shall receive for his services such compensation as the city council may determine, not to exceed eighteen hundred dollars per annum, and shall give bond for the faithful per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formance of his duties in the sum of ten thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Section 54. To pass ordinances for the condemnation of property for the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses of opening streets in the city, conforming the mode and manner of the same to the rales prescribed for cities and towns by the General Laws of the State; and to regulate, prohibit, or remove all buildings or structures on the shores or in the waters within the limits of the city where the same are not authorized by law.</p>
<p>Section 116. There shall be and is hereby created a board, called the commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners of water works, to consist of five members, to be appointed by the mayor and confirmed by the city council, who shall hold their offices for the term of four years, and until their successors are duly elected and qualified, except as herein<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after prescribed. Said commissioners shall be entitled to receive such salary as the city council may determine, not to exceed three hundred dollars each per annum, payable quarterly. The mayor, with the approval of the city council, shall have the power to remove any commissioner for cause, and to fill any vacancy occur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ring in said office either from death, resignation, removal from office, removal from the city, or other cause. All appointments to fill vacancies shall be for the unex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pired term. No person shall be eligible to the office of commissioner unless be is thirty years of age, a freeholder and qualified voter in said city. The mayor shall, on the first Monday in July, 1887, or as soon thereafter as practica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble, appoint the five commissioners provided for in this act, and said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners shall hold their offices two of them for two years and three of them for four years from the date of appointment. The mayor shall issue commissions to the persons so appointed, designating the terms for which they are severally appointed, and whenever the term of of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fice of any commissioner expires the appointment of his successor shall be for four years. Said commissioners shall take the oath of office required of other<pb n="985" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>officers of said city, and give bond for the faithful performance of their duties, payable to the city of Galveston, in the sum of ten thousand dollars, to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the mayor of the city. Upon the appointment and qualification of the commissioners they shall organize by the election of a president from among their own number, and appoint a secretary, with such salary as they may prescribe, and a majority of the commissioners shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. They shall advertise and let contracts for the construction of a sys<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tem of water works, according to plans and specifications to be adopted by them, but all contracts shall be subject to the approval of the city council, and shall be signed by the mayor and countersigned by the city clerk before the same shall take effect. Any contract made under the provisions of this section shall state the source of water supply, the location, capacity, and plan of the main reservoir; the location, capacity, and plan of all stand-pipes and reservoirs in the city, and the location, size, number, and material of all hydrants. Any contract made under this act for the construction of water works shall be paid for by the city, in five per cent forty-year bonds, issued for the purpose of constructing water works. For the purpose of obtaining information, and paying their necessary expenses and the expense of a competent engineer for consulting and advisory purposes, said board is hereby authorized to expend the sum of ten thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, to be paid by the city council out of the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeds of sales of bonds to be issued for the construction of water works. The water works, except the assessment of water rates and the collection of revenue therefrom after their construction, shall be under the control and management of the board of commissioners of water works, and the board shall appoint all officers, agents, and other subordinates and employes as may be necessary for the man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />agement and efficient operation of said water works, as may be provided by ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance. The board shall have authority to remove or suspend any officer, agent, or employe of said department. The doing of all work and repair&#8217;s, and the fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nishing of all material and supplies, shall be let out by the board by contract, except in cases where it is not practical to do such work or furnish such material by contract, and all contracts involving the expenditure of over one thousand dollars shall be submitted to the city council for their approval. Whenever the city council shall by ordinance provide for the extension of the system of water works along streets and alleys not supplied in the original construction of the water works, the board shall contract for the construction of the same in the man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner hereinbefore provided, subject to the approval of the City council. The city council shall fix, assess, and collect all water rates and tolls, and pass all ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nances necessary for the protection, preservation, and regulation of the water works, and enforce the same by suitable penalties. The board shall keep a record of their proceedings in a well bound book kept for that purpose; they shall keep an account of all contracts, purchases, and expenditures made by them, and shall report to the city council on the first day of every month a pay roll and list of expenditures made in their department during the preceding month.</p>
<p>Section 122. In order to effect the abatement of nuisances or removal of ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ccmulated filth, the board of health shall have power, whenever in their opinion such nuisance or filth exist, and is, or is likely to become, detrimental to the public health, after officially so declared by them, to notify in writing, through its officers, the owner, agent, lessee, or tenant there of, to abate or remove the same, either by filling up, draining, cleansing, purify<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, or removing the same, as the case may be. If the owner who shall<pb n="986" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>have been served with such notice shall fail within the time indicated in the notice to comply with such order of the board, or fail to show good cause why he cannot or ought not to comply with such order, for which purpose he shall be entitled to be heard before said board if he so requests it, he shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction shall be fined not less than ten dollars, nor more than two hundred dollars, with an additional fine of not less than five nor more than fifty dollars imposed for each and every day that the person or persons thus con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />victed shall, after conviction and due notice thereof, fail or refuse to abate or use due diligence in the work of abating such nuisance; and if such service cannot be made, for the reason that the owner, agent, lessee, or tenant of the property upon which the nuisance may exist cannot be found in the city, of which fact the return upon such notice of the officer serving the same shall be conclusive evidence, then the board shall cause such notice to be published in the newspaper doing the city printing for five consecutive days (Sundays excepted), and if within five days after such service of notice, or after its publication as aforesaid, such nuisance shall not be abated or the order observed by the owner, then the board shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port the same with the proceedings had by them thereon to the city council, and thereupon the city council shall, if two-thirds of all the aldermen elect vote there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />for, order said nuisance to be a bated, either by filling up, draining, cleansing, puri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fying, or removing the same, as the case may be, under the supervision of the city engineer. The city council before ordering said nuisance to be abated shall, for the purpose of acquiring the most reliable information practicable of the prob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able cost of said work, cause an estimate to be made of said probable cost by the city engineer, and said engineer shall also report, a full list of all lots or fraction of a lot with the number of blocks upon which such nuisance is situated, and the names of the owners thereof, and such other information as may be required by the city council, and if there be any lot or fractional lot the owner whereof is not known, the same shall be entered on said list as &#8220;unknown,&#8221; and said engineer shall enter in said list opposite each lot or fractional lot the estimated cost of the work to be done on the same; and when said work is ordered by the city council, and shall have been completed, the council shall cause an accurate report of the cost thereof to be made by said engineer, stating the cost of the work done on each lot or fractional lot, and upon the acceptance and approval of said report and list by the council, said amounts shall be imposed, levied, and assessed by the city council on said lots or fractional lots respectively, and collected by the col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lector, and shall be a first privileged lien upon the property until paid. Said assess<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment shall bear interest at the rate of eight per cent per annum from the date of assessment until paid. The enforcement of the payment of said assessment shall be regulated, governed, and controlled in the mode and manner provided for the collection of assessments for street improvements contained in section one hundred and twenty-nine: Provided, That for any such assessment and interest as afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said, the city council may cause suit to be instituted and recovery had in the name of the city in any court having jurisdiction, and the report of the engineer of the cost of said work, together with the proceedings of the city council making said levy and assessment, or a copy thereof duly certified by the city clerk, shall be full proof and satisfactory evidence for the recovery of judgment for said assessment and interest.</p>
<p>Section 127. The city council shall be invested with full power and author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity to grade, fill, raise, repair, pave, or otherwise improve any avenue, street, or alley, or any portion thereof, within the limits of said city, when<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever by a vote of two-thirds of the aldermen elected they may deem such im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="987" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>provement for the public interest: Provided, The city pay one-third and the own<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers of the property two-thirds of the paving thereof, except the intersection of the streets from lot to lot across the streets either way shall be paid by the city alone. Said two-thirds of said costs of the paving to be paid by the owners of the prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty fronting on said thoroughfares shall be assessed on or against said property and collected by the city whenever such improvement is completed and accepted by the city council: Provided further, That not more than thirty thousand super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficial yards of such thoroughfares shall be filled, graded, and paved in any one year: Provided further, That the filling, raising, and grading of streets or alleys upon which the limitation as to paving does not apply the city council shall fix the maximum grade on Broadway at not less than ten feet above mean low tides, so as to drain the city north and south from Broadway.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the charter of the city of Galveston be amended by addling thereto Sections 73a, 96a, 131a, and 132a, as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Section 73a. To regulate, control, and direct the mode and manner of the laying and construction of street railway tracks, switches, turnouts, turn-tables, and other necessary structures in the streets and alleys, and to compel railway com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />panies to keep the streets between their rails ballasted and graded on a level with their rails; and to keep the space between their rails in all paved streets in per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fect repair, or to pay actual cost of the same when done by the city; to compel the street railway companies to build all necessary culverts, and to make all neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary improvements, so as to insure a safe and easy passage for vehicles over said streets, or to pay the actual cost of the same when done by the city; to compel street railways to raise or lower their rails and the road-beds between the same to conform to the grades of the streets, or to pay the actual cost of the same if done by the city; to compel street railway companies to pay the actual cost of filling and grading, or filling, grading and paving the streets between their rails in all cases where the same may be filled and graded, or filled, graded, and paved by the city: Provided, That this section shall not alter or change the mode of improving streets and assessing the cost of the same, as prescribed in Sections 127, 128, 129, and 130 of the city charter. To regulate -the speed of street cars; to forfeit rights of way and franchises heretofore or hereafter granted to street railway companies, for non-user or abandonment; and to enforce the provisions of this section by proper ordina ces and penalties.</p>
<p>Section 96a. That in all cases where any dealer in merchandise, wares, or goods of any kind subject to ad valorem or occupation taxes, or both, under the provis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ions of this act, who shall, after the rendition of said goods, wares, or merchandise for taxation, or, after becoming liable for any occupation tax, become bankrupt, or make an assignment of said merchandise, wares, or goods, or sell out the same in bulk, then the collector of taxes shall at once present to the receiver, assignee, or vendee of said dealer, for payment, the amount due for said taxes by said dealer, and in case of failure of said receiver, assignee, or vendee to at once pay the amount of said taxes, the said collector shall levy upon, seize, and sell, from the said merchandise, wares, or goods, enough to satisfy the amount of said taxes; and said taxes until paid shall constitute a prior lien on said mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chandise, goods, and wares in default of the payment of said taxes. And when<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever any merchandise, wares, or goods shall be levied upon or seized under any writ of attachment or execution upon which the city has a claim for taxes unpaid, the collector shall present for payment, to the officer levying said writ of attachment or execution, the amount due for said taxes on said<pb n="988" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>merchandise, wares, or goods, and in case of failure of said officer or the plaintiff in said writ to at once pay the amount of said taxes, the collector shall proceed to levy upon, seize, and sell enough of said merchandise, wares, or goods to satisfy the amount of said taxes.</p>
<p>Section 131a. The said city shall have the power to appropriate the net pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeds of the bonds authorized under Section 131 of the city charter, for the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of paying and redeeming the legal and valid floating debts of the city exist<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing on the first day of January, 1887, not to exceed in amount the sum of one hundred and fifty thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Section 132a. The said0 city shall have the power to issue bonds to the extent of seven hundred thousand dollars, of the denomination of one hundred dollars or any multiple thereof, payable at forty years after the date of their issue, bearing interest at a rate not to exceed five per cent per annum, payable semi-annually. The net proceeds of four hundred and fifty thousand dollars of said bonds shall be used exclusively for the establishment and construction of water works for the supply of fresh water for the city of Galveston and its citizens, and for the establishment of a system of sewerage for said city. The net proceeds of two hundred thousand dollars of said bonds shall be used exclusively for permanent street improvements, not more than forty thousand dollars of which shall be expended in any one year. And the net proceeds of fifty thousand dollars of said bonds shall be used for the construction of a city hall. The indebtedness provided for in this section shall not be governed and limited by the provisions and limitations contained in section one hundred and fifty-two of this charter: Provided, That said bonds shall not be sold for less than par: Provided, That no contract for water works or work done in the construction of water works shall be paid for with the bonds hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to be issued, but said work shall be paid for with cash arising from the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeds of the sale of said bonds.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That whereas the near approach of the end of the present session creates an imperative public necessity requiring the suspension of the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days; therefore said rule is hereby suspended; and it is further enacted that this bill take effect and be in force from and after the first day of July, A. D. 1887.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 78 yeas, 1 nay; and passed the Senate by a vote of 23 yeas, no nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 29, 1887</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">GALVESTON CITY&#8212;AMENDMENTS OF CHARTER.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 6.&#8212;[S. B. No. 290.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amendatory of and supplementary to an act entitled An Act to incorporate the city of Galveston and to grant a new charter, approved August 2, 1876, and amended April 5, 1881, March 7, 1883, and Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary 26, 1885, by adding thereto Title No. 13, authorizing the construction of sea-walls and breakwaters, and for that purpose authorizing the exercise of the right of eminent domain, the issuance of bonds, and the levy of a, tax, and granting in aid of said works certain rights and privileges in and to the land upon the gulf shore opposite said city from the southwest corner of the city league to the east end of Galveston Island.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That said act be and the same is hereby amended by the addition of a title to be known as Title 13, to read as follows:</p>
<p>Title 13. Article I. Section 177. The city council shall have power to<pb n="989" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>establish, locate, erect, construct, and keep in repair, sea-walls, breakwaters, and other works which said council may deem necessary for the protection of the city from encroachment or overflow by the waters of the gulf or bay; and said council shall have full and continuing power over and about said works to. renew, alter, remove, or relocate the same; to license and regulate such additional uses of said works as will not impair their efficiency, or to prohibit the said additional uses; to pass ordinances for protection and preservation, of said works from obstructions or injuries of any description; and to impose fines and imprisonment, within the limits prescribed by this charter, for the violation of either or any of the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of said ordinances.</p>
<p>Section 178. The city council shall have power to impose additional uses and burdens upon the streets, avenues, alleys, and public grounds of said city for the location and maintenance of sea-walls and breakwaters; also power to take such lands as said council may deem necessary for the establishment, location, and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction and protection of sea-walls, breakwaters, and other like works for the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tection of the city from encroachment or overflow by the waters of the gulf or bay, and for said purposes to define the area of land needed, and to take the use of and easement over said lands, but in no case shall the fee to the land be taken except by consent of the owner or owners thereof.</p>
<p>Section. 179. In exercising the right of eminent domain under the preceding sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion the city shall make a just compensation for the property taken, damaged, or destroyed; and whenever the city, its officers or agents, cannot agree with the owners of the property which is to be taken, damaged, or destroyed, as to the amount of compensation, or whenever the owners thereof are under any legal dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ability or unknown, the amount of compensation shall be ascertained and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posited with the city treasurer in trust for the owner thereof before said city shall have the right to enter upon said land for any purpose other than the mak<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of preliminary surveys.</p>
<p>Section 180. If the parties cannot agree as to the amount of compensation pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for in the preceding section, or if the owners of the land required are under any legal disability or unknown, the city council shall by resolution define the land sought to be condemned for said uses, giving the names and residences of the owners thereof if known, and indicating who if any among said owners are minors or under other disability, and said council shall file a copy of said resolution with the county judge of Galveston County, who shall appoint commissioners as provided by Article 4183 of the Revised Statutes, and notice shall be given to the owners, the compensation shall be assessed, and the condemnation of the land or the use thereof as defined by the city council shall be enforced under and in compliance with the laws of this State regulating the appropriation of lands for railroad purposes in so far as the same are applicable, and the proceedings under said laws and the judg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the county court thereunder shall vest in the city of Galveston the estate in fee simple or such less estate in the lands as may be taken hereunder.</p>
<p>Article II. Section 181. Before incurring any indebtedness, and before issuing the bonds of the city for the purpose of constructing sea-walls and breakwaters, and securing the right of way therefor, the city council shall by ordinance prescribe the amount of the bonds to be issued and the rate of interest thereon, and provide for an election at which all taxpayers who are qualified voters entitled to vote in said city shall be allowed to vote for or against the proposed taxation for the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of said bonds and interest thereon.</p>
<pb n="990" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Section 182. For the purpose of ascertaining whether two-thirds of the tax<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />payers of said city have voted, in favor of the proposed taxation, the mayor, the city (assessor, and the city collector are hereby constituted and appointed a board of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quiry. Whenever an election is ordered hereunder said board shall make out from the latest completed assessment roll of said city a list of all taxpayers of said city who are qualified voters therein, and from the date of the notice of said election until five days before the day thereof said board shall sit daily for the purpose of making additions to and corrections of said list, and all taxpayers shall, during said period, have the right to apply to said board and to have their names entered on said list. During the period of five days before said election said board shall make out under certificate and file with the city clerk a Complete alphabetical list of all the taxpayers who are qualified voters at said election, and shall furnish printed copies of said list to the officers at each poll at said election: Provided, neverthe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />less, That the judges of said election shall have the right to examine any person offering to vote whose name is not on said list, and shall receive the vote of such person if satisfied that he is a taxpayer and qualified voter in said city, and a list of the names of all persons thus permitted to vote shall be kept by the officers of the election, and said lists, together with the printed lists furnished by said board, and the returns and poll lists of said deletion, shall the returned to the city clerk. The ballots at said election shall be printed or written on white paper, without any outward mark or device to distinguish the same, and shall (contain the words, in substance, &#8220;in favor of the proposed tax,&#8221; or &#8220;against the proposed tax.&#8221; Said election shall be, except as herein otherwise provided, ordered and conducted in the same (manner in all respects as elections for mayor and aldermen of said city, and the returns thereof shall be made in like manner: Provided, nevertheless, That said election may be held upon thirty days notice thereof at any time fixed by the city council: And provided further, That the council may renew the propo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sition to tax for sea-walls and breakwaters until the limit of the indebtedness herein authorized has been reached.</p>
<p>Section 183. The city council shall, as soon as practicable after said election, meet and canvass the returns thereof, and &#8216;with the aid of tire returns and lists herein provided for, together with such other evidence as may foe required, ascer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain and record in the minutes of said council the total number of taxpayers of said city who are qualified voters in said city on the day of said election, the number of said taxpayers voting in favor of the proposed taxation, and the number of said taxpayers voting against the same. In the event that two-thirds of the taxpayers of said city who are qualified voters therein shall have voted in favor of the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed tax, the said city shall thereupon have power to issue its&#8217; &#8216;bonds for the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction and maintenance of sea-walls and breakwaters, &#8216;and for securing the right of way for said) works: Provided, however, That the tota.1 amount of the bonds issued hereunder shall not exceed eight hundred thousand dollars, and that the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest.on said bonds, which shall be payable semi-annually, shall not exceed six per cent&#8217;per annum.. Said bonds shall be issued in denominations of one hundred dollars or multiples thereof, and made payable thirty years.after the date of their issuance, and the city council shall &#8216;by ordinance prescribe the style, form, and requisites of said bonds, the amount of bonds to be issued, the annual rate of inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est, and the time and place or places of paying the same; and said council shall make all further provision required for the issuance and disposal of said bonds: Provided, however. That said bonds shall not&#8217; be issued without.the assent of.the Galveston Sea-Wall &#8216;Commission herein created, which assent shall foe endorsed<pb n="991" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>on said bonds before issuance, together with the signatures of the president and secretary of said commission: And further provided, That said bonds shall not be sold below their par or face value.</p>
<p>Section 184. Whenever bonds are issued under the preceding section the city council shall, without regard to the general limitation of taxes prescribed by this charter, annually levy, assess, and collect, in the mode prescribed by law for other municipal taxes, a tax on all the real estate and personal property in the city not exempt from taxation by the Constitution, sufficient to pay the interest and provide a sinking fund of not less than two per cent of the principal of all of said bonds which are outstanding or which are to be issued during the year, and all taxes collected by virtue hereof shall be held in trust by the city as a special and inviolable fund for the payment of the interest and principal of said bonds: Provided, however, That with the advice and consent of the Galveston Sea Wall Commission herein created, any surplus over and above the amount re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to meet the annual interest on said bonds may be invested for the benefit of the sinking fund; first, in the bonds issued hereunder, which may be offered for sale by a written proposal filed with the city clerk; secondly, if there be no unaccepted offer or offers to sell said bonds on file with said clerk, in approved securities of this State, or the counties thereof, or of the United States. But no bonds or securities shall ever be bought or paid for at a greater rate than their face or par value, with accrued interest.</p>
<p>Article III. Section 185. There shall be and is hereby created a commission composed of three members, to be styled the Galveston Sea-Wall Commission. If the votes of two-thirds of the taxpayers of said city shall be in favor of the levy of said tax, the Governor of the State shall thereupon appoint the members of said commission, one of whom shall be selected from the aldermen of the city, and all of the members shall be citizens of the city and taxpayers therein. The Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor shall also fill all vacancies in said commission, observing the requirements last above imposed as to original appointments, and he shall have full power to remove from office any of said commissioners. The members of said commission shall not directly or indirectly, as individuals or as members of any company or corporation, become interested in any contract growing out of the construction of the works, or the sale or the purchase of bonds herein authorized, and each mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber shall, before entering upon the duties of his office, make oath, in the presence of the city council, in form as follows: I, &#8212;&#8212;&#8212;, to solemnly swear that I am not interested in any contract growing out of the construction of sea-walls, breakwaters, or other like works, or in the sale or purchase of bonds connected with said works, and that I will well and truly, discharge my duty as a member of the Galveston, Sea-Wall Commission. Said commissioners shall, unless sooner re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moved, hold their office for a term of two years, corresponding to the term of the mayor and aldermen, and until their successors are appointed and qualified, and shall each receive a salary of not less than one thousand dollars per annum. Said commission shall elect a presiding officer, and may employ a secretary and a consulting engineer, at salaries to be fixed by the city council, Said commission shall be and is hereby charged with the duty of ascertaining and adopting the plans and specifications for the works best adapted to se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cure the city from overflow, and with the awarding of contracts for the construction of the whole or any part of said works, and the inspection and acceptance and rejection of said works and the material therein if the same are constructed under contract, and with the purchase of material and employment of labor if said commission shall deem it expedient to<pb n="992" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>construct said works or any part thereof under its immediate supervision. It shall audit and approve all bills and claims of every description payable from the funds raised under this act, and payments out of said fund, shall be made by the city treasurer on drafts by the president of said commission, countersigned by the secretary thereof, accompanying the bills and claims so approved. Said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission shall also be charged with the duty of negotiating the right of way for said works, if necessary, and making contracts therefor, and with the sale of the bonds issued hereunder, which shall be turned over to said commission for de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />livery, upon a requisition stating fully the proposed disposition of said bonds.</p>
<p>Article IV. Section 186. To better enable the city to secure the protection herein provided for, and to aid in the construction of said works, the right to the use and control of that certain strip or tract of land or sea bottom fifteen hundred yards in width lying along the gulf shore south of and contiguous to the line of mean low tide, and extending from the south jetty at the east end of Galveston Island to the prolongation of the western line of the Menard or city league, shall be and is hereby granted to said city, together with the right to reclaim land along the gulf shore Within said limits: Provided, nevertheless, That the lights, uses, and powers herein granted shall be enjoyed, used, and exercised without inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fering permanently with the rights of the public to the sea shore or with the maintenance of a beach from ordinary high tide to low water.</p>
<p>Section 187. All funds, revenues, and moneys derived from the sale of the bonds herein authorized, the sale or rent of reclaimed or other lands acquired under this act, and from the additional uses of said works as herein authorized, shall be deposited with the city treasurer, and said funds, revenues, and moneys&#8217;, together with all lands acquired under this act, shall be held in trust by the city ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clusively for the construction and maintenance of sea-walls and breakwaters and for the purchase of the right of way therefor: Provided however, That said funds, revenues, and moneys, or part thereof, may be applied if necessary to the payment of the interest or to the sinking fund of the bonds issued for constructing said works.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas the necessity for the speedy construction of the protection works herein authorized creates an emergency calling for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and for the immediate operation of this act, said rule shall be and is hereby suspended, and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the Senate, and passed the same by a vote of 23 yeas, no nays; and passed the House by a vote of 71 yeas.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>March 30, 1887</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">AUTHORIZING WILLIAM M. WILSON TO SUE THE STATE.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 7.&#8212;[S. S. B. No. 206.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize William M. Wilson to sue the State of Texas in the District Court of Travis County, Texas, to determine whether or not the State of Texas is indebted to him in any sum on account of the building and construction of the State Penitentiary at Rusk.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That William M. Wilson be and is hereby authorized to sue the State of Texas in the District Court of Travis County, Texas, to determine whether or not the State of Texas is indebted to said Wilson on account of the building and<pb n="993" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>construction of the State penitentiary at Rusk, Texas, and to fix the amount, of such indebtedness, if any.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the sum of nine thousand dollars, or so much thereof as is necessary be and the same is hereby appropriated to pay off and satisfy any judgment that may be rendered against the State by virtue of this suit: Provided, That the State shall in no event be required to pay any court cost or costs of said suit, but the same shall be paid by said Wilson; and he shall be required to give the necessary cost bond as is required in other civil actions: And provided further, Either party shall have the right of appeal to the Supreme Court of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Nothing herein shall be construed as an admission on the part of the State that said Wilson has any cause of action whatever against it, nor that the State is indebted to said Wilson in any sum whatsoever.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 2, 1887</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">FOR RELIEF OF HEIRS OF ALEXANDER FARMER.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 8.&#8212;[H. B. No. 463.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the heirs of Alexander Farmer, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be and he, is hereby authorized, em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />powered, and required to issue to the heirs of Alexander Farmer, deceased, the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing certificates, to-wit: One special headright certificate for two-thirds of a league and a full labor of land; one donation certificate for six hundred and forty acres; one bounty certificate for six hundred and eighty acres.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said certificates may be located upon any of the vacant lands belonging to the State of Texas not heretofore appropriated or reserved from location: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, That if said Certificates cannot be located on any public land, the owners thereof shall have no claim against the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The near approach of the end of the present session of the Legislature rendering it improbable that this bill will pass in the regular course of legislation, creates an imperative public necessity for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 2, 1887</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">FOR RELIEF OF W. T. PEERY, ETC.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 9.&#8212;[H. B. No. 607.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of W. T. Peery, and to relin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quish the title of the State of Texas to certain lands to the said Peery under a judgment obtained in the District Court of Cooke County on the 9th day of December, 1867, against J. M. and E. C. Peery.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas certain lands of Wm. Peery, deceased, were supposed to be escheated to the State of Texas about the year 1801, in Cooke County, Texas; and whereas said lands were sold to J. M. and E. O. Beery and judgment obtained against said ven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dees, and an order enforcing the vendors lien of the State on said lands; and whereas the heir of the said Wm. Peery appeared and received the purchase money for said land, alter proving up his heirship to the satisfaction of the county court, on the 27th day of April, 1869; and whereas the said judgment of foreclosure in favor of the State of Texas still remains unsatisfied and is a cloud upon the title to<pb n="994" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>said, land, to-wit, the Wm. R. Middleton survey of three hundred and twenty acres, and the James Rutledge survey of three hundred and twenty acres, situated in Cooke County, Texas; and whereas the State of Texas has by reason of the prem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ises aforesaid no right to or interest in said judgment or said land: Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted be the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the State of Texas hereby relinquishes all claim to or interest in said judgment or the land aforesaid to the said W. T. Peery, his heirs and assigns.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas the near approach of the close of the session of the Legislature and the injury likely to result to the true owner of said land creates an imperative public necessity requiring that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house be suspended, and that the bill be passed, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 4, 1887</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">FOR RELIEF OF S. S. RANDALL, ET AL.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 10.&#8212;[H. B. No. 608.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of S. S. Randall, William Walker, J. W. Gaines, W. W. Parr, John W. Stevens, L. O. Starkie, S. W. Betti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />john, O. B. Robinson, E. J. Hughes,. J. S. Storkigd, and the relief of such parties by whom and through whom they hold.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas the State of Texas has instituted [suit] to escheat a certain, tract of land containing fourteen hundred and seventy-nine acres, situated on the Leon, in Comanche County, Texas, granted to Henry Hubble as assignee of E. H. Wind<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />field; and whereas the said parties hold the said land by purchase, and have occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pied the same for a great number of years, paying taxes thereon, and have given notice of intention to apply for legislative relief, as provided by Section 57, Article 3, of the Constitution of the State of Texas: Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That all rights of the State by reason of the escheat of said land, or proceedings to escheat, be and the same are hereby relinquished to the said parties and the parties under and from reborn the said parties hold, and that the Attorney-General of the State he instructed to cause the district attorney to dismiss the suit by the State in the District Court of Comanche County brought to escheat said lands.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Nothing herein contained shall be construed to prejudice the rights of Thomas Frazier, his heirs or assigns, or any other person from or under whom the said parties hold, and the said panties are- hereby quieted in their title and posses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion in and to said lands, in so far as any adverse right, title, or claim of the State is concerned.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Whereas the said District Court of Comanche County is soon to convene, therefore an imperative public necessity and emergency exist for the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and the said rule is therefore suspended, and this act takes effect from and after its passage.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 68 yeas, 9 nays; and passed the Senate by a vote of 24 yeas.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 4, 1887</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
<pb n="995" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 11.&#8212;[S. B. No. 323.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of J. C. Patton.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas J. C. Patton is the legal owner of nineteen alternate certificates for land, of three hundred and twenty acres each, viz., Certificates Nos. 25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30, 49, 50, 52, 53, 54, 55, 56, 59, 61, 83, 85, 87, and 88, issued March 20, A. D. 1873, by the Commissioner of the General Land] Office of the State of Texas to the Sulphur Pork Iron Works Company a company duly chartered by the laws of Texas:</p>
<p>And whereas said nineteen certificates became in due course of trade, and for a valuable consideration, the lawful property of the said J. C. Patton, and were by him placed in the hands of the surveyor of Jack Land District for location upon the unappropriated public domain of Texas;</p>
<p>And whereas by and through the carelessness and neglect of said district sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyor, the said certificates were, without the knowledge and consent of said Pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, located, or attempted to be located, and surveyed upon lands already appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated, and which locations and surveys were not ratified and confirmed by patents;</p>
<p>And whereas information of the failure of said surveyor to properly locate said certificates, and of the loss consequent thereon, was not brought to the knowledge of said Patton until application was made to the Commissioner of the General Land Office for patents on said Ideations and surveys, and which knowledge was Obtained after said certificates had become invalid by operation of law;</p>
<p>And whereas by reason of the acts and facts above recited and without any fault of his own, the said J. C. Patton has suffered the loss of the entire value of the said nineteen certificates for land, of three hundred and twenty acres each: Now, therefore.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be authorized and required to issue to the said J. C. Patton, or his legal heirs and representatives, nineteen alternate certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates for land, of three hundred and twenty acres each, to be located and surveyed upon any of the public domain of Texas not otherwise appropriated or reserved from location. Said location to be made in accordance with the laws now in force regulating the location of alternate certificates: Provided That if no unappropriated public domain is found upon which to locate said certificates, then and in that event the State is released from any further liability or obligation by reason of the issu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of the same, and this proviso shall be embodied in the face of each certificate issued hereunder: Provided further, No certificate shall be issued under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act until all of the old certificates mentioned in the preamble of this act are returned to the General Land Office and have been marked across their face, &#8220;Cancelled,&#8221; by the Commissioner.</p>
<p>Section 2. This law shall be in force and take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented) to the Governor for his approval on the second day of April, A. D. 1887, but was not signed by him or returned to the house in which it originated with his objections thereto within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.&#8212;J. M. Moore, Sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />retary of State.]</p>
</div4>
</div3>
<pb n="996" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">FOR RELIEF OF HEIES OF JAMES L. HOLMES.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 12.&#8212;[H. B. No. 283.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to require the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue to the heirs of James L. Holmes duplicate bounty warrant for 1920 acres of land.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the Commissioner off the General Land Office be and he is hereby required to issue to the heirs of James L. Holmes a duplicate bounty warrant for 1920 acres of land, in lieu of one issued to said Holmes in accordance with law, and which warrant was lost: Provided, The State shall not be any further responsible either in land or money on said claims.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas the near approach of the close of the present session renders it improbable that this bill will pass in the regular order of business, therefore an imperative public necessity and emergency exists requiring the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, and that this act be in force from and after its passage and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;the foregoing act was presented to the Governor for his approval on the first day of April, A. D. 1887, but was not signed by him or returned) to the house in which it originated with his objections thereto within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.&#8212;J. M. Moore, Secretary of State.]</p>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<p>THE STATE OF TEXAS. <lb/>Department of State.</p>
<p>I, J. M. Moore, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, certify that the fore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />going special laws, passed at the regular session of the Twentieth Legislature, have been carefully examined and compared with the original enrolled bills now on file in this department, and are true copies of said originals.</p>
<p>I further certify that the Twentieth Legislature convened, in the City of Austin January 11, A. D. 1887, and adjourned April 4, A. D. 1887.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof I have subscribed my name, and hereto affixed <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[Seal.]</p></body></floatingText>the seal of the State of Texas, in the City of Austin, April 14, 1887.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. M. MOORE, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="997" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="I" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>PASSED AT THE <lb/>SPECIAL SESSION OF THE TWENTIETH LEGISLATURE <lb/>CONVENED <lb/>AT THE CITY OF AUSTIN</head>
<byline>APRIL 16, 1888, AND ADJOURNED MAY 15, 1888.</byline>
<figure xml:id="fig2">
<graphic url="images/0997_001.jpg"/>
</figure>
<byline>AUSTIN 1888</byline>
<pb n="998" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="II" />
<pb n="999" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS OF TEXAS. TWENTIETH LEGISLATURE, 1888.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Amends Art. 566, Chap. 2, Title XX, Revised Statutes, as amended by the act of March 23, 1887, declaring for what purposes charters may be granted.</p>
<p>2. Emergency Clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 1.&#8212;[H. B. No. 16.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Article 566, Chapter 2, Title XX, of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, as amended by the Twentieth Legislature, approved March 23, 1887.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section. 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticle 566, of Chapter 2, Title XX, of the Revised Civil Statutes of Texas, as amended by the Twentieth Legislature, approved March 23, 1887, be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Article 566. The purposes for which private corporations may be formed are&#8212;</p>
<p>1. The support of public worship.</p>
<p>2. The support of any benevolent, charitable, educational, or missionary un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dertaking.</p>
<p>3. The support of any literary undertaking, the maintenance of a library, or the promotion of painting, music, or other fine arts.</p>
<p>4. The encouragement of agriculture and horticulture by associations for the maintenance of public fairs and exhibitions of stock and farm products.</p>
<p>5. The maintenance of a public or private cemetery.</p>
<p>6. The construction and maintenance of any species of road except a railroad and a bridge in connection therewith.</p>
<p>7. The construction and maintenance of a bridge.</p>
<p>8. The construction and maintenance of a telegraph or telephone line.</p>
<p>9. The establishment and maintenance of a ferry.</p>
<p>10. The establishment and maintenance of a line of stages.</p>
<p>11. The building and navigation of steamboats, and the carriage of persons and property thereon.</p>
<p>12. The supply of water to the public.</p>
<p>13. The manufacture and supply of gas, or of the supply or light or heat to the public by any means.</p>
<p>14. The transaction of any manufacturing or mining business.</p>
<p>15. The transaction of a printing or publishing business, and in connection therewith the sale of goods, wares, and merchandise of a stationery and blank book manufacturing business.</p>
<p>16. The establishment and maintenance of a hotel.</p>
<p>17. The erection of buildings and the accumulation and loan of funds for the Purchase of real property in cities, towns, and villages.</p>
<p>18. The transportation of goods, wares, and merchandise, or any valuable thing.</p>
<p>19. The promotion of immigration.</p>
<pb n="1000" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>20. The construction and maintenance of sewers.</p>
<p>21. The construction and maintenance of a street railway.</p>
<p>22. The erection and maintenance of market houses and market places.</p>
<p>23. The construction and maintenance of canals for the purposes of irrigation, navigation, or manufacture.</p>
<p>24. The purchase and sale of goods, wares, and merchandise, and agricultural and farm products. The number of persons incorporating for such purposes shall in no instance be less than ten, nor shall any person hold or own more than five hundred dollars of such stock; and any person owning or holding more than five hundred dollars of such stock shall be liable for all the debts of such corporation.</p>
<p>25. The construction of harbors and canals on the coast of the Gulf of Mexico.</p>
<p>26. The growing, purchasing, and selling seeds, plants, trees, etc., for agricul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tural, horticultural, and ornamental purposes.</p>
<p>27. The construction and maintenance of mills and gins.</p>
<p>28. The accumulation and loan of money; but this subdivision shall not permit incorporations with banking or discounting privileges.</p>
<p>29. The construction and maintenance of stock yards and pens.</p>
<p>30. The construction and maintenance of establishments for slaughtering, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />frigerating, canning, curing, and packing meat.</p>
<p>31. The construction and maintenance of establishments for the preserving and canning of fruits, vegetables, and fish.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas the present incorporation act restricts the amount of capital stock in the formation of corporation and co-operative associations to be organized under clause 24 of the first section of the act hereby amended to an extent injuri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ous to public interest; and whereas it is of great public importance and necessity that corporations and co-operative associations, which tend to the rapid develop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the State with greater capital stock than is now permitted by law, may be immediately organized: wherefore an emergency and an imperative public ne<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessity exist, demanding that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on. three separate days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 81 yeas, no nays; and passed the Senate by a vote of 23 yeas, 5 nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 30, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">APPEALS AND WRITS OF ERROR.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Amends Article 1034, Revised Stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />utes, prescribing wben transcript must be filed, etc.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 2.&#8212;[S. B. No. 50.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Article 1034 of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, relating to appeals and writs of error from the District and County Courts to the Supreme Court and Court of Appeals of the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Article 1034 of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, relating to appeals and writs of error from the District and County Court to the Supreme Court and Court of Appeals of the State, be amended so as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<pb n="1001" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Article 1034. When an appeal from any final judgment of a district or county court has been taken and an appeal bond has been filed, or when an appeal has been taken in cases where no appeal bond is required, or when a citation has been served on a petition for a writ of error, it shall be the duty of the appellant or plaintiff in error to file a transcript of record with the clerk of the Supreme Court or Count of Appeals, at the place where such appeal or writ of error is returnable, on or before the first day of the term to which the same is so returnable that is had next succeeding the term when the appeal was perfected or the citation for writ of error was served, or on or before the first day in such term designated for the trial of causes from the county in which such appeal or writ of error was taken: Provided, however, That if such appeal was perfected or such citation in error was served less than twenty days before the said first day of the term next succeeding the taking thereof, or less than twenty days before the first day of the term in said term designated for the trial of causes brought from the county in which such appeal or writ of error was taken, then such transcript shall be filed at the next succeeding term thereafter in the same manner: And provided also, That where a party is unable to file such transcript in the time limited by this ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticle, from any unavoidable cause, the court shall, upon satisfactory proof thereof, permit such transcript to be filed at a later period: And provided further, That whenever any civil cause in which the State of Texas is a party has been or may be tried during a term of the District Court while the Supreme Court is in session, the power of the District Court to revise or set aside its judgment shall terminate within ten days after the rendition of any judgment therein which assumes to finally dispose of said cause, unless there has been or shall be a new trial awarded Within that period, and the jurisdiction of the Supreme Court then sitting shall immediately attach, to affirm, or reverse, or reverse and render said judgment, on the filing by either party of the transcript of the proceedings in said cause in the Supreme Court, five days&#8217; notice of the intention to file such transcript being first given to the adverse party or to his counsel, and bond being given when the same is required.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the close of the session, and the fact that there are certain suits of great interest to the people of Texas which ought to be at once determined by the Supreme Court of the State and which can not now be heard by the said court, creates an emergency and a public necessity that the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended and that this act take effect on and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the Senate, and passed the same by a vote of 26 yeas, no nays; and passed the House by a vote of 80 yeas.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 12, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">TAXATION.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Amends Chapter 2, Title 95, Revised Statutes, adding Article 4674a, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cerning taxation of property re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moved from State.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<p>(On this subject also Chaps. 4, 10, 11, and 12.)</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 3.&#8212;[H. B. No. 37.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Title 95, Chapter 2, of the Revised Civil Statutes, by adding thereto Article 4674a.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Title 95, Chapter 2, of the Revised Civil Statutes, be amended by adding thereto Article 4674a, as follows:</p>
<pb n="1002" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Article 4674a. It shall be the duty of the assessor of taxes to list on his rolls for taxation all property temporarily removed from the State on or before the first day of January of each year, and all property removed from the State for the purpose of evading taxation prior to January first of each year shall be liable to taxation at any time after the same shall have been returned to the State be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore the assessor has completed his rolls, and all notes or bonds executed for money loaned in the State and sent out of the State before the first of January shall be subject to assessment for each of the years during which the notes and bonds re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />main unpaid: Provided, That said property so returned and brought into the State after the first day of January shall not be the proceeds of any moneys or property already assessed for said year.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas the early adjournment of this session renders it impossible to read this bill on three several days, therefore an emergency exists and an imper<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ative public necessity requires that the rule requiring bills to be read on three sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral days be suspended and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 77 yeas, 8 nays; and passed the Senate by a vote of 25 yeas, no nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 15, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">TAXATION.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Adds Article 4748a to Chapter 4, Title 95, of Revised Statutes, providing for collection of taxes on certain trust estates.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<p>(On this subject also Chaps. 3, 10, 11, and 12.)</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 4.&#8212;[S. B No. 36.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Title 95, Chapter 4, of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, by adding thereto Article 4748a.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Title 95, Chapter 4, of the Revised Civil Statutes of the State of Texas, be amended by adding thereto Article 4748a, as follows:</p>
<p>Article 4748a. In all cases where a tax payer makes an assignment of his prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty for the payment of his debts, or where his property is levied upon by creditors, by writs of attachment or otherwise, or where the estate of a decedent is or be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />comes insolvent and the taxes assessed against such person or party or against any of his estate remain unpaid in part or in whole, the amount of such unpaid taxes shall be a first lien upon all such property; Provided, That when taxes are due by an estate of a deceased person the lien herein provided for shall be subject to the allowances to widows and minors, funeral expenses, and expenses of last sick<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness; and such unpaid taxes shall be paid by the assignee, when said property has been assigned, by the sheriff out of the proceeds of sales, in case such property has been seized under attachment, or other writ, and by the administrator or other legal representative of decedents, and if said taxes shall not be paid all said prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty may be levied on by the tax collector and sold for such taxes, in whomso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever&#8217;s hands it may be found.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The near approach of the close of this session rendering it improbable that this bill can be considered on three several days creates an imperative public necessity that the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is so enacted.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 14, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<pb n="1003" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">OFFENSES RELATING TO PUBLIC BUILDINGS.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Amends Chapter 4, Article 417, of the Penal Code.</p>
<p>2. More fully defines the offenses em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />braced in said article.</p>
<p>3. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 5.&#8212;[S. B. No. 41.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Article 417, Chapter 4, Title 13, of the Penal Code of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, for purposes of preserving the new State Capitol, it becomes neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to better define the offenses set out in the aforesaid act: Therefore, Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Arti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cle 417, Chapter 4, Title 13, of the Penal Code of the State of Texas, which took effect July 24, A. D. 1879, be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Article 417. If any person shall willfully injure or deface any public building or the furniture therein in this State, he shall be fined not less than five nor more than five hundred dollars. The word deface in this act shall be held to apply to writing, carving, or scratching on the walls or plastering or furniture of said building, or staining the same with paint or any other article which will produce a discoloration of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Whereas, the preservation of the State Capitol Building, together with other public buildings, creates an imperative public necessity, and an emergency exists requiring the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house be suspended, and it is so suspended, and that this act bake effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the Senate, and passed the same by a vote of 27 yeas, no nays; and passed the House by a vote of 76 yeas, 5 nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 14, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">PUBLIC FREE SCHOOLS.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Amends Sec. 71 act of April 2, 1887, defining what counties shall be ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />empt from district system.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 6.&#8212;[S. B. No. 27.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend Section 71, of Chapter 132, of an act passed at the regular session of the Twentieth Legislature, approved April 2, A. D. 1887.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion 71, Chapter 132, [of] the laws passed at Regular Session of the Twentieth Legislature, be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 71. The following counties shall be and the same are exempted from the district system provided for in this act, to wit: Anderson, Angelina, Aransas, Bastrop, Bosque, Bowie, Brazoria, Burleson, Calhoun, Callahan, Cameron, Camp, Cass, Chambers, Concho, Delta, De Witt, Duval, El Paso, Erath, Falls, Fannin, Fay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ette, Fort Bend, Franklin, Freestone, Gillespie, Goliad, Gonzales, Gregg, Grimes, Guadalupe, Hardin, Hays, Henderson, Hidalgo, Hopkins, Jackson, Jasper, Jeffer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, Karnes, La Salle, Lee, Lampasas, Liberty Limestone, Medina, Marion, Mason, Matagorda, McMullen, Milam, Montgomery, Morris, Nacogdoches, Newton, Or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ange, Panola, Pecos, Polk, Presidio, Rains, Reeves, Red River, Refugio, Robertson, Rusk, Sabine, San Augustine, San Jacinto, Shelby, Smith, Somervell, Starr, Titus, Tom Green, Trinity, Tyler, Upshur, Van Zandt, Victoria, Waller, Washington, Webb, Wheeler, Wharton, and Zapata.</p>
<pb n="1004" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact that it is necessary that this act should go into effect within less than ninety days after the adjournment of this session of the Legislature, in order that the benefits hereof may be immediately enjoyed by the counties affected thereby, and the fact that the near approach of the close of this session of the Legislature renders it improbable that this bill could be read and considered on three several days, create an emergency, and imperative public necessity exists demanding the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the Senate, and passed the same by a vote of 27 yeas, no nays; and passed the House by a vote of 90 yeas.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 14, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">PUBLIC FREE SCHOOLS.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Requires treasurers of counties and cities to report disbursements, etc., to county commissioners.</p>
<p>2. County treasurer to transmit certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied copy of report to Superintend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent of Public Instruction.</p>
<p>3. Prescribes penalty for failing to transmit report.</p>
<p>4. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 7.&#8212;[H. B. No. 51.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to require county treasurers and treasurers of the school board of each city or town having exclusive control of its schools to make reports of the disbursements of the State and county school fund and to prescribe a penalty for failure to do so.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That it shall be the duty of the county treasurer of each county and the city treasurer or treasurer of the school board of each city or town having exclusive control of its schools to report the disbursement of the school fund, State and county, to the commissioners court of his county. Said report shall be made at the first regular term of the commissioners court after the thirty-first of August of each year or the end of the school year, and shall consist of a complete exhibit of all moneys received and paid out by him, to whom paid, upon what voucher, and what moneys if any remain in his hands.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. When such report shall have been examined and approved by the com missioners court it shall be the duty of the county treasurer to immediately trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit a copy of such report, including a statement of the status of the permanent county school fund, certified to by the county clerk, to the Superintendent of Pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic Instruction at Austin.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Any county or city treasurer failing to make and transmit said report and certified copy or either shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof shall be fined in any sum not less than fifty dollars nor more than five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The near approach of the close of this session of the Legislature and the importance of passing some law requiring treasurers of the school fund to make an exhibit of its proper disbursements creates an imperative public necessity that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended, and it is so suspended.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a four-fifths vote; and passed the Senate by a vote of 26 yeas, no nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 15, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<pb n="1005" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">PUBLIC FREE SCHOOLS.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Appropriates $254,000 for payment of outstanding school warrants.</p>
<p>2. Said appropriation declared to be a loan. Comptroller&#8217;s duties in ref<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence thereto.</p>
<p>3. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 8.&#8212;[H. B. No. 48.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the speedy payment of the outstanding warrants held by the several counties against the available public free school fund.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the Comptroller is hereby authorized to transfer the sum of two hundred and fifty-four thousand dollars from the general revenue fund to the available public free school fund, to be used in liquidation of the outstanding warrants held by the several counties against said available public free school fund for the scholastic year end<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing August 31, 1888.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Should, the amount herein set apart exceed the sum necessary to liqui<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />date the said outstanding warrants, the Comptroller shall, after paying such war rants, transfer such excess back to the general revenue fund. The sum used by the Comptroller in paying said warrants shall be considered a loan to the avail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able public free school fund, and shall be returned to the general revenue fund without interest when the available free school fund shall justify it, not later than January 1, 1895.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Whereas there is a large deficiency in the available public school fund, which creates an emergency and imperative public necessity requiring that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and said rule is therefore suspended, and this act shall be in force and effect from and after its passage.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 88 yeas, no nays; and passed the Senate by a vote of 25 yeas, no nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 11, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SINKING FUND.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. $250,000 appropriated, for payment of debts maturing in 1890 and 1891 and loaned to the school fund.</p>
<p>2. Comptroller&#8217;s duties, etc., in refer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence thereto.</p>
<p>3. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 9.&#8212;[H. B. No. 61.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create a sinking fund for the payment of bonds of the State of Texas held by individuals maturing in 1890 and 1891, and to provide for its use as a loan to the available school fund until said bonds mature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the state of Texas: That the sum of two hundred and fifty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby set aside, out, of the surplus revenue now in the State treasury, as a sinking fund for the purpose of paying off such portion of the bonded indebtedness of the State of Texas maturing in 1890 and 1891 as is held by individuals, and that said sinking fund so created be loaned to the avail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able school fund for the purpose of supplying any deficiency that may exist in said fund without interest until the maturity of said bonds in 1890 and 1891.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Comptroller of Public Accounts is hereby authorized to place to the credit of the available school fund the amount hereby set aside as a sinking fund, and it shall be his duty to see that provision is made for its return through the proper channels prior to the maturity of the State bonds for the payment of which said sinking fund is created. It shall be the duty of the Board of Education to set apart, put of the available school fund for the years 1890 and 1891, before the apportionment for said years<pb n="1006" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall be made, an amount sufficient to pay off said bonds as they fall due. And the Comptroller is directed to use said money in payment of said bonds as herein provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The fact that a deficiency now exists in the available school fund, causing serious embarrassment to school teachers throughout the State, creates an emergency and imperative public necessity for the suspension of the constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days, therefore said rule is hereby suspended, and this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 92 yeas, no nays; and passed the Senate by a vote of 24 yeas, 1 nay.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 9, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">INJUNCTIONS.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Providing for remedy by injunction for violation of penal and revenue laws.</p>
<p>2. This remedy shall be cumulative.</p>
<p>(On this subject also Chaps. 3, 4, 11, and 12.)</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 10.&#8212;[S. B. No. 29.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to confer the right of injunction upon the State to prevent breach of the revenue and penal laws.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the full right, power, and remedy of injunction may be resorted to and invoked by the State at the instance of the county or district attorney or Attorney-General, to prevent, prohibit, or restrain the violation of any revenue or penal law of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the right and remedy hereby provided shall be cumulative of other laws now in force in the State.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 12, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">TAXATION.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Authorizes suit against delinquent tax payers.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<p>(On this subject also Chaps. 3, 4, 10, and 12.)</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 11.&#8212;[H. B. No. 17.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize district and county attorneys to bring suit for the collection of taxes on unrendered personal property.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />alter it shall be the duty of the district or county attorney of the respective counties of this State, by order of the commissioners court, to institute suit in the name of the State for the recovery of all money due the State and county as taxes due and unpaid on unrendered personal property; and in all suits where judgments are obtained under this act the person owning the property on which there are taxes due the State and county shall be liable for all costs: Provided, Such suits may be brought for all taxes so due and unpaid for which such delinquent tax payer may be in arrears for and since the year 1886: And provided further. The State and county shall be exempt from liability for any costs growing out of such action: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, All suits brought under this act for the recovery of taxes due on<pb n="1007" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>personal property shall be brought against the person or persons who owned the property at the time such property should have been listed or assessed for taxa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion: Provided, That no suit shall be brought until after demand is made by the collector in person for taxes due: And provided further, That no suit shall be brought for an amount less than twenty-five dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas the early adjournment of this session renders it impossible that this bill can be read on three several days, therefore an emergency exists and an imperative public necesssity demands that the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 71 yeas, 17 nays; and passed the Senate by a vote of 12 yeas, 11 nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 17, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">TAXATION.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Reduces rate of ad valorem tax for 1888 to ten cents and thereafter at twenty cents on the hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars.</p>
<p>2. Saving clause.</p>
<p>3. Emergency clause.</p>
<p>(On this subject also Chaps. 3, 4, 10, and 11.)</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 12.&#8212;[H. B. No. 1.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the levy and collection of an ad Valorem State tax for general revenue purposes for the year 1888 of ten cents on the hundred dollars, and of an annual ad valorem State tax for general rev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />enue purposes for every year thereafter of twenty cents on the hundred dollars.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That there shall be levied and collected for the year 1888 an ad valorem tax of ten cents on the hundred dollars for general revenue purposes, and for every year thereafter an annual ad valorem tax of twenty cents on the hundred dollars, of the cash value thereof estimated in lawful currency of the United States, on all real property situated and on all movable property owned in the State on the first day of Jan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uary in each and every year, and on all property sent out of the State prior to the first day of January for the purpose of avoiding the payment of taxes thereon and afterwards returned to the State, except so much thereof as may be exempted by the Constitution and laws of the State or of the United States, which cash value shall be estimated in the manner prescribed by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Nothing in this act shall be construed as in any manner repealing or af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fecting the provisions of an act known as Chapter 111 of the Acts passed at the regular session of the Nineteenth Legislature of the State of Texas, approved March 31, 1885, except so much of section one thereof as relates to the levy and collection of an annual State ad valorem tax for general revenue purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Whereas there is now a large surplus in the State treasury to the credit of the general revenue account, which will authorize a reduction of the State general revenue tax. for the year 1888 and subsequent years, and thereby relieve the tax payers from the payment of an unnecessary tax to support the State government for the year 1888; and whereas the early adjournment of the session of the Legislature renders it impossi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble that this bill can be read on three several days; therefore, for the reasons and purposes aforesaid, an emergency and an imperative public necessity exists requiring that the rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be<pb n="1008" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>suspended, and such, rule is suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 85 yeas, 6 nays: and passed the Senate by a vote of 22 yeas, 4 nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 21, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">GEOLOGICAL AND MINERALOGICAL SURVEY.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Provides that the Commissioner of Agriculture, etc., shall cause geo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />logical and mineralogical survey to be made of State.</p>
<p>2. Defines conditions upon which as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />says and analyses are to be made, etc.</p>
<p>3. Provides for preservation of records, etc., by the Commissioner, and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ports to the Governor.</p>
<p>4. The Commissioner to prescribe rea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonable fees for assays, etc.</p>
<p>5. Prohibits under penalty the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner or his employes from be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />coming interested in mines.</p>
<p>6. $15,000 appropriated for the purposes of this act.</p>
<p>7. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 13.&#8212;[S. H. Bs. Nos. 5, 6, and 11.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Commissioner of Agriculture, Insurance, Statistics, and History to have a geological and min<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eralogical survey made of the State of Texas, and to make an appropriation therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That it shall be the duty of the Commissioner of Agriculture. Insurance, Statistics, and History to have a geological and mineralogieal survey made of the State of Texas, and for that purpose he shall employ such a number of competent persons skilled in the science of geology and mineralogy us shall be necessary to properly and expedi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tiously execute said work. The persons so employed shall be under the supervision and control of the said Commissioner, and shall receive such compensation as the Commissioner may direct, not to exceed two thousand dollars per year. The Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner shall provide all necessary chemical apparatus, books, maps, and sta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tionery to carry out the provisions of this act, and may employ such additional clerks as shall be requisite to a proper execution of this act, which clerks shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive such compensation as he may deem proper, not to exceed nine hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars each per year.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Commissioner shall cause to be made assays, analyses, or other scientific examination of all Reds or deposits of ores, coals, clays, marls, and other mineral substances situated in this State as shall be requisite to a correct knowl<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />edge of the extent and value thereof. He shall also in all proper cases upon appli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cation require like examinations, assays, or analyses to be made of deposits, mines, and lands situated in this State, and shall furnish proper certificates of the result of such examination, assay, or analysis. He shall also upon request of any person require assays or analyses to be made of any specimen of soil or mineral deposit in this State, and shall also furnish to the party requesting it a certificate thereof: Provided, That in all cases when assays or anabases are made upon re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quest of any person the party making the request shall be required by the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner to make affidavit that the specimen offered was found upon the land of the party making the request, or that said request is made at the instance or with the full knowledge and consent of the owner of the land upon which said specimen was found.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Commissioner shall preserve a record of thus department of his of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fice, and the information therein collected and preserved shall be reported to the Governor as in case of other matters relating to his office. He shall also report to the Governor before each session of succeeding Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islatures, for information of the Governor and such Legislatures, all<pb n="1009" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>money expended under this act, and how and for what purpose such money was expended. He shall also report the amounts of money received from persons, cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porations, syndicates for services rendered specifying the amount so received. He shall also preserve specimens of minerals, coals, stones, and other natural sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stances useful in agricultural, manufacturing, or the mechanical arts, and shall from time to time as far as practicable add specimens of organic remains and other objects of natural history peculiar to this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The Commissioner shall prescribe a schedule of reasonable fees to be charged and collected from all persons haying scientific examinations, assays, or chemical analyses made, and for certificates furnished under this act, which fees shall when collected be paid into the State treasury to the credit of the general revenue fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. It shall be unlawful for the Commissioner of Agriculture, Insurance, Statistics, and. History, or any person employed by him or connected with his office, to purchase all or any part of any mine or mineral lands, or be in any manner in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terested in such purchase, during the term of his office or employment. Any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son violating the provisions of this section shall be punished by fine not less than one thousand dollars, and shall be removed from his office, or employment, as the case may be.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the sum of fifteen, thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated, out of any moneys in the State treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the purpose of carrying out the provis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ions of this act: Provided, That no expense in excess of the amount hereby appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated shall be incurred under the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The great necessity for gathering and collecting useful and valuable in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formation concerning the mineral and other natural resources of the State, and the present lack of means to ascertain the same, creates an imperative public neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity, and an emergency exists requiring that the constitutional rule which requires bills to be read on three several days in each house be suspended, and said rule is so suspended, and it is enacted that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 45 yeas, 37 nays; and passed the Senate by a vote of 24 yeas, 4 nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 12, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">NORTH TEXAS INSANE ASYLUM.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Provides for construction of wings to said asylum.</p>
<p>2. Character and capacity of said wings.</p>
<p>3. To be contracted for by Governor, Comptroller, and Treasurer.</p>
<p>4. Duties of Superintendent.</p>
<p>5. $150,000 appropriated for the purposes of this bill.</p>
<p>6. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 14.&#8212;[S. B. No. 7.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to erect and furnish additions to the North Texas Insane Asylum, and to make an appropriation therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be lit enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That there shall be erected upon the grounds belonging to the North Texas Insane Asylum at Terrell, Texas, an addition to said asylum, said addition to consist of two wings to be added to the east and west ends of said asylum respectively, which said wings shall be substantial duplicates of the east and west sections of said asylum build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing.</p>
<pb n="1010" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. Said wings shall be of sufficient capacity to accommodate at least four hundred patients, and shall be provided with modern improvements for furnishing water, heat, light, ventilation, and sewerage.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Governor, Comptroller, and Treasurer shall immediately after the passage of this act contract for the construction of said wings, according to such specifications as they may adopt, with the lowest responsible bidder, who shall give a good and sufficient bond for the completion of the buildings according to contract.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the Superintendent of said asylum and a building supervisor, who shall be employed by the Governor, shall supervise the construction of the said additions to said asylum provided for in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That there shall be appropriated, out of any funds now in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, the sum of one hundred and fifty thousand dollars, or so<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />much thereof as may be necessary, for the construction of said wings and purchas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the necessary furnishings therefor: Provided, That such wings shall be of such a character that same may be completed and amply furnished and equipped for the comfort of the inmates out of the appropriation herein made.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Whereas there are now a large number of insane persons throughout the State who are in need of immediate treatment, and whose condition is rapidly growing worse from a lack of such treatment, therefore an emergency exists that this law shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the Senate, and passed the same by a vote of 28 yeas, no nays; and passed the House by a vote of 87 yeas, 4 nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 8, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">FURNISHING NEW CAPITOL.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Creates and authorizes Governor to appoint Capitol Furnishing Board.</p>
<p>2. Prescribes oath of said board and expert.</p>
<p>3. Board to appoint expert.</p>
<p>4. Provides for advertising for sealed bids, etc.</p>
<p>5. Deposit by bidders as guarantee of good faith.</p>
<p>6. Opening of bids by board, award, etc.</p>
<p>7. Bond of contractor.</p>
<p>8. Compensation of board and expert.</p>
<p>9. A majority of the board may act.</p>
<p>10. Report by the board to the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture.</p>
<p>11. $140,000 appropriated for purposes of this bill.</p>
<p>12. Provides manner of payment of vouchers of hoard.</p>
<p>13. Empowers the Governor to dismiss any or all of board.</p>
<p>14. Emergency clause.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 15.&#8212;[H. B. No. 91.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for a board to contract for, direct, and supervise the furnishing of the new Capitol building, the grading, improv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, and fencing the Capitol grounds, and to make an appropriation therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the Governor is hereby authorized to appoint three competent resident citizens of the State of Texas to be known as the Capitol Furnishing Board, whose duty it shall be to contract for, direct, and supervise the furnishing of the new capitol build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, and to contract for the fencing, grading, and improving of the new capitol grounds.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Before said board and the expert hereinafter mentioned can enter upon the discharge of their duties each one shall subscribe to the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing oath.: &#8220;I (A. B.) do solemnly swear that I wall not directly or indirectly be interested or concerned with any contractor or contractors for the furnishing of said capitol building or any portion thereof, or in the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeds or profits growing out of the same, or in any work or labor done thereon, or material furnished or any portion thereof, so help me God.&#8221;<pb n="1011" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>And any one of said board offending against the true intent and meaning of this oath shall upon indictment and conviction suffer all the pains and penalties of perjury as defined and imposed in this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Said board shall have power to appoint an expert, who shall assist them in examining the drawings, plans, and specifications for furnishing said capitol building. Said specifications shall conform to the specifications adopted by the United States government in regard to construction, material and finish. Said board shall have power to appoint a civil engineer to make an estimate of the number of cubic yards of earth to be removed.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Said board Shall advertise for sealed bids from furniture dealers, man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ufacturers, or other persons. Each bid must be accompanied by drawings, plans, and specifications of the articles to be furnished. The cost of the advertisements to be paid out of the appropriation hereinafter provided. The bids aforesaid for furnishing the capitol may be for doing all the furnishing or any part or parts thereof as in the judgment of the board may be deemed best and most economical. And said board shall also advertise for sealed bids for fencing and improving the new capitol grounds and said board shall be governed in said bids as hereinbefore and hereinafter provided. And they shall require of the person, firm, or association of persons, where a bid has been accepted for the fencing and grading and improv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the new capitol grounds, a bond in the sum of twenty-five thousand dollars, with two or more good and sufficient sureties, to be approved by them and payable to the Governor of the State of Texas, for the faithful compliance on their part with the terms of the contract in every particular.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Before any bids can be opened and considered by said board, the person, firm, or association of persons submitting drawings, plans, specifications, and bids, shall deposit with the State Treasurer a sum of money, or certified cheek approved by and payable to the State Treasurer, equal in amount to at least one-tenth of the amount so bid by such person or persons, in lawful money of the United States, for the faithful compliance on their part with the terms of the contract herein<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after provided for in this act; said sum of money or check to be returned to said person or persons who deposited the same when the Treasurer has been notified by the board that the bids of such person or persons have been rejected by the board, or the terms of the contract complied with; but should the bid of any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, firm, or association of persons, with the accompanying drawings, plans, and specifications, be accepted by said board, and such person fail to give the bond re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired by this act within thirty days after such person, firm, or association of persons have been notified that their bid has been accepted by said board, then the sum of money or certified check deposited shall be considered as liquidated damages, and be forfeited to the State and credited to the appropriation herein provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Said board shall open said bids, with the accompanying drawings, plans, and specifications, on the day fixed by the board for opening the bids, before such persons as may desire to be present, and shall award the contract to the lowest and best bidder. Said board shall have power to reject any and all bids.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Said board shall require of the person, firm, or association of persons whose bid for furniture has been accepted, a bond in the sum of fifty thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars, with two or more good and sufficient sureties, to be approved by them and made payable to the Governor of the State of Texas, for the faithful compliance on their part with the terms of the contract in every particular.</p>
<pb n="1012" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 8 The members of said board and the expert herein provided for shall each receive the sum of five dollars per day for each and every day actually engaged in said work, not to exceed ninety days, and all necessary expenses, the amounts of each to be itemized and verified by their own affidavits.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. A majority of said, board shall be sufficient to transact all business that may come before them.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Said board stall submit to the next Legislature a full and detailed ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />count of all their acts and doings in the premises.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. For the purpose of supplying furniture for the new capitol building and fencing and improving the capitol grounds, the sum of one hundred and forty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated, out of any of the funds of this State not, otherwise appropriated. Out of the amount herein appropriated for the purposes of this act one hundred thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars shall constitute the sum for furnishing the capitol, and the sum of forty thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars shall constitute the sum for fencing, grading, and improving the cap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />itol grounds.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. All moneys to be paid out under this act shall be by warrants drawn upon the Treasurer by the Comptroller of Public Accounts, who is authorized to draw the same upon the vouchers of the board approved by the Governor.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. The Governor, is hereby authorized and empowered to dismiss, at his own discretion, any one or all of said board, and appoint their successors.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. Whereas the near approach of the close of this session renders it impos<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sible that this bill can be read on three several days, and there being no law re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quiring the furnishing of the new capitol building and the fencing and improving of the capitol grounds, therefore an emergency exists and an imperative public necessity demands that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and it is so suspended, and this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 60 yeas, 24 nays: and passed the Senate by a vote of 21 yeas, 4 nays.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 17, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">FOR REMOVING DEBRIS FROM GROUNDS OF NEW CAPITOL.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. $500 appropriated for removing de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bris, etc., from grounds of new Capitol; defines how same is to be expended, etc.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 16.&#8212;[H. S. for S. C. R. No. 3.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for clearing Capitol grounds and making an appropriation therefor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas from the condition of the capitol grounds approach to the new capitol is rendered tedious and difficult; and</p>
<p>Whereas it is of the utmost importance that said approaches be cleared and the debris and rubbish now upon the capitol grounds be removed before the dedication of said capitol: Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the Superintendent of Public Buildings and Grounds be and is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized and required to contract for the removal of said rubbish and debris<pb n="1013" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and the clearing of said approaches in such manner as to him may be deemed best, and the sum of five hundred dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated out of any moneys now in the State treasury not otherwise appropriated, to carry out the objects of this act, which may be drawn from the treasury upon the warrant of said Superintendent: Provided, That under author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity granted the Superintendent under this act he shall not have the power to bind the State for the payment of a greater amount of money than is hereby appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas the near near approach of the time set for the dedication of the new capitol, and the importance of having the approaches cleared to the Cap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />itol, create an imperative public necessity which requires that the constitutional rule that bills be read on three several days be suspended and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 71 yeas, 14 nays; and passed the Senate by a vote of 23 yeas, 2 nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 1, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">RECEPTION OF NEW STATE CAPITOL.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. Creates Capitol Board and defines duties of in respect to receiving new Capitol.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 17.&#8212;[S. for S. H. B. No. 38.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the reception of the new State Capitol Building.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas there is no provision in the law which clearly defines how or in what manner the new State Capitol Building shall be received: Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor, Treasurer, Comptroller and Commissioner of the General Land Office, are hereby constituted a board for the purpose of receiving or ejecting the new State Capitol Building, in whole or in part, with full power to act in the premises, saving and reserving to the State all rights under the contract and the securities given for the performance thereof: Provided, That the contractor shall in no wise be held responsible for any injury done to said building by the public after the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ception of the said building or any part thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the near completion of this important work requires immediate action not heretofore provided for by law, and creates an imperative public neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity and an emergency demanding that the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days be suspended, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 83 yeas, 1 nay: and passed the Senate by a vote of 22 yeas, 5 nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 2, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<pb n="1014" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">APPROPRIATION FOR MILEAGE AND PER DIEM PAY OF OFFICERS, MEMBERS, AND EMPLOYES.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. $40,000 appropriated for per diem pay of members, etc., of the Special Session Twentieth Legislature.</p>
<p>2. Manner of auditing claims against this appropriation.</p>
<p>3. Unexpended balances heretofore ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated for per diem pay of Legislatures hereby appropriated for purposes of this act.</p>
<p>4. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 18.&#8212;[H. B. No. 2.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation for mileage and per diem pay of members and per diem pay of officers and employes of the First Called Session of the Twentieth Legislature of Texas, convened April 16, A. D. 1888, by proclamation of the Governor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the sum of forty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated, out of any moneys in the treasury not otherwise ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated, for the payment of mileage and per diem pay of the members and the payment of the per diem pay of the officers and employes of the First Called Ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of the Twentieth Legislature of Texas, convened April 16, A. D. 1888, by proclamation of the Governor.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the certificate of the Secretary of the Senate, approved by the President thereof, or the certificate of the Chief Clerk of the House, approved by the Speaker thereof, shall be sufficient evidence to the Comptroller upon which he shall audit the claims and issue his warrants upon the Treasurer for the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective amounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 3, That the balance of the moneys remaining in the treasury heretofore appropriated for the per diem pay and mileage of the members and the per diem pay of the officers and. employes of any preceding session of the Legislature of the State of Texas, be and the same is hereby reappropriated for the purposes specified in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. And whereas the Called Session of the Twentieth Legislature, for the payment of the members and officers of which this law is enacted, is now in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion, and public policy requires this payment, therefore an imperative public ne<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessity exists that the rule requiring this bill to be head on three several days be suspended, and it is so enacted, and that this [act] take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 89 yeas, no nays; and passed the Senate by a vote of 28 yeas, no nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 20, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">APPROPRIATION TO DEFRAY CONTINGENT EXPENSES.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. $10,000 to defray contingent expenses of Special Session Twentieth Leg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />islature.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 19.&#8212;[H. B. No. 15.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to defray the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tingent expenses on the First Galled Session of the Twentieth Legislature, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vened April 16, A. D. 1888, by proclamation of the Governor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas it is of sufficient importance that the contingent expenses of the extra session of the Twentieth Legislature be promptly paid, in order that the material furnished and labor performed may be procured at cash prices: Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the sum of ten thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessaary. is<pb n="1015" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>hereby appropriated, out of any moneys in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, to pay the contingent expenses of me First Called Session of the Twentieth Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature, convened April 16, 1888, by proclamation of the Governor, and that the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proval by the Chairman of the Committee on Contingent Expenses of either house, countersigned by the President of the Senate, or Speaker of the House of Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives, as the case may be, shall be sufficient authority to authorize the Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller to issue his warrant on the State Treasurer for the payment of any ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />count against said fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the public importance of the objects herein contemplated, creates an imperative public necessity and emergency fully authorizing the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three several days in each house, and said rule is hereby suspended, and that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 90 yeas, no nays; and passed the Senate by a vote of 28 yeas, no nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>April 26, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">GENERAL APPROPRIATION.</head>
<p>Sec.</p>
<p>1. General appropriation, for current expenses, etc., of State govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment.</p>
<p>2. Emergency clause.</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAP. 20.&#8212;[S. H. Bs. Nos. 7, 18, 30, 47, 50, 53, and S. S. Bs. 11, 20.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making additional appropriations for the support of the State government for the period of time beginning March 1, 1888, and ending February 28, 1889, and to pay certain obligations of the State incurred prior to March 1, 1887.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing sums of money, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated, out of any money in the treasury not otherwise ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated, for the support of the State government for the period of time begin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ning March 1, 1888, and ending February 28, 1889, and to pay certain obligations of the State incurred prior to March 1, 1887:</p>
<p>For constructing additional buildings at the State Lunatic Asylum at Austin, for repairs, etc., as follows:</p>
<p>Residence for Superintendent and other officers and employes..... $10,000 00</p>
<p>Laundry, etc....................................................... 5,700 00</p>
<p>Literature, music, etc............................................... 500 00</p>
<p>Repair of walls.................................................... 1,000 00</p>
<p>Salary of three attendants and one night watchman at $20 each per month............................................................ 800 00</p>
<p>Pigeon-holes for Court of Appeal at Galveston....................... $300 00</p>
<p>Books, furniture, etc., Court of Appeals............................. 600 00</p>
<div5 type="section">
<head type="main">For the Blind Asylum.</head>
<p>For the erection, enlarging, and repairing of buildings, and equipping the same; building, repairing, and equipping a<pb n="1016" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>steam laundry; gas pipes and fixtures; steam heating apparatus and fixtures; and steam engine and boiler; the sum of..... $18,500 00</p>
</div5>
<div5 type="section">
<head type="main">For the Agricultural and Mechanical College.</head>
<p>To erect a dormitory and assembly hall.............................. $20,000 00</p>
<p>Furniture for same.............................. 2,000 00</p>
<p>Repair of college buildings and professors&#8217; residence.............................. 9,000 00</p>
<p>To provide a water supply.............................. 2,000 00</p>
<p>For fencing college land and repairing of present fences.............................. 2,500 00</p>
<p>To erect barn.............................. 1,000 00</p>
<p>Equipping of mechanical department.............................. 1,500 00</p>
<p>Equipment of civil engineering department.............................. 1,000 00</p>
<p>Equipment of drawing department.............................. 500 00</p>
<p>Equipment of veterinary science department.............................. 1,500 00</p>
<p>Work stock and farm implements.............................. 500 00</p>
<p>For furnishing, improving, and making certain additions to the State Reformatory, the sum of.............................. $25,890 00</p>
<p>Provided, That not more than $5,700 of said sum shall be expended in the erection of additional buildings.</p>
</div5>
<div5 type="section">
<head type="main">For the Deaf and Dumb Asylum.</head>
<p>To erect addition to present building, or to purchase ground and erect new building and furnish same, as may be determined by trustees. $18,000 00</p>
<p>For buildings, repairs, and improvements, and to provide a water supply, at Prairie View Normal School.............................. $25,000 00</p>
<p>For quarantine service.............................. $36,500 00</p>
<p>For the purchase of pictures and statuary of men prominent in his<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tory, which sum, or so much thereof as may be necessary, shall be expended) by the Governor, Secretary of State, and Commissioner of Agriculture, Insurance, Statistics, and History, upon whose order the Comptroller shall issue Ms warrants for such sums as may be so expended.............................. $10,000 00</p>
</div5>
<div5 type="section">
<head type="main">State Department.</head>
<p>For indexing, labelling, arranging, and binding books, rolls, docu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments, printed and unprinted, and all other papers in State De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partment in the new capitol.............................. $2,500 00</p>
<p>For extra clerk hire.............................. 200 00</p>
<p>For rent of rooms and storage of books.............................. 75 00</p>
<p>For the erection of buildings and other improvements on the grounds of the State Orphan Asylum at Corsicana, Texas, to be ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended under the direction of the Board of Managers of said asylum, and to be disbursed upon vouchers approved by said board and by the Governor.............................. $15,000 00</p>
<p>and the available fund to the credit of said asylum now in the treasury.</p>
<pb n="1017" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>For moving furniture, books, papers, etc., into the new capitol.............................. $500 00</p>
<p>To pay actual expenses of Commissioner of Agriculture, Insurance, Statistics, and History, in enforcing insurance laws.............................. $400 00</p>
<p>To purchase one type-writer.............................. 85 00</p>
<p>To pay to Nelson M. Darden, for service as night watchman on the third floor of the temporary capitol, for the month of March, 1887, the sum of.............................. $65 00</p>
<p>To pay certain deficiencies, as follows: Witness fees prior to march 1, 1887.............................. $5,581 00</p>
<p>Publishing constitutional amendments.............................. 7,246 00</p>
<p>Henry Hollingsworth.............................. 2 61</p>
<p>Wayland &#38; Crizer.............................. 4 95</p>
<p>George Assman.............................. 4 10</p>
<p>J. A. Nagle.............................. 7 06</p>
<p>W. N. Lowe et als.............................. 59 35</p>
<p>E. S. Cumeley.............................. 26 70</p>
<p>D. D. Atchison.............................. 78 15</p>
<p>Covert &#38; McCarty.............................. 216 50</p>
<p>Telephone Company.............................. 150 00</p>
<p>To pay for the survey and marking of the boundary line of the real property belonging to the State and situated in the city of Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin.............................. $150 00</p>
<p>To pay W. B. Houston, district attorney of the 39th judicial district, for services in suit of The State v. E. P. Davis et als.............................. 500 00</p>
<p>To pay Geo. E. Miller, district attorney of the 30th judicial district, for services in suit of The State v. The Stone Cattle and Pasture Company.............................. 250 00</p>
<p>For flag and flag-staff to be placed on the new capitol, to be ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended by the Superintendent of Public Buildings and Grounds... 100 00</p>
<p>For fuel, lights, and water for capitol building.............................. 10,000 00</p>
<p>For employing such service as may be necessary for preservation, care, and protection of the eapitol building and grounds, to be expended by the Superintendent of Public Buildings and Grounds. 10,000 00</p>
<p>To pay cost in the case of Ex parte Robert Stockton, in U. S. Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Court for Eastern District of Texas.............................. 178 75</p>
<p>Far compensation of clerks of county courts of various counties for recording lists of school lands placed by the Commissioner of the General Land Office upon the market for sale, to be at the rate of ten cents per hundred words, to be paid out Of school fund.... 2,500 00</p>
<p>For payment of amounts due by the State to officers of courts tin escheat cases.............................. 300 00</p>
<p>To purchase of library for consultation room for the Supreme Court.. 2,500 00</p>
<p>As a loan to the available fund of the University of Texas, to be placed to the credit of said fund out of the indemnity fund now in the State treasury, and to be repaid to the State out of the revenues of the University on or before January 1, 1910, without interest.............................. 125,000 00<pb n="1018" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Of which the sum of $50,000 is hereby appropriated and set apart to be used in the construction of buildings for the Medical Branch of the University of Texas at the city of Galveston: Provided, That the said city of Galveston shall donate to the University of Texas Block No. 668 in said city to be used for the Medical Branch of said institution: And provided further, That the executors of the estate of John Sealy, deceased, shall agree to construct on said block, at a cost of not less than $50,000, a medical hospital, which, when completed, is to be donated to the Medical Branch of the University of Texas, and to be under the control of the Board of Regents of said University: Provided further, That this loan shall be in full payment and satisfaction of all claims of the University of Texas against the State of Texas for moneys drawn from the University fund by said State.</p>
<p>To pay expenses of State agent while at Washington, D. C., in es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablishing the balance of State frontier indemnity claim due by the general government, to be paid upon the warrant of the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor.............................. $1,000 00</p>
<p>For repairs of the General Land Office building.............................. 3,000 00</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The fact of the near approach of the close of the session and the great press of business rendering tit improbable that this bill will be reached in its regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lar order creates an emergency and an imperative public necessity which justifies the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring bills to be read on three sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral days, and that this act should go into effect from and after its passage, and it is so enacted.</p>
<p>[Note.&#8212;The foregoing act originated in the House, and passed the same by a vote of 69 yeas, 24 nays; and passed the Senate by a vote of 24 yeas, no nays.]</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 17, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div5>
</div4>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="1019" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">RESOLUTION.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION ADDRESSED TO SENATORS AND REPRE<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />SENTATIVES IN CONGRESS FOR RETENTION OF TROOPS IN TEXAS.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">[S. C. R. No. 5.]</head>
<opener>
<salute>Senate Concurrent Resolution requesting our Senators and Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives in Congress to use their utmost efforts with the administration to secure the retention of the present number of regiments and especially the pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent cavalry force now on duty in the Department of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas under the late orders of the War Department the stations of a num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of regiments in the United States Army have been changed, and in the new movements contemplated the Eighth Regiment of Cavalry, which has been on duty in this department for a number of years guarding our long frontier, is to be sent to Dakota, and no new regiment has been ordered to take its place, the force in this State being thus reduced to this extent; land whereas the troops now serving in the department, including said regiment, are absolutely essential to the protection of life and property along the exposed frontier of the State, and two regiments of cavalry especially are absolutely required to maintain the long line of defense from the mouth of the Rio Grande to El Paso and to guard effectually the western borders of the State; and whereas the reduction of the present force would be most unfortunate for the interest of our people and would impair its efficiency for the defense of our border and endanger the security of the life and property of our citizens: Therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators and Representatives in Congress be requested to exhaust every means in their power to induce the administration to abandon the idea of any such diminution of the military strength in this department as is said to be contemplated, and to secure the retention of the present establishment.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>May 14, 1888</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div4>
<div4 type="addendum">
<pb n="1020" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" />
<p>STATE OF TEXAS, <lb/>D<smcap>EPARTMENT OF</smcap> S<smcap>TATE</smcap>.</p>
<p>I, J. M. Moore, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, certify that the fore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />going laws and concurrent resolution, passed at the Special Session of the Twen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tieth Legislature, have been carefully examined and compared with the original enrolled bills now on file in this department, and that the same are true copies of said originals.</p>
<p>I further certify that the Twentieth Legislature convened in Special Session, in pursuance to the proclamation of the Governor of Texas, in the City of Austin April 16, A. D. 1888, and adjourned May 15, A. D. 1888.</p>
<p>In testimony whereof I have subscribed, my name and affixed <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[SEAL.]</p></body></floatingText>the seal of the State of Texas. Done in the city of Austin, May 26, A. D. 1888.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. M. MOORE, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div4>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="1021" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">APPENDIX.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">PROCLAMATION</head>
<opener>
<salute>By the Governor of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>To all to whom these presents shall come:</p>
<p>Whereas there is now in the State Treasury a larger amount of money than is required for the economical administration of the government; and the near com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pletion of the State Capitol building requires that it should be inspected by rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives of the people with a view to its acceptance, or rejection, and if ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cepted, the proper provisions made for its occupancy; and there is an imperative public necessity for the amendment of the tax laws, so that if found practicable the burden of taxation may be lightened from the people; and as the State is indebted for services of school teachers of the public schools, to an extent which greatly impairs their usefulness, and which requires such amendment of the school law as may most conduce to the effectiveness of our system of public education; and Congress has now before it an act looking to the permanent settlement of the disputed claim of our State to Greer County, which, if it becomes a law, will necessitate prompt legislative action; and these several matters are of such grave importance and general interest as to create an emergency necessitating the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vening of the Twentieth Legislature in special session:</p>
<p>Now, therefore, I, L. S. Ross, Governor of Texas, do hereto issue this my proc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lamation convening the Twentieth Legislature to meet in their respective halls, in the City of Austin, on Monday the sixteenth day of April, A. D. 1888, in special session, and do hereby designate the following as subjects of legislation, to wit:</p>
<p>1. To provide for the proper distribution of the surplus moneys now in the treasury, by necessary appropriations.</p>
<p>2. To inspect and make such, provision for furnishing and preserving the new capitol as may be deemed proper; for putting the capitol grounds in condition, and to determine what disposition shall be made of other State property at the seat of government.</p>
<p>3. To make such, changes in the laws relating to taxation and revenue as may seem most consonant with the interests of the people, with the view of a more uniform and just assessment and certain collection; and a consideration of the advisability of reducing the present tax rate.</p>
<p>4. To make such, alteration in the present law regarding the public education of the youth of our State as may be found necessary, and appropriations to pay any indebtedness that may have accrued by reason thereof; to make appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions for our various charitable institutions requisite to their more extended use<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fulness and betterment; and for a geological survey of the State, if demanded by general public interest.</p>
<p>5. To make such, charges in subdivision 24, of Article 566, Rievised Statutes, as amended by Act of March 23, A. D. 1887, as may be deemed wise and expedient to meet the increased demands of the agricultural interest of the State.</p>
<p>6. To make such provision as may be necessary for co-operation with<pb n="1022" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Appendix.</fw>the United States government in the settlement of the boundary of that portion of the State embracing Greer County.</p>
<p>Done at the Executive Office in the City of Austin, this the 31st day of March, A. D. 1888, and in the year of our independence the fifty-third.</p>
<closer>
<signed>L. S. ROSS, <lb/>Governor of Texas.</signed>
<signed>By the Governor: <lb/>J. M. MOORE, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">EXECUTIVE MESSAGE.</head>
<p>Executive Office, Austin, May 8, 1888.</p>
<p>To the Honorable Senate and House of Representatives:</p>
<p>Gentlemen&#8212;I have the honor to inform you that Attorney-General Hogg has called my attention to the fact that the State has now pending several important suits, involving interests of great magnitude to the general public, which are likely to suffer serious loss by reason of the great delay incident to the regular procedure of the courts now provided; and as it is further stated that those rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resenting the interests adverse to the State have signified their desire for a speedy determination of these litigated questions, I respectfully suggest for your con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sideration the propriety of amending Article 1034, Revised Civil Statutes, relating to practice in the courts, if, in your judgment, the same may be done at this stage of your proceedings without jeopardizing the successful completion of other legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lation now being considered by your honorable bodies.</p>
<closer>
<signed>L. S. ROSS, <lb/>Governor of Texas.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="1023" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX.</head>
<p>Acts Amendedl&#8212;Act of April 2, 1887, relating to. public free schools.......... 5</p>
<p>Act of March 23, 1887, amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />atory of Art. 566, Chap. 2, Title XX, Revised Civil Stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><sub>utes.......... </sub>1</p>
<p>Agricultural and Mechanical Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege&#8212;Appropriation for.......... 18</p>
<p>Amendments&#8212;Revised Civil Stat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />utes, Art. 566, Title XX.. 1</p>
<p>Art. 1034, Title XXVI.......... 2</p>
<p>Adds Art. 4674a.......... 3</p>
<p>Adds Art. 4748a.......... 4 Penal Code, Art. 417.......... 5</p>
<p>Act of March 23, 1887, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lating to private corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions.......... 1</p>
<p>Act of April 2, 1887, relating to public free schools.......... 5</p>
<p>Anderson County-exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Angelina County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Appeals and Write of Error&#8212;From District and County Courts to Supreme Court and Court of Appeals.......... 3</p>
<p>Appeals, Count of&#8212;Appropriation for.......... 17</p>
<p>Appropriations&#8212;General appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion act.......... 17</p>
<p>For State geological survey, etc. 11</p>
<p>For furnishing new capitol.... 12</p>
<p>For North Texas Insane Asy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lum.......... 11</p>
<p>To pay outstanding school warrants.......... 7</p>
<p>To pay State indebtedness ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turing in 1890 and 1891.......... 7</p>
<p>For removal of debris from Cap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />itol grounds.......... 14</p>
<p>For mileage and per diem of members, etc., of Legislature 16</p>
<p>For contingent expenses Special Session Twentieth Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture.......... 16</p>
<p>Assays of minerals, etc.......... . 10</p>
<p>Assignments&#8212;For collection of taxes on property assigned.. 4</p>
<p>Asylum, Blind&#8212;Appropriation for. 17</p>
<p>Asylum, Deaf land Dumb&#8212;Appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation for.......... 18</p>
<p>Asylum North Texas Insane&#8212;Ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriation for additions thereto, etc.......... . 11</p>
<p>Asylum, State Lunatic at Austin&#8212;Appropriation for.......... 17</p>
<p>Asylum, State Orphan at Corsicana &#8212;Appropriation for.......... 18</p>
<p>Attorneys, District and County&#8212; Suits by, for taxes, etc.......... . 8</p>
<p>Attachments&#8212;Collection of taxes on property seized under... 4</p>
<p>Aransas County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Bastrop County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Blind Asylum&#8212;Appropriation for.. 17</p>
<p>Boards&#8212;Capitol Board.......... 15</p>
<p>Capitol Furnishing Board.......... 12</p>
<p>Bosque County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Bowie County&#8212;exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Brazoria County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Burleson County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Callahan County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Calhoun County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Cameron County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5 Camp County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5 Cass County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Capitol&#8212;Capitol Board created, du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties, etc.......... . 15</p>
<p>Furnishing Board created, du<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of.......... 12</p>
<pb n="1024" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Capitol&#8212;Grounds, removal of debris from, appropriation.......... 14</p>
<p>Moving into new, appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for.......... 19</p>
<p>New, reception of by board... 15</p>
<p>Furnishing, fencing grounds, etc., appropriation for.......... 14</p>
<p>Preservation of, etc., appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ation for.......... 19</p>
<p>Contracts for furnishing, etc.. 13</p>
<p>Certificate.&#8212;Authentication of laws 22</p>
<p>Chambers County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>City Treasurers&#8212;Reports by, of dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bursemeuts of school funds.. 6</p>
<p>Clerks, County&#8212;hiatus of perma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nent school fund to be Cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tified by.......... 6</p>
<p>Compensation for recording lists of school lands, appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation for.......... 19</p>
<p>Collection of Taxes&#8212;On trust es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tates.......... 4</p>
<p>Reduced rate of, year 1868 and thereafter.......... 9</p>
<p>Commissioners Courts&#8212;Duties as to reports of disbursements of school funds.......... 5</p>
<p>Commissioner of Agriculture, Insur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance, Statistics, etc.&#8212;Duties in respect to geological sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vey of State, etc.......... . 10</p>
<p>Commissioner of General Land Of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fice&#8212;Member of Capitol Board.......... 15</p>
<p>Comptroller of Public Accounts&#8212; Duties of with respect to sinking fund.......... 7</p>
<p>Member Capital Board.......... 15</p>
<p>With Governor and Treasurer to contract for improvements to North Texas Asylum.......... 12</p>
<p>Concurrent Resolution&#8212;Urging re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tention of U. S. troops in Texas.......... 21</p>
<p>Concho County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Contingent Expenses&#8212;Special ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion, appropriation for.......... 16</p>
<p>Corporations&#8212;Private, purposes for which may be formed.......... 1</p>
<p>Costs&#8212;Appropriation to pay certain 19</p>
<p>Counties&#8212;Certain exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>County Treasurers&#8212;Reports by, of disbursements of school funds 6</p>
<p>Court of Appeals&#8212;Appropriations for.......... 17</p>
<p>Deaf and Dumb Asylum&#8212;Appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for.......... 18</p>
<p>Debts of State Maturing in 1890 and 1891&#8212;Appropriation for payment of.......... 7</p>
<p>Decedents, Estates of Collection of taxes on.......... 4</p>
<p>Deficiencies&#8212;Appropriation for pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of.......... 17</p>
<p>Delta County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Department of State&#8212;Appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for.......... 18</p>
<p>De Witt County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>District and County Attorneys&#8212; Duties of, in respect to suits for taxes, etc.......... . 8</p>
<p>Dural County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>El Paso County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Erath County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Error&#8212;Writs of and appeals.......... 2</p>
<p>Escheated Cases&#8212;Appropriation for payment of costs in.......... 19</p>
<p>Estates of Decedents&#8212;Collection of taxes on.......... 4</p>
<p>Expert&#8212;For appointment of by Capitol Furnishing Board... 13</p>
<p>Falls County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Fannin County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Fayette County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Fencing&#8212;Capitol grounds.......... 12</p>
<p>Flag&#8212;Appropriation to buy.......... 19</p>
<p>Fort Bend County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Franklin County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Freestone County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Frontier Claims&#8212;Appropriation to pay State agent.......... 20</p>
<p>Fuel, Lights, etc.&#8212;Appropriation for.......... 19</p>
<p>Furnishing Capitol&#8212;Appropriation for, etc.......... . 12</p>
<p>Furniture, Public&#8212;Offense for in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jury.......... 5</p>
<p>General Land Office&#8212;Appropriation, for repairs of.......... 21</p>
<p>Geological and Minenaloigical Sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vey&#8212;Commissioner Agricul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture to have made.......... 10</p>
<p>Gillespie County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Goliad County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<pb n="1025" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Gonzales County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Governor&#8212;Member Capitol Board.. 15</p>
<p>To appoint a Capitol Furnish<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing Board.......... 12</p>
<p>To appoint a building supervi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sor North Texas Insane Asy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lum.......... 11</p>
<p>With Treasurer and Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller to contract for im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provements on said asylum.. 11</p>
<p>Gregg County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Grimes County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Guadalupe County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Hardin County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Hays County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Hidalgo County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Hopkins County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Houston, W. B.&#8212;Appropriation to pay for services of.......... 19</p>
<p>Injunction&#8212;Remedy by, for viola<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion revenue laws.......... 8</p>
<p>Insane Asylum, North Texas&#8212;Ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ditions to, etc.......... . 11</p>
<p>Jackson County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Jasper County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Jefferson County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Karnes County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Lampasas County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>La Salle County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Lee County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Legislature&#8212;Appropriation to pay mileage and per diem of members, etc.......... . 16</p>
<p>Contingent expenses of special session, appropriation for.... 16</p>
<p>Library, Supreme Court&#8212;Appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ation for.......... 19</p>
<p>Liberty County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Lien&#8212;First on certain trust es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tates favor of State for taxes 4</p>
<p>Lights, Fuel, etc.&#8212;Appropriation for.......... 19</p>
<p>Limestone County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Listing Property for Taxes&#8212;Tem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porarily removed from State 3</p>
<p>Loan&#8212;To available school fund... 7</p>
<p>Marion County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Mason County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Matagorda County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>McMullen County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Medical Branch State University&#8212; Appropriation for.......... 20</p>
<p>Medina County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Mileage and Per Diem&#8212;Pay of members, etc., of the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature.......... 16</p>
<p>Milam County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Miller, Geo. E.&#8212;Appropriation to pay for services of.......... 19</p>
<p>Mineralogical Survey&#8212;Provided for 10</p>
<p>Montgomery County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Morris County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Nacogdoches County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Newton County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Normal School, Prairie View&#8212;Ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriation for.......... 18</p>
<p>North Texas Insane Asylum&#8212;Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cerning.......... 11</p>
<p>Offenses&#8212;Relating to public build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings, etc.......... . 5</p>
<p>Orange County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Panola County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Fecos County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Penal Code&#8212;Amendment of Art. 417.......... 5</p>
<p>Penal Laws&#8212;Violation of, remedy by injunction.......... 8</p>
<p>Pictures, etc.&#8212;Appropriation for purchase of.......... 18</p>
<p>Polk County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Prairie View Normal School&#8212;Ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriation for.......... 18</p>
<p>Presidio County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Private Corporations&#8212;For what purposes may be created.... 1</p>
<pb n="1026" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Property Removed Prom State&#8212;When listed for taxes.......... 3</p>
<p>Public Buildings, etc.&#8212;Offenses re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lating to.......... 5</p>
<p>Public Free Schools&#8212;Laws relating to.......... 5, 6, 7</p>
<p>Quarantine&#8212;Appropriation for.... 18</p>
<p>Rains County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Reduction of Taxation&#8212;Provided for.......... 4</p>
<p>Red River County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Reeves County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Reformatory, State&#8212;Appropriation for.......... 18</p>
<p>Refugio County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Revenue Laws&#8212;Remedy by injunc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for violation of.......... 8</p>
<p>Revised Civil Statutes&#8212;Amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of Art. 566.......... 1</p>
<p>Art. 1034.......... 2</p>
<p>Adds Art. 4674a.......... 3</p>
<p>Adds Art. 4748a.......... 4</p>
<p>Resolution&#8212;Concurrent.......... 21</p>
<p>Robertson County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Sabine County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>San Augustine County&#8212;Exempt from district school system.. 5</p>
<p>San Jacinto County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>School District System&#8212;Counties exempt therefrom.......... 5</p>
<p>School Warrants&#8212;Payment of outstanding.......... 7</p>
<p>Schools, Public Free&#8212;Laws relating to.......... 5, 6, 7, 8</p>
<p>Senators and Representatives in Congress&#8212;Resolution ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dressed to.......... 21</p>
<p>Shelby County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Sinking Fund&#8212;Provided for.......... 7</p>
<p>Smith County&#8212;Exempt, from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Somervell County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Starr County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>State Agent, Frontier Claims&#8212;Ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriation for.......... 21</p>
<p>State Lunatic Asylum at Austin&#8212; Appropriation for.......... 17</p>
<p>State Orphan Asylum at Corsicana &#8212;Appropriation for.......... 18</p>
<p>State Reformatory&#8212;Appropriation for.......... 18</p>
<p>Suits&#8212;For collection of taxes.......... 8</p>
<p>Superintendent of Public Instruc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion&#8212;Reports to.......... 6</p>
<p>Supreme Court&#8212;Appropriation for library.......... 17</p>
<p>Survey&#8212;Or real property in City of Austin belonging to State, appropriation for.......... 19</p>
<p>Geological, provided for.......... 10</p>
<p>Taxation&#8212;Laws in relation thereto.......... 3, 4, 8, 9</p>
<p>Titus County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Tom Green County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Treasurer, State&#8212;With the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor and Comptroller, to contract for improvements North Texas Insane Asylum. 11</p>
<p>Member of Capitol Board.......... 15</p>
<p>Treasurers, City and County&#8212;To report to Superintendent of Public Instruction.......... 6</p>
<p>Trinity County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Trust Estates&#8212;Collection of taxes on.......... 4</p>
<p>Tyler County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>University of Texas&#8212;Appropriation for.......... 19</p>
<p>Upsher County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Van Zandt County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Victoria County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Waller County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Warrants, School &#8212; Appropriation for payment of.......... 7</p>
<p>Washington County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Webb County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Wharton County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Wheeler County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
<p>Writs&#8212;Of error and appeals.......... 2</p>
<p>Zapata County&#8212;Exempt from school district system.......... 5</p>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
