<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<div1 type="article">
<pb n="437" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="131" />
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 1. JOINT RESOLUTION</head>
<opener>
<salute>Making an appropriation of four thousand five hundred dollars, to be used in repairing and furnishing the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor&#8217;s Mansion.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the sum of four thousand five hundred dollars, or so much thereof, as may be necessary, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated, is hereby appropriated, to be expended under the control and direction of the Governor, for repairing and furnishing the Governor&#8217;s mansion and grounds.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whereas the Governor&#8217;s mansion is now in a condition not fitted for comfortable occupancy, which creates an imperative public ne<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessity and emergency which requires that the constitutional rule be sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended, and this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 2, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect from passage.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 2. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Amending Sections 4 and 6, of Article 7 of the Constitution of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That sections 4 and 6 Article 7, of the Constitution of the State of Texas, be amended so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The lands herein set apart to the Public Free School fund, shall be sold under such regulations, at such times, and on such terms as may be prescribed by law; and the Legislature shall not have power to grant any relief to purchasers thereof. The Comptroller shall invest the proceeds of such sales, and of those heretofore made, as may be directed by the Board of Education herein provided for, in the bonds of the United States, the State of Texas, or counties in said State, or in such other securities, and under such restrictions as may be prescribed by law; and the State shall be responsible for all investments.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. All lands heretofore, or hereafter granted to the several coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of this State for educational purposes, are of right the property of said counties respectively, to which they were granted, and title thereto<pb n="438" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="132" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>is vested in said counties, and no adverse possession or limitation shall ever be available against the title of any county. Each county may sell or dispose of its lands in whole or in part, in manner to be provided by the commissioner&#8217;s court of the county. Actual settlers residing on said lands, shall be protected in the prior right of purchasing the same to the extent of their settlement, not to exceed one hundred and sixty acres, at the price fixed by said court, which price shall not include the value of existing improvements made thereon by such settlers. Said lands, and the proceeds thereof, when sold, shall be held by said counties alone as a trust for the benefit of public schools therein; said proceeds to be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vested in bonds of the United States, the State of Texas, or counties in said State, or in such other securities, and under such restrictions as may be prescribed by law; and the counties shall be responsible for all invest<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments; the interest thereon, and other revenue, except the principal shall be available fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor of this State shall issue his proclamation ordering an election to be held on the second Tuesday in August A. D. 1883, at which time the foregoing amendments shall be submitted for adoption, to the qualified electors of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That those voting for the adoption of said amendment to Section 4, shall have written or printed on their ballots the words: &#8220;For amendment to Section 4, Article 7 of the Constitution;&#8221; and those vot<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing against the adoption of said amendment to Section 4, shall have written or printed on their ballots the words: &#8220;Against amendment to Section 4, Article 7 of the Constitution," and those voting for the adop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of said amendment to Section 6 shall have written or printed on their ballots the words; &#8220;For amendment to Section 6, Article 7, of the Constitution;&#8221; and those voting against the adoption of said amendment to Section 6, shall have written or printed on their ballots the words: &#8220;Against amendment to Section 6, Article 7, of the Constitution.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Received in office, <date>March 26th, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>NOTE.&#8212;The foregoing act was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the 26th day of March, A. D. 1883, and was not signed by him or returned to the House in which it originated, with his objec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions thereto, within the time prescribed by the constitution, and there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />upon became a law without his signature.</p>
<p>Takes effect after passage.</p>
<closer>
<signed>[Signed] JOS. W. BAINES, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 3. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Requesting Texas Senators and Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives to urge upon Congress, the settlement of the claims of those who suffered from the burning of the town of Brenham, Texas, in 1866.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas a joint select committee of the Senate and House of Represen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tatives of the Legislature of the State of Texas in 1866 who had been appointed to investigate and report the facts Connected with the burn<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing of a portion of the town of Brenham in Washington county, Texas, and to recommend the proper action to be had in the matter, on the 28th September 1866, reported that the fire was the work of United<pb n="439" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="133" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>States troops stationed at Brenham and done in a spirit, of incendiarism and also for the purpose of pillage; the property which was destroyed and lost amounting in value to $131,026.00, a full list of which with names of owners and the sworn evidence of witnesses to the facts upon which the report was based and whereas, said committee recommended that our Senators and Representatives in Congress, and the Governor of this State urge upon the Congress of the United States the justice and im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />portance of a settlement of the claims for said property so destroyed, and the removal of said troops, and whereas, no further action was ever taken by the Legislature of this State except to request the removal of said troops, therefore:</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That our Senators and Representatives in Congress be requested to urge by bill or otherwise as they may deem best the early settlement of these claims by the United States.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Secretary of State be requested to furnish a copy of these resolutions to each of the Senators and Representatives of Texas in Congress, together with a copy of the official report of said joint select committee with such papers as may accompany the same.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>March 31, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 4. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend Section 9, Article 8, of the Consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Section 9, Article 8, of the Constitution of the State of Texas be so amended as hereafter to read as follows:</p>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Article 8.</head>
<p>&#8220;Section 9. The State tax on property, exclusive of the tax neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary to pay the public debt, and of the taxes provided for the benefit of public free schools, shall never exceed thirty-five cents on the one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars valuation; and no county, city or town shall levy more than twenty-five cents for city or county purposes, and not to exceed fifteen cents, for roads and bridges, on the one hundred dollars valuation, ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cept for the payment of debts incurred prior to the adoption of this amendment, and for the erection of public buildings, street, sewer and other permanent improvements, not to exceed twenty-five cents on the one hundred dollars valuation in any one year, and except as is in this Constitution otherwise provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor of this State be, and he is hereby required to submit the foregoing resolutions to a vote of the qualified electors of this State on the second Tuesday in August, 1883.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That those voting for the amendment to Section 9, Article 8, of the Constitution, shall have written or printed on their ballots the words, &#8220;For amendment to Section 9, Article 8, of the Constitution,&#8221; and those voting against the adoption of Section 9, Article 8, of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution shall have written or printed on their ballots the words, &#8220;Against amendment to Section 9, Article 8, of the Constitution.&#8221;</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 7, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="440" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="134" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 5. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>To amend Section 3 of Article 7, of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Section 3, of Article 7, of the Constitution of the State of Texas be so amended as to hereafter read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 3. One-fourth of the revenue derived from the State occu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pation taxes, and a poll tax of one dollar on every male inhabitant of &#8220;this State between the ages of twenty-one and sixty years, shall be set &#8220;apart annually for the benefit of the public free schools, and, in addi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion thereto, there shall be levied and collected an annual ad valorem &#8220;State tax of such an amount, not to exceed twenty cents on the one &#8220;hundred dollars valuation, as, with the available school fund arising &#8220;from all other sources, will be sufficient to maintain and support the &#8220;public free schools of this State for a period of not less than six months &#8220;in each year; and the Legislature may also provide for the formation &#8220;of school districts within all or any of the counties of this State, by &#8220;general or special law, without the local notice required in other cases &#8220;of special legislation, and may authorize an additional annual ad valo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rem tax to be levied and collected within such school districts for the &#8220;further maintenance of public free schools and the erection of school &#8220;buildings therein; provided, that two-thirds of the qualified property &#8220;tax paying voters of the district, voting at an election to be held for &#8220;that purpose, shall vote such tax, not to exceed in any one year twenty &#8220;cents on the one hundred dollars valuation of the property subject to &#8220;taxation in such district, but the limitation upon the amount of district &#8220;tax herein authorized shall not apply to incorporated cities or towns &#8220;constituting separate and independent school districts.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor of this State shall issue his proclamation ordering an election to be held on the second Tuesday in August A. D. 1883, at which time the foregoing amendment shall be submitted for adoption by the qualified electors of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That those voting for the adoption of the amendment to Sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion 3, shall have written or printed on their ballots the words &#8220;For amendment to Section 3, Article 7, of the Constitution, school tax,&#8221; and those voting against the adoption of said amendment shall have writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ten or printed on their ballots the words &#8220;Against the amendment to Section 3, Article 7 of the Constitution, school tax.&#8221;</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 7, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 6. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Proposing an amendment to Article 5 of the State Constitution diminishing the number of terms of county courts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That Article 5 of the Constitution of the State shall be amended by add<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing thereto another section which shall read as follows:</p>
<pb n="441" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="135" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<p>Section 29. The county court shall hold at least four terms for both civil and criminal business annually as may be provided by the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture, or by the commissioners&#8217; court of the county under authority of law and such other terms each year as may be fixed by the commissioners court; provided the commissioners court of any county having fixed the times and number of terms of the county court shall not change the same again until the expiration of one year. Said courts shall dispose of probate business either in term time or vacation under such regulation as may be prescribed by law. Prosecutions may be commenced in said courts in such manner as is or may be provided by law, and a jury therein shall consist of six men. Until otherwise provided the terms of the county court shall be held on the first Mondays in February, May, August and November and may remain in session three weeks.</p>
<p>Sec 2. This amendment shall be submitted on the 2nd Tuesday in August A. D. 1883.</p>
<p>NOTE.&#8212;The foregoing resolution was presented to the Governor of Texas for his approval on the 13th day of April, A. D. 1883, and was not signed by him, or returned to the house in which it originated, with his objection thereto, within the time prescribed by the Constitution, and thereupon became a law without his signature.</p>
<closer>
<signed>[Signed] JOS. W. BAINES, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 7. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Requesting the Senators and Representatives in Congress from Texas to use their best efforts in behalf or such an understanding between the Government of the United States and that of the Republic of Mexico, as will establish and maintain efficient quarantine laws, to prevent the spread of infectious and epidemic dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eases on the border of the two nations.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the recent yellow fever epidemic on the Rio Grande border has demonstrated the necessity for additional precantionary measures to prevent the introduction of yellow fever into Texas, and the fact that small pox has obtained such a foot hold in the border districts of Mexico, as make it almost impossible to protect our people from its ravages unless measures are adopted by that government to hold it in check,</p>
<p>And whereas, the Republic of Mexico has no quarantine or sanitary system whatever, thereby impairing the efficiency of the quarantine laws of Texas, and from this cause owing to the constant communication ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />isting between the two people, and the close proximity of the towns and ranches, the homes of the people of Texas residing on that border are constantly endangered, causing loss of life, injury to commerce, and ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penditures of large sums of money to prevent the spread of infectious diseases on the American side of the Rio Grande; therefore:</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Senate of the State of Texas, the House of Representatives concurring, That our Senators and Representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tives in Congress be requested to urge upon the Congress of the United States the imperative necessity of such an understanding between<pb n="442" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="136" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>the government of the United States and Mexico, as will result, in the es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablishment by the government of Mexico of such quarantine laws and sanitary regulations as will prevent the introduction and spread of in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fectious diseases along the border of the two republics.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Secretary of State be requested to furnish immedi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ately a copy of this joint resolution to each of our Senators and Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives in Congress.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The danger of not being able to reach this measure in regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lar order creates a necessity for suspending the rule requiring it to be read on three several days: and it is so suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 14, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 8. JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Requiring the Governor to submit all consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tutional amendments passed by the 18th Legislature to a vote of the people and fixing the time at which the election shall be held.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That all amendments to the Constitution, passed by the 18th. Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture shall be submitted to a vote of the people at an election for that purpose to be held on the second Tuesday in August A. D. 1883, unless a different time is fixed in the amendment to be submitted.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor shall issue his proclamation calling said election and designating the manner of voting in accordance with Article 17, Section 1, of the Constitution and shall also cause advertisements to be made in accordance therewith.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The near approach of the close of the session is such an im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perative public necessity as justifies the suspension of the constitutional rule requiring this resolution to be read on three several days and said rule is hereby suspended.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>April 14, 1883</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Takes effect ninety days after adjournment.</p>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>